<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap374.xml">apap377</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Deans, Marie; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>Deans, Marie; Papers <num>apap377</num></titleproper><author>Jodi Boyle</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2023-02-17 23:00:06 -0500</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Marie Deans Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap377</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4.36 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1957/2015" type="inclusive">1957-2015</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_f3657e0064debba93388dadc920b7551">This collection documents the death penalty abolitionist work of Marie McFadden Deans.  A smaller amount of personal materials, such as Deans' poetry and writing, also is included.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_0a517f5b8bc40d7058d30d95d81daff2">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_93915fb4263db54cf730ecdcf9b2fdc6">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>The collection includes writings by Marie Deans; clippings about Deans; clippings about death penalty; materials from Virginia Coalition on Jails and Prisons (founded by Deans); correspondence; reports; subject files; and court documents.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_8478835bc3029f0daaf0c41abebc2183">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Marie McFadden Deans (1940-2011) was a death penalty abolitionist and an advocate for individuals on death row.  Following the murder of her mother-in-law Penny Deans in 1972, Marie Deans began to voice her opposition to capital punishment.  In 1976, Marie Deans formed Murder Victims' Families Against the Death Penalty (later called Murder Victims' Families for Reconciliation) and, in 1983, established the Virginia Coalition on Jails and Prisons.  Deans worked on legal cases – those of individuals already on death row and individuals on trial for capital crimes, hoping to mitigate their sentences.   She visited inmates on the death row, and was present at the executions of almost three dozen individuals in Virginia and South Carolina.  </p><p>Although the Virginia Coalition on Jails and Prisons closed after a decade of existence, Marie Deans continued to investigate cases, find inmates attorneys, petition for clemency, call for the abolishment of the death penalty, and advocate for prisoners until her death from lung cancer.</p>  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_d7be18948f676986913b7e08e65a7ed8">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection was processed by Dulcie Beauregard in 2023.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_36a2c4328bdbcef6a59f9dc4085e6486">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is arranged in alphabetical order. It has no series.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_2bae17dfecad5d817f727ca1fba87049">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Robert Deans, son of Marie Deans, donated all materials in this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in <date normal="2018">2018</date>.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_a1dfeba612125aa6b9e44b5ea1df046f">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is not restricted. Portions of the collection may be restricted due to personally identifiable information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_0b5c4d709d398753caa96687ce43e30f">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_d574a57b00607782078801b80ac5659b">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Marie Deans Papers, 1957-2015. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Deans Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">Death Penalty</subject>
    <geogname source="local">Virginia Coalition on Jails and Prisons</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Deans, Marie McFadden, 1940-2011</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Capital punishment--United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Death row inmates.</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
