<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap371.xml">apap371</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Death Penalty Information Center; Records</titleproper><titleproper>Death Penalty Information Center; Records <num>apap371</num></titleproper><author>Jodi Boyle</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2017</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-10-28 18:59:19 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Death Penalty Information Center Records</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap371</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10.0 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1991/2014" type="inclusive">1991-2014</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_0a991c51c6f7360a8a2c4f7330c4b1d1">This collection predmoinantly contains the Death Penalty Information Center's audio/video resources on capital punishment.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_d11f839aabfaea9c420906fa20e529e8">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_022c1630a56c332a71fcf42e14181986" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container>
    <container id="aspace_650fa57a4e6e36517c015a485bf80371" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container>
    <container id="aspace_6b91d9f5728304b541be4913970712bc" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container>
    <container id="aspace_2253e5f6df4b42331bbdd0cb8d48a071" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container>
    <container id="aspace_91e57759313e0375530981e8824c1fc3" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">5</container>
    <container id="aspace_aeacddca625021a190fbd78be8c66fb2" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">6</container>
    <container id="aspace_6d6eccb8798a53b5ee152da01a2950bd" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">7</container>
    <container id="aspace_db6c0d7958ccef22753899cf5f0657d2" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">8</container>
    <container id="aspace_1b2a574f728a741cfdbfc7da20af0de0" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">9</container>
    <container id="aspace_98273e2703eae8f6e420dbf0ff62fbb9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">10</container>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_8b7b5451f7f88b3812ad45e1d535a2e6">
    <head>Description of Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains handwritten notes, some news clips, audio cassettes, and over 200 video cassettes.  The cassettes contain media coverage related to capital punishment, including documentaries about the death penalty; news about executions, clemency, victims, innocence, race, mental health, Death Row interviews, and more.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_15028f9b83d48a2295466190eb58c556">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_c079b48d2f11e8b5f0a4753c81f404e2">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites. Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder. The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks. The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_2aada90419e5cd9800fc5042f91e9d7e">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Anne Holsinger in <date normal="2017">2017</date>.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_ffba19e442c10eb7cf065500f8849d7f">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>Founded in 1990 and based in Washington, D.C., the Death Penalty Information Center is a national non-profit organization serving the media and public with analysis and information on issues concerning capital punishment. In addition to the day-to-day resources it provides, the Center releases an annual report on the death penalty, highlighting significant developments and featuring the latest statistics.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_3424ea1ad367ac828a3e872952a18c32">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_21dae5ed07b598da4cb7307e0e797514">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Death Penalty Information Center Records, 1991-2014. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Death Penalty Information Center Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_ad0017526e7f62f1116a0948fc0e6b4e">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Collection is unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">Death Penalty</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Death Penalty Information Center (U.S.)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Capital punishment -- United States</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
