<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>apap283</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Zaretski, Joseph; Papers <num>apap283</num></titleproper><author>Unprocessed. </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-09-03 13:15:20 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Joseph Zaretski Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap283</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">60.8 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1966/1970" type="inclusive">1966-1970</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_38596e82fedb05d111267dcc4f52c3c3">Joseph Zaretzki was born in New York City on March 9, 1900. Zaretzki served in the U.S. Army during World War I and was a lawyer. Zaretzki was a member of the New York State Senate from 1948 through 1974 (23rd District 1948-1965, 32nd District 1966, 28th District 1967-1974) and was Senate Majority Leader in the 1960s. He was a member of the NAACP, American Legion, Freemasons, and Elks. Zaretzki died on December 20, 1981, with an extensive obituary for him on December 21, 1981, in the New York Times.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_9baa9fe923d1a13139ba3a7c042d3cbc">These materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_f1f2d051adf4d871772f71c0ece85bdb" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_f4e13f664a44c2402509ab481cd3abc4">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection is unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_3b0c1accf129e65ec0cf94bee519c424">
    <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
<p>Joseph Zaretzki was born on March 9, 1900 in Warsaw, Poland. After immigrating to the United States during his childhood, Zaretzki served in the United States Army during World War I and graduated from Columbia College. Zaretzki went out to Columbia Law School and eventually practiced law in the upper Manhattan area. During the Great Depression, Zaretzki worked close with politicians in Tammany Hall and became a local district leader. </p><p>
In November 1947, Zaretzki was elected to the New York State Senate. Zaretzki represented Washington Heights, Manhattan from 1948-1974. Zaretzski also served as the Democratic Minority Leader from 1957-1964, and then again from 1966-1974. Zaretzki was the first Democrat to be a Majority leader when the Democratic party gained control of the Senate in 1965. During his time in the Senate, he became a proponent of legalized off-track betting.</p><p>Zaretzki lost his seat in the New York State Senate in 1974, when Franz S. Leichter defeated him in the Democratic primary election. Zaretzki returned to practice law in the private sector until his death on December 20, 1981 in the Bronx. He was survived by his wife Helen, his two brothers, and a grandson. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_1eb3a676a850166a8963265e64d2a584">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of materials from Joseph Zaretzki's service in the new York State Senate, including correspondence, bills, subject files, reports, and press releases.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_ffaa8a9c7ce7de02d7ce2dfaf777aea3">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_63a9acbae33b4c92e4c6e6cbfda355d2">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Joseph Zaretzki donated his papers to Syracuse University in 1967. Additonal materials were donated  in 1970. In 2006, the materials were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_010bdb021f72271c237fb4b2456bb325">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_0391435e2d2384cbfc8c1c9763577419">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_eda5cccbf4ac47aa1d92770c8c43f099">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Joseph Zaretzki, 1966-1970. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Zaretzki Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">Politics and Politicians</subject>
    <geogname source="local">Zaretzki, Joseph, 1900-1981</geogname>
    <occupation source="local">New York State-- Senate</occupation>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
