<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap299.xml">apap299</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>The Prudent Residents Opposed to Electric Cable Transmission (PROTECT) Records <num>apap299</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.</author><sponsor>Funded by the Documentary Heritage Program Grant.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2017</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-06-12 08:16:41 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>The Prudent Residents Opposed to Electric Cable Transmission (PROTECT) Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="local" source="local">PROTECT</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>apap299</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">18 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1980/2007" type="inclusive">1980-2007</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_c60b54a9e341c737a3c7ef4ff5340353">P.R.O.T.E.C.T. (Prudent Residents Opposed to Electric Cable Transmission) initially formed in 1982 to oppose construction of a high voltage power line originating from Marcy, New York in Oneida County and running down to the New York City area.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_English">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_The materials are located onsite in the department.">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_133aeaf2c9d89b7ebda7f001625944ef" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_4a38a99aaaa6f55e5931a3ce84df5f89">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The Prudent Residents Opposed to Electric Cable Transmission (PROTECT) Records are arranged into the following series: 1. The Mary South Transmission Line 2. James Bay 3. General Activism 4. Administrative Materials 5. Publications</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_Access to this collection is unrestricted.">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <processinfo id="aspace_Processing Information">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Melissa McMullen</p>  </processinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_Copyright Statement">
    <head>Copyright Statement</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>

<p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>


<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_a091a0e6c840a0b3cb8ae34928da4743">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Doris Delaney in 2004, 2012.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_95d288c17fc9ac578e08ffe1e7a5051f">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, The Prudent Reidents Opposed to Electric Cable Transmission (PROTECT) Records. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the PROTECT Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="aspace_02d019b0a6fc6fd0a209aa79580e42b9">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>P.R.O.T.E.C.T. (Prudent Residents Opposed to Electric Cable Transmission) initially formed in 1982 to oppose construction of a high voltage power line originating from Marcy, New York in Oneida County and running down to the New York City area. A volunteer organization, P.R.O.T.E.C.T. was organized into chapters, one for each county affected by the power line construction, and led by chairperson Doris Delaney of Orange County who donated the collection. The records document P.R.O.T.E.C.T.s efforts to mobilize and educate concerned citizens, and its legal actions against the Public Service Commission of the State of New York and the Power Authority of the State of New York. The papers include correspondence, newsletters, news articles, scientific papers and reports, press releases, hearing transcripts, and other legal files. For the next two decades P.R.O.T.E.C.T. remained an active advocacy organization and the subject files and background materials in the collection demonstrate its broader interests in the environmental movement. Files include materials related human exposure to electromagnetic fields, efforts to halt Hydro-Quebecs building of dams in the James Bay region of Quebec the constructions potential impact on the environment and the native people of the area, and forestry.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_249beb67b55fe86d28c75b78e07780e5">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The Prudent Residents Opposed to Electric Cable Transmission records are arranged into five series: 1. The Marcy South Transmission Line 2. James Bay 3. General Activism 4. Administrative Records and 5. Publications. The materials in this collection document efforts of this upstate New York environmental organization to stop the high voltage power line Marcy South Transmission Line in the 1980s by the Power Authority of New York State and Hydro-Québec’s Great Whale (Grande Baleine) River/James Bay II development efforts in the early 1990s. The types of materials in the collection includes press releases, manuscripts and writings, fliers for rallies and events, conference materials, U.S. and Canadian newspaper clippings, statements made at public hearings, correspondence and subject files.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname authfilenumber="Delaney, Doris" source="local">Delaney, Doris</geogname>
    <genreform authfilenumber="Conservation and the Environment" source="lcsh">Conservation and the Environment</genreform>
    <subject source="meg">Social Activists and Public Advocates</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">James Bay Region--Environmental conditions.</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Cree Indians--James Bay Region--Social life and customs</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Lobbying--New York (State)</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_cf2a4da4e07d57cecc417a68455d952b" level="series"><did><unittitle>The Marcy South Transmission Line</unittitle></did></c><c id="aspace_1bd0873814e1aba7cc8a99ff15413f0e" level="series"><did><unittitle>James Bay</unittitle></did></c><c id="aspace_625e5226cc9cdfd0b2599e7cae00d306" level="series"><did><unittitle>General Activism</unittitle></did></c><c id="aspace_039649fe884b216c83a4f5239dd88a58" level="series"><did><unittitle>Administrative Materials</unittitle></did></c><c id="aspace_3acd3eff14dc0327e3b124ccfe12630d" level="series"><did><unittitle>Publications</unittitle></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
