<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>apap262</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Kupferman, Thomas; Papers <num>apap262</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.
Processed by unprocessed. </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-10-28 18:31:29 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Thomas Kupferman Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap262</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">52 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1600/2000" type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_02b36101afa4eb472034c64e62bf5b29">Theodore Roosevelt Kupferman was a Representative from New York. Kupferman was born in New York City on May 12, 1920. Kupferman was elected as a Republican to the Eighty-ninth Congress by special election to fill the vacancy caused by the resignation of U.S. Representative John V. Lindsay. Kupferman was reelected to the Ninetieth Congress (February 8, 1966-January 3, 1969), but was not a candidate for reelection to the Ninety-first Congress in 1968. Kupferman was also a justice of the New York State Supreme Court, 1969-1996. Kupferman died on September 23, 2003, in New York, NY. This collection contains materials related to Kupferman's political career.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_0a59161738c896b747f36bec7999b974">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_8a0d9bce5fb037a94a280d2e4c093de9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_0e4c8394ee76778b5b3885430e04a521">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Proccessed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_bb1ac694181ea6ac66edebe1e89277de">
    <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
<p> Theodore Roosevelt (Thomas) Kupferman was born in New York City on May 12, 1920. Kuperfman graduated from De Witt Clinton High School, in New York City, earned his B.S. from the City College, New York, and earned his LL.B. from Columbia Law School. Kupferman was admitted to the New York Bar in 1943 and the United States Supreme Court Bar in 1948. Kupferman then became a law secretary in the Appellate Division, New York State Supreme Court from 1948-1949. Kupferman was also a member of the legal department of Warner Brothers Pictures, Inc., from 1943-1951, a member of the legal department of National Broadcasting Co., Inc., from 1951-1953 and the general counsel of Cinerama Productions Corp., from 1953-1958. Kuperfman also served as an assistant and adjunct professor of law at New York Law School from 1959-1964, a counsel and legislative assistant to minority leader, New York City Council from 1958-1962 and a councilman of the city of New York, 1962-1966.</p><p>Kupferman was elected as a Republican to the Eighty-ninth Congress by special election to fill the vacancy caused by the resignation of U.S. Representative John V. Lindsay. Kupferman was reelected to the Ninetieth Congress (February 8, 1966-January 3, 1969), but was not a candidate for reelection to the Ninety-first Congress in 1968. Kupferman was also a justice of the New York State Supreme Court, 1969-1996. After his retirement, Kupferman returned to private practice.  Kupferman died on September 23, 2003, in New York, NY.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_5b30b7bdd39df1b29d75c5e7e8bcd06f">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of case files, correspondence, subject files, and legislation.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_98c177f2712c67bf6311db40884ec14a">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_c507309da077782cf8b04cb83650b518">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Thomas Kupferman donated his papers to Syracuse University between 1968-1969. In 2006, materials were transfered to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_cee711af227076f07ca4c009e53fd7cb">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_9e761171f6dae04ca90fe589e52767a9">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_be7cfe139e64813244ae390dbf629c45">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Thomas Kupferman Papers, Undated. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Kupferman Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Kupferman, Theodore R.</geogname>
    <subject source="meg">Politics and Politicians</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">U. S. Congress</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
