<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>apap246</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Fino, Paul A.; Papers <num>apap246</num></titleproper><author>Sheri Sarnoff </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>March 2020</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-03-23 23:00:04 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Fino, Paul A. Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="local">Fino, Paul A.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>apap246</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">68 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1949/1969" type="inclusive">1949-1969</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_e620fbd86adca0d954c7f487c0164a9c">
Paul A. Fino was a United States Representative from Bronx, New York. Fino was a member of the New York State Senate from January 1945 to May 1950. He was then member of the New York City Civil Service Commission from June 1, 1950, to December 31, 1952. Fino was elected as a Republican to the Eighty-third and to the seven succeeding Congresses and served from January 3, 1953, until his resignation December 31, 1968, to become a New York Supreme Court Justice having been elected November 5, 1968. Fino assumed his duties as a justice on January 1, 1969. Fino passed away in 2009. This collections contains records related to Fino's time in office. These records include constituent files, legislative files, and records related to the national lottery that Fino tried to implement. 
</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_f3bf27b23003293340ad1a2a5d8b8c02">English.</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_fb005103e7fe52e47c49b94bf164a2a3">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_ab7a396f776148b1b8ef86e18126a5b5" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_43390f4442ac2be13ea8b0a17ce0bf58">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_638607fde56232f1f514392e9bfcea92">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection was partly processed by Sheri Sarnoff in 2020.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_42476e2e9dd934d407f15f01206c3677">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Paul A. Fino Papers include consituent files, legislative material, records relating to the national lottery that Fino tried to implement, biographical materials, and other records related to his time in the United States Senate and New York Supreme Court.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_6a6c86674e878010830475af6361dfaf">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Paul Fino initially donated his papers to Syracuse University in 1968 and 1969. In 2006, the papers were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_53a13e92fb087607b25718c950541bfa">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>This collection is restricted because it is unprocessed.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_e3113fb7772eb0420ba02345c16aaeaa">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal refernce use, reffered to, or linked to from other websites. Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder. The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.)and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additonally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks. The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_ecf08df75a6630fa46fe647f5a90a57a">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Paul A. Fino Papers, xxxx-xxxx. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Taylor Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Congressional Records</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Legislative hearings--New York (State)--New York--1960-1970.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Constituent Communication</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Lotteries - United States</geogname>
    <title source="meg">Paul A. Fino</title>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_a145a6733f1d99f0ed658062be557241" level="series"><did><unittitle>Biographical </unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1949/1969" type="inclusive">1949-1969</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_4a24c48a1c021834f3945afd19771e24"><head>Arrangement</head></arrangement></c><c id="aspace_eeb3b456476863b0a4ce4f2d5ff1d6f4" level="series"><did><unittitle>Legislation</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1949/1969" type="inclusive">1949-1969</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_c2e596929a18c5bfb81942693f7af5ee"><head>Arrangement</head></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_b2058e50134b21ca5a2518404e2c1729"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains legislative records that Paul A. Fino worked with during his time in Congress from January 3. 1953 to December 31,1968. During this time, Fino tried to inact a national lottery. During his time in the House of Representives, he was a delegate to the Republican National Convention in 1960, 1964, and 1968. This series contains records of his time in Congress as well as records related to the National Lottery.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a77463e0fb5f7620d4439285f30912e4" level="series"><did><unittitle>Constituent Files </unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">25 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1949/1969" type="inclusive">1949-1969</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_a17e5db4264c862b18427511526f0e8e"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged alphanetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_e07afb4d075bb445e70003833df04c86"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains Paul A. Fino's constiuent files from his time in the United States House of Representatives. Fino's contiuents were mostly from the Bronx, New York, but some constiuents in Brooklyn wrote to Fino because they did not have a Republican representative. This series contains correspondence from constiuents realting to the Vietnam and Korean War. Soliders would often write to Fino and ask for help relating to hardship dischages, compassionate reassignments, medical discharges and transfers. While Fino did not have the athourity to grant these assignments, he often had the contacts to help speed the process of recieving a response from the Army, Military, and Navy. This series also includes records   of constiuents who asked Fino to reccomend them for the United States Naval Academy, constiuents asking for Fino to help them find a job, veterans asking for help related to Social Security and benefits, as well as general questions about housing and government information. This series gives a glimpse of what was happening during times of War in the United States and how people responded to these war efforts. Many records contain medical information and social security numbers. These folders are restricted. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e9d3e42456831664aa75f27d9543cb40" level="series"><did><unittitle>Subject Files</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1949/1968" type="inclusive">1949-1968</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_45f496df6b2a3b526e09e665d3ef9e5b"><head>Arrangement</head></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_c4a23827d7ebfadd063c5f1a6c4ce9d3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains professional correspondence, and  other records related to Paul A. Fino's political career.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
