<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="unprocessed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap400.xml">apap400</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Spence, Bill and Andy; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>Spence, Bill and Andy; Papers <num>apap400</num></titleproper><author>Jodi Boyle</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2021</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-12-03 23:00:34 -0500</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Bill and Andy Spence Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap400</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.0 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1960/1991" type="inclusive">1960-1991</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_c8643b1152ef9e4bceec21d1401e6cb4">This collection contains materials related to the lives of Bill and Andy Spence, including folk and traditional music and materials documenting the Fox Hollow and Old Songs Festivals.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_f828312e0600c8278019995d168075bd">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_3ca2f1ae3f61a7fcb752d0b85211f94c">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>The collection includes reel-to-reel tapes, LPs, photographs, a scrapbook, ephemera, DVDs, and born digital files.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_8c6459255abbb45fb4516a91c3fb4823">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Born in Iowa, spouses Bill (1940-2019) and Kay "Andy" Spence relocated to Voorheesville, N.Y. in 1965.  For decades, the two were involved with folk and traditional music in the Capital Region. Initially involved with the Fox Hollow Festival in the late 1960s, the two founded the nonprofit Old Songs, Inc. in 1977 to present folk and traditional music and dance to the public through concerts and group instruction. The first Old Songs Festival was held in 1981 in Guilderland, N.Y.  before moving to the Altamont Fairgrounds the following year. Andy Spence served as director of the festival until 2017. </p><p>Andy Spence also served as executive director of Old Songs, Inc. until 2018 when she became executive director emeritus. Bill Spence retired from the University of New York at Albany where he worked as a specialist in television, audio, and graphic design in 1998. The two also formed Andy's Front Hall, a full-service mail-order business for selected folk music recordings, books, instruments, and accessories which they operated for decades.</p><p>Bill Spence was a musician for more than 60 years. He played banjo, guitar, and Autoharp but was best known for playing the hammered dulcimer. In 1970 he formed a string band named Fennig's All-Star String Band with musicians living in the Albany area brought together by a folk music organization known as "The Pick'n' and Sing'n' Gather'n.'"</p><p>Bill and Andy Spence had one daughter Hannah, a graduate of Oberlin Conservatory of Music, Oberlin, Ohio.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_678e1f5f55d344e767ad7b296668fdbf">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_2a59928a31f2daad11e3ec7a63c1d009">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Don Person donated 164 reel-to-reel tapes in October 2020. Andy Spence donated materials in August 2021.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_b31c3cb172372a40bcacbc6874a7ca2a">
    <head>Arrangement of the collection</head>
<p>The collection is currently unprocessed and is not yet arranged.</p>  </arrangement>
  <processinfo id="aspace_aa0c6f9baa13c201a132cbf55c69a80f">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The collection is currently unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_938afcd514f4eb99341006ee6a23e9be">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_90b4abc95da11c285296cef88c1a6ddd">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Bill and Andy Spence Papers, 1960-1991. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Spence Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="local">Spence, Kay "Andy"</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Spence, Bill (Musician)</geogname>
    <subject source="meg">Music</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Folk music festivals</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Mail-order sound recording industry</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Folk music-United States</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
