<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>apap282</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Wilson, Kenneth L.; Papers <num>apap282</num></titleproper><author>Unprocessed. </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-03-26 23:00:03 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Wilson, Kenneth L. Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="local">Wilson, Kenneth L., 1908-1971</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>apap282</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">11 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1600/2000" type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_5f2ab47b00e8bbd0673b5cef910dc0ae">Kenneth L. Wilson of Woodstock, NY was a Republican member of the New York State Assembly from 1953 through 1968 (Ulster County 1953-1965, 109th District 1966, 99th District 1967-1968). Wilson was also an alternate delegate to the Republican National Convention from New York in 1960.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_9f6898f7a676782a687b3b799ca5382c">English.</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_c350edb2f34e77fdfa8e901f26e2420d">This collection is located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_ac83c7c94c8e3ec98c7e2db9bd57f19c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_832fb048e0e5b309b786f0b52718569d">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_0a381557c44024bc06f8000a5091657a">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Kenneth L. Wilson was born in 1908. Prior to running for office, Wilson was a real estate agent. Wilson was active in the town of Woodstock and was the supervisor of the town from 1944-1953. Wilson also sat on the Ulster County Board of Supervisors and sat as the chair from 1949 to 1953. Wilson sat on the advisory board of the National Bank of Orange and Ulster Counties and was a trustee of the Saugerties Savings Bank.</p><p>Active in the Republican Party, Wilson was the chairman of the Ulster County Republican Committee and gained a seat in the New York State Assembly in 1953. Serving in this position through 1968, Wilson was the secretary of the Joint Legislative Committee on Penal Institutions. Wilson also helped promote the bill that led to the building og the Gov. Thomas E. Dewey Thruway, as well as the Kingston-Rhinecliff Bridge. </p><p>	In his spare time, he enjoyed being involved in the Federated Sportsmens’ Clubs of Ulster County. Wilson passed away in 1971 and was survived by his wife Anna M. Kuhlewind and three children. In 1979, a campground site in North Central Ulster County was named in honor of the assemblyman. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_81fa549c1ecd23804a990aad3678c1b0">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of materials from Kenneth L. Wilson's service in the New York State Assembly, including correspondence, bills, subject files, reports, and press releases.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_64157606f49e2a46af0e4c8ce49c5245">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_bbff42108d7d32a51a406a311363845c">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>This series</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_e2aeff9f2220cafabdc6510955d8b5bf">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_380c449592112390950880240269b73c">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_85639612657d12b9538b4ff4afd94836">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Kenneth L. Wilson Papers, xxxx-xxxx. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Wilson Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">Politics and Politicians</subject>
    <occupation source="local">New York State-- Assembly</occupation>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
