<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap393.xml">apap393</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Capital Region Planning; Collection</titleproper><titleproper>Capital Region Planning; Collection <num>apap393</num></titleproper><author>Jodi Boyle</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2021</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-09-30 23:00:36 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Capital Region Planning Collection</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap393</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.0 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1949/2008" type="inclusive">1949-2008</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_a3f31f0a6b5fc00f1f2ab11ea7ccd93b">This collection contains project plans, designs, and recommendations. The materials discuss plans for cities and towns in New York's Capital Region as well as for the state overall.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_4384a4fe3c5cce00b8ec6156141b7794">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_fc03f60e5deb6e20368f94461491cfb4">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_882983fd88213a6bb3dc5e8f7c2350ae">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Ray Bromley, Emeritus Professor, Department of Geography and Planning, donated all materials in this collection in 2019 and 2021.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_61b729b4bbe0e33840150369292cfc63">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_a764da5a34417c162171781930f9bf65">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The University at Albany's Department of Geography and Planning first offered undergraduate degrees in 1967 under the name the Department of Geography. An M.A. was introduced in 1970. It became the Department of Geography and Regional Planning in 1985, and was renamed the Department of Geography and Planning in 1988. Over the years, the Department gathered many project plans from the surrounding area as research tools and resources for the faculty and students. In addition, faculty and graduate students created project plans of their own.</p>  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_029cec5b515b680d280b926a5da0bdb2">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_1d5069103e6a2ca964ee189d129e7c02">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_c76218980eab5d256f733fa5c9c66470">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Capital Region Planning Collection, 1949-2008. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Capital Region Planning Collection).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">State University of New York. Department of Geography and Planning</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Regional planning--New York (State)</geogname>
    <subject source="meg">Albany, New York</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
