<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>apap278</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Seymour, Whitney; Papers <num>apap278</num></titleproper><author>Processed by unprocessed.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-03-31 23:00:07 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Seymour, Whitney Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="lcsh">Seymour, Whitney North, Jr., 1923-2019</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>apap278</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">50 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1966/1968" type="inclusive">1966-1968</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_e0774ae3b781ff636a285115619269b5">Whitney North Seymour, Jr. was born in Huntington, Cabell County, West Virginia on July 7, 1923, Seymour served in the U.S. Army during World War II, was a lawyer, served as a Republican member of the New York State Senate (1966-1968), and was also the U.S. District Attorney for the Southern District of New York (1970-1973). His papers contain records relating to his time in the New York State Senate. </abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_229d665ce8cd39196048d527b699c5b5">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_e5071892b5b1d04a9e80d530504291d6">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_e067a5bd13e24e8ceb49f2a5d717e515" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_49e1233d2222434bb95638fb396b25cf">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_3e59abf3020fbf4971130d55e5892557">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Whitney North Seymour, Jr. was born in Huntington, Cabell County, West Virginia on July 7, 1923, the son of Whitney North Seymour and Lola (Vickers) Seymour. He graduated from Princeton University and Yale Law School before he served in the U.S. Army during World War II.  Seymour then became a lawyer and eventually served as a Republican member of the New York State Senate (1966-1968). Seymour was also the U.S. District Attorney for the Southern District of New York (1970-1973). During his political career, he was appointed as independent counsel to investigate Michel Deaver, a former Reagan White House official. Seymour also co-founded the Natural Resources Defense Council in 1970. </p><p>Seymour was an Episcopalian and a member of the American Bar Association and the American Judicature Society. After this time in the Senate, Seymour did pro-bono public interest work at the small firm of Landy and Seymour in midtown Manhattan. Seymour was also an author, who wrote three books and co-wrote a one-act play that was performed off Broadway.He and his wife Catryna have two daughters. He lived with his wife in the Greenwich Village district of Manhattan until his death on June 29, 2019.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_42995e9dc994b054138fbba6bbbce798">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of materials from Whitney North Seymour's service in the New York State Senate, including subject files, legislation, and ephemera.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_16eedca4f559208766d4182e29d0aa52">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_661fd9605cfbc3b0a1f4355dac507462">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Whitney Seymour donated his records to Syracuse University in 1970. Additional accessions were donated in 1977 and 1980. In 2006, the papers were transferred to the M.E. Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_d821b998ab4d014df3c123ba10758f4a">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b6ddfcd87521def5d6b4a1e232d283a4">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_a14cc2038788c5ee7322c68fc7d63cc9">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Whitney Northern Seymour Papers, 1966-1968. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Seymour Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Seymour, Whitney North, Jr., 1923-2019</geogname>
    <occupation source="local">New York State-- Senate</occupation>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
