<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap380.xml">apap380</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Capital District Regional Planning Commission; Records <num>apap380</num></titleproper><author>Jesse McCaughey</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2019-2020</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-10-20 23:00:04 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Capital District Regional Planning Commission Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="lcsh">Capital District Regional Planning Commission</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>apap380</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">55.07 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1934/2013" type="inclusive">1934-2013</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_45169e8e955298b76eab6dddd47f3504">This collection documents the comprehensive planning work of New York's Capital District Regional Planning Commission across several decades.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_c917f00cfa78bac6ebbc9bb566e68b24">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_31fd64a3100f4b6bb42c756ea59dd082">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>The collection contains plans; proposals; maps; reports; studies; booklets on codes, regulations, and zoning laws; and correspondence.  The materials discuss plans for cities and counties in New York's Capital Region as well as the Adirondacks.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e6e4141bee1f5f2bca68a80b5848c67d">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>The Capital District Regional Planning Commission (CDRPC) is a regional planning and resource center, established pursuant to New York State law, serving Albany, Rensselaer, Saratoga, and Schenectady counties.  CDRPC was created in 1967 by a cooperative agreement amongst these four counties. Its original purpose was to perform and support comprehensive planning work, including surveys, planning services, technical services, and the formulation of plans and policies to promote coordinated development of the entire Capital Region. Over time, the mission of the CDRPC evolved in response to changes in the needs of the Capital Region, funding sources, organizational structures, and information technology. While continuing to provide a wide variety of comprehensive planning services, CDRPC has also assumed the functions of Data and Information Center, Economic Development District, Foreign-Trade Zone Administrator, Climate Smart Communities Coordinator, and Water Quality Manager.</p>  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_e263047660e991efa5edf9950f7aa4db">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection was arranged and described in 2019-2020 by Jesse McCaughey.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_ee697176effbd9677b6c2727566f23e7">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is arranged into six series: Albany County, Rensselaer County, Saratoga County, Schenectady County, Capital District, and Greater Region.  Planning documents that describe work sited in only one of the four home counties of the Capital District are filed in the series named for that county, labeled with the most relevant village, town, or city. For documents that include plans that span county boundaries within the Capital District -- e.g., the Port of Albany or the I-87 Northway -- those have been filed in the series entitled "Capital District." All other documents in the series, whose plans pertain to areas entirely outside the four home counties of the Capital District, are filed in the series entitled "Greater Region." Examples of the last category include plans for the Adirondack Park, the Lower Hudson River, and western New York.
 
Some common file types within the collection include comprehensive/master plans, local waterfront revitalization plans, environmental impact assessments, soil surveys, and water/sewer plans. A special indication is present for those documents that contain either a supplemental or a fold-out map.
 
Particular sites for which there are a substantial number of documents include the Albany Pine Bush Preserve, the Port of Albany, Albany Airport, and Adirondack Park. The earliest dated documents in the collection are USGS soil surveys from the 1930s. However, the great majority of documents date from the 1960s, 1970s, and 1980s.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_3355ebd283d1234c47718a40540bc71e">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Mark A. Castiglione, executive director, Capital District Regional Planning Commission, donated all materials in this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in July <date normal="2019">2019</date>.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_360f38dd2ff9a1b7a912f0d1585c2ab3">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_29a84f6ffaa30a87d542cdb62a5d5aab">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_05cca7707f163af71e745118c632ab5c">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Capital District Regional Planning Commission Records, 1934-2013. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Capital District Regional Planning Commission Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Capital District Regional Planning Commission</geogname>
    <geogname source="meg">Albany, New York</geogname>
    <subject source="meg">Rensselaer County, New York</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Schenectady, New York</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Regional planning--New York (State)</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_cac61e3e2ccee87ae2f020b289b65bcd" level="series"><did><unittitle>Albany County</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">11.42 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1942/2013" type="inclusive">1942-2013</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_a99b53bfb058ae716eb631206dd312a8"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement></c><c id="aspace_39ea9061a9010bfd0f38df40b6e76aeb" level="series"><did><unittitle>Saratoga County</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9.68 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1960/2008" type="inclusive">1960-2008</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_b1f0f0ac74b5ebd88020cfa7313d0b49"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_e4b0537c33ff39500b331a34f1f7b291"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains files pertaining to planning decisions in Saratoga County, New York. Some of the documents refer to plans for specific municipalities -- i.e., villages, towns, and the City of Saratoga Springs -- while others pertain to county-wide planning efforts. Among the most common file types are: comprehensive/master plans (including master plans for Saratoga Springs published in the 1960s and 1980s), zoning ordinances/maps, soil surveys, county land use and development plans, transportation plans (e.g., bikeways, park and ride, highway rest station plans), environmental impact statements, and numerous reports on county water/sewerage projects.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_bf5e0ff722b2250aa30b6e0e8a9707c6" level="series"><did><unittitle>Rensselaer County</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8.01 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1937/2003" type="inclusive">1937-2003</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_250b5ae06683d007350a8f9b030f7303"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement></c><c id="aspace_b7f027bed59eee78415878febe67205b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Schenectady County</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.88 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1948/2008" type="inclusive">1948-2008</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_c43b6a3c4672541db430e1d8ae83156c"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_68c4dc862105045c700eef5e494f9113"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains files pertaining to planning decisions in Schenectady County, New York. The majority of the documents involve planning issues within the City of Schenectady, although there are also numerous documents pertaining to the towns of Niskayuna, Glenville, and Rotterdam, as well as several for the Village of Scotia. Of particular note are a series of master/comprehensive plans for the City of Schenectady published in the 1940s, 1970s, and 1990s. This series also contains a variety of sub-area plans for downtown and neighborhood development. Other common file types include: economic analyses (at the municipal and county level), water supply/treatment documents (e.g., aquifer/groundwater and wastewater facilities), housing plans, and recreational facility profiles.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a97fca3d5ea5add839c9a6b23c89abd3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Capital District </unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.22 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1936/2008" type="inclusive">1936-2008</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_bb9f38deb5f7994a5deb6d9a5ea69e81"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement></c><c id="aspace_6f0335aaf78711b932a723732a73df3f" level="series"><did><unittitle>Greater Region</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.43 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1934/1997" type="inclusive">1934-1997</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_678274754fcaee64610b502b61bd8dac"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
