<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>apap050</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Worker's Union (ACTWU), Hudson Valley Area Joint Board; Records <num>apap050</num></titleproper><author>Geoffrey A. Huth</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-08-26 23:01:05 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2019</date><item>Encoded into EAD and additional arrangement and description by Sheri Sarnoff in 2019.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Worker's Union (ACTWU), Hudson Valley Area Joint Board Records</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap050</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">13.03 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1919/1989" type="inclusive">1919-1989</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_62c321f1a284d6f099811c2f2f72c5ee">The Hudson Valley Area Joint Board was formed in 1957 through the merger of the Columbia County and Mid-Hudson Valley Joint Boards. At that point, the two joint boards were affiliated of the Textile Workers Union of America (TWUA), which merged with the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (ACWA) in 1976 to form the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU).  The collection documents the organization, administration, and activities of the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board and its predecessor organizations.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_4eba6b483beb17e43614beaf93d589f3">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_b2039d79861895b2bd9fd92e81dfb539" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://archives.albany.edu/catalog?f[collection_number_sim][]=apap050" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Hyrax Search: Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Worker's Union (ACTWU), Hudson Valley Area Joint Board Records" xlink:type="simple">
    <daodesc><p>Hyrax Search: Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Worker's Union (ACTWU), Hudson Valley Area Joint Board Records</p></daodesc>
  </dao>
  <processinfo id="aspace_8283d1082437281229ea5a2bddb1bf9a">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Collection processed in 1990 by Geoffrey A. Huth.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_4adc885089bd70962eb8b47c8329138e">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>
The Hudson Valley Area Joint Board was formed in 1957 through the merger of the Columbia County and Mid-Hudson Valley Joint Boards. At this point, the two joint boards were affiliated of the Textile Workers Union of America (TWUA), which merged with the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (ACWA) in 1976 to form the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU). After the formation of the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board in 1957, other joint boards joined the union. The Capital District Joint Board, which was chartered in 1937, joined the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board in 1968. The Amsterdam Joint Board, which was charted in 1942, also joined the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board in the mid 1960's.  All of the joint boards had local chapters that represented different workplaces and institutions. Each local chapter had its own set of bylaws and constitutions, and each institution had its own set of bylaws and constitutions as well.</p><p>Prior to the merge the Capital District Joint Board oversaw the Berkshire Joint Board, which was chartered in 1946.  When the merge occurred, the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board oversaw their records until 1968-1969. The Berkshire Joint Board then joined the Connecticut Joint Board in 1969. The Capital District Area Joint Board was also affiliated with the Troy Area Industrial Union Council, CIO. The Hudson Valley Area Joint Board was also associated with the AFL-CIO and helped keep track of their local unions. These unions included the Upper Hudson Area Industrial Council, which became the Upper Hudson Area Central Labor Union in 1958. These records were held by the Columbia County Joint Board until the merge. The Hudson Valley Area Joint Board also helped maintain the Central Labor Union of New York records as well.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_7fef7fee490d2e87167be4a8f0462c99">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is made up of five series. Series 1 includes records documenting the activities of the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board. Series 2 documents the activities relating to the Amsterdam Joint Board. Series 3 includes records from the Capital District Area Joint Board. Series 4 is made up of records relating to the Columbia County Joint Board and Series 5 contains records relating to the Mid-Hudson Valley Area Joint Board.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_caaf2900ac1e2a57f09c6aebe6847e86">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>All the items in series 1 of this manuscript group were lent to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board, ACTWU, and were subsequently microfilmed as a part of the Harry Van Arsdale, Jr., Labor History Project.  The originals have been returned to the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board.  The original items in series 2-5 were subsequently donated.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_0baafd981db8db0e3cc362261fb3db74">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Worker's Union (ACTWU), Hudson Valley Area Joint Board Records, 1919-1989. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the ACTWU Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_30d06e0762e99a921924964e639b72ac">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection divided into five series that document the organization, administration and activities of the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board of the ACTWU and its predecessor organizations.  The collection contains meeting minutes, correspondence, contracts and arbitration documents, board by-laws and organizing leaflets for the Hudson Valley Board and its predecessors. The collection also contains bylaws, constitutions, and meeting minutes of the AFL-CIO organizations that the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board helped maintain.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <odd id="aspace_fbcc0f6cf99498d710e34b417a40a2ae">
    <head>Indexes to Companies Where Locals Worked</head>
<p>Below is a list of the different local chapters of the joint boards prior to their merge. The Hudson Valley Area Joint Board contains all of the local chapters after the merge, as well as the Berkshire Joint Board local records as well. </p><p>Amsterdam Joint Board
(chartered 1942; merged with the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board  ca. 1965)
Bigelow-Sanford Carpet Company (Local 1) 
Mohasco Industries (Local 489) 
Mohawk Carpet Mills (Local 489 and Local 856) 
Fownes Brothers and Company, Inc. (Locals 646) 
Chalmers Knitting Company (Local 835) 
Montco Manufacturing Company, Inc. (Local 835)
Local 846
BAM Industries, Inc. (Local 1761) </p><p>
Capital District Joint Board 
(chartered, 1937; merged with Hudson Valley Area Joint Board, 1968)
Beaunit Mills (Local 89) 
NAFI Corporation (Local 237) 
National Automotive Fibres, Inc., NAFI (Local 237) 
National Automotive Wadding Co., Inc. (Local 237) 
Waterford Industries (Local 237) 
Peerless Fibre Company (Local 238 and Garnett Workers Union, Local 577)
Cohoes Screen Print Corporation (Local 346) 
Cohoes Textile Printing Company (Local 346) 
Wilson Athletic Goods Manufacturing Company, Inc. (Local 574) 
Cohoes Dyeing and Finishing Company, Inc. (Local 575) 
Batt and Shoddy Manufacturers (Garnett Workers Union, Local 577) 
Enterprise Garnetting Co. (Garnett Workers Union, Local 577) 
Lowenthal and Co. (Garnett Workers Union, Local 577) 
National Textile Manufacturing Co. (Garnett Workers Union, Local 577) 
Star Woolen Company (Local 1351 and Garnett Workers Union, Local 577) 
United Waste Manufacturing Co. (Garnett Workers Union, Local 577) 
Wilson Brothers, Inc. (Local 675)
William Barnet and Son, Inc. (Local 964 and United Textile Workers of America, Local 520) 
Regis Textiles (Local 907) 
Albany Parlor Company (Local 976) 
Montague Furniture Company (Local 976) 
Montague Upholstering Company (Local 976) 
Star Textile and Research (Local 1351) </p><p>Columbia County Joint Board 
(existed at least since 1947; merged with the Mid-Hudson Joint Board in 1957 to form the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board)
Local 96
Local 791
High Rock Mills, Inc. (Local 792) 
Springdale Mills (Local 793) 
Imperial Pen and Pencil Co. (Local 938) 
Nassau Pen Manufacturing Co. (Local 938) 
Faith Mills, Inc. (Local 1122) 
Hudson Glue Corporation (Local 1246) 
Union Piece Dye Works (Local 1342)</p><p>
Mid-Hudson Valley Joint Board 
(chartered 1948; merged with the Columbia County Joint Board in 1957 to form the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board)
Braendly Dye Works, Inc. (United Textile Workers of America, Local 282) 
Capitol Piece Dye Works, Inc. (Local 464) 
Elk Piece Dye Works, Inc. (Local 464)
Garnerville Dye Works, Inc. (Local 464) 
Poughkeepsie Finishing Corporation (Local 501) 
Dutchess-Lockwood Holdings (Local 673) 
Dutchess-Lockwood, Inc. (Local 673) 
P-V-M Corporation (Local 673) 
United Wire Goods (Local 683) 
Textile By-Products (Local 791) 
Bernhard Altmann International Corp., High Rock Div. (Local 792) 
High Rock Knitting Corporation (Local 792) 
High Rock Mills (Local 792) 
Springdale Mills (Local 793)
Local 893
S. Stroock and Company, Inc. (Local 898) 
Local 982 
Tex Ray Fabrics, Inc. (Local 988) 
Steinfeld Fabrics Company, Inc. (Local 1001) 
Highland Prints, Inc. (Local 1121) 
Winston Prints, Inc. (Local 1121)
Faith Mills, Inc. (Local 1122) 
Local 1277
Metrotex, Inc. (Local 1318) 
Price Fire and Waterproofing Company (Local 1318) 
Atlas Fibres Company, Inc. (Local 1338) 
Local 1818
Local 1420</p><p>Hudson Valley Area Joint Board 
(formed in 1957 from the merger of the Columbia County and the Mid-Hudson Joint Boards, TWUA) The Berkshire Joint Board Local Chapters are also listed here.</p><p>A. D. Julliard (Local 96) 
Hightstown Rug Co. (Local 200) 
Baldwin NAFI Division of Chris-Craft (Local 237) 
Chris-Craft (Local 237) 
NAFI Division of Chris Craft (Local 237) 
Cohoes Fabric Printers (Local 346)
E and S Finishing Corporation (Local 464) 
Elk Piece Dye Works (Local 464) 
Piermont Sales Corporation (Local 464) 
SD Sales Corporation (Local 464) 
Mohasco Corporation (Local 489) 
Mohawk Carpet Mills (Local 489) 
Fownes Brothers (Local 646) 
Label Products Corporation (Local 683) 
Modern Dust Bag Company, Inc. (Local 683) 
Modern Filters, Inc. (Local 683) 
Rockland Knitting Company (Local 683) 
Lorbrook Corporation (Local 791) 
Textile By-Products Company, Inc. (Local 791) 
Bernhard Altman International Corporation (Local 792) 
High Rock Mills (Local 792) 
Philmont Finishing Corporation (Local 792) 
Zamax Manufacturing Company (Local 683)
Berkshire - Dewey and Almy Chemical Division of W. R. Grace and Co. (Local 841) 
Berkshire - W. R Grace and Co.--Dewey and Almy Chemical Division (Local 841)
French-American-British Woolens Corp. (Local 898) 
S. Stroock and Company, Inc. (Local 898) 
William Barnet and Son, Inc. (Local 964) 
Albany Parlor Company (Local 976) 
House of Montague (Local 976) 
Montague Upholstering Company (Local 976) 
Star Textile and Research (Local 976) 
Garnerville Holding Company (Local 982) 
I.M.I. Warp Knits, Inc. (Local 1001) 
Leewin Fabrics (Local 1001) 
Steinfeld Fabrics Company (Local 1001) 
Blouses by Vera (Local 1032) 
Prince High Rock Mills, Inc. (Local 1032) 
Prince Mills, Inc. (Local 1032) 
Printex Corporation (Local 1032) 
Elite Manufacturing Company (Local 1122) 
Elite Yarn Corporation (Local 1122) 
Faith Mills, Inc. (Local 1122) 
Hudson Glue Corporation (Local 1246) 
Hudson Industries Corporation (Local 1246) 
Insl-X (Local 1277) 
Berkshire - James Hunter Machine Company (Local 1280)
Steiner and Company (Local 1351) 
Lynrus Company (Local 1318) 
Metrotex, Inc. (Local 1318) 
Atlas Fibers (Local 1338) 
Mastercraft Industries (Local 1338) 
Skydyne, Inc. (Local 1410 and Federal Labor Union No. 24087, AFL) 
Jack Barnett and Sons (Local 1420) 
Jack Barnett Slipper Company (Local 1420)
Roselle Shoe Corporation (Local 1420) 
A and W Products Co., Inc. (Local 1456) 
Crown Carton (Local 1466) 
Maybern Corporation (Local 1466) 
Vaucanson Silk Mills (Local 1477) 
Ace Fibers Company (Local 1537) 
Ace Fibre Mills, Inc. (Local 1537) 
Go-Bar Footwear Company (Local 1537) 
Inflated Products Contract (Local 1596) 
Change-O-Matic Corporation (Local 1625) 
International Cord and Thread Corporation (Local 1625) 
Carnegie Coating Company (Local 1648) 
Carnegie Industries (Local 1648) 
K and P Enterprises, Inc., T/A Carnegie Industries (Local 1648) 
T/A Carnegie Industries (Local 1648) 
Sealy of Eastern New York, Inc. (Local 1714) 
BAM Industries (Local 1761) 
Beaver Cloth Cutting Machines, Inc. (Local 1761) 
Academic Press (Local 1870) 
Johnson Reprint Corporation (Local 1870) 
Futura Fabrics Corp. (Local 1873) 
Cryogenic Structures, Inc. (Local 1916) 
Fasco Coated Products (Local 1939) 
Packaging Lithographers Division, Packaging Systems Corp. (Local 1939) 
Packaging Systems Corporation (Local 1939) 
Ogden Allied Industrial Service Corporation (Local 1939-O) 
X-Tyal International Corporation (Local 1946) 
Cohoes Sleeping Bag Factory/Sander Consumer Product Corporation Local 2317) 
Mohawk and Hudson River Humane Society, Inc. (Local 2317) 
Sander Consumer Products Corporation (Local 2317) 
Universal Needle Craft Corporation (Local 2317) 
Hoerner Waldorf Bag Co. (Local 2318)
Industrial Knitted Fabrics &amp; Finishing Corporation (Local 2325) 
Keuffel and Esser Company (Local 2342) 
Berkshire Hathaway, Inc. (Local Unknown) 
Lion Brand, Inc. (Stottville Independent Union) </p>  </odd>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions -- New York (State)</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Labor</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union. Hudson Valley Joint Board.</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_a3e25212804bd99f47b44bf05070dbfe" level="series"><did><unittitle>Hudson Valley Area Joint Board</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8.19 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1919/1989" type="inclusive">1919-1989</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial></did><arrangement id="aspace_46fb594f5a3e680f4e7f420a9ae1402c"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_e47bd8fcd5dede33796e45705226b71c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains records related to the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board. This series is divided into four sub-series. The first sub-series contains the subjetc files of the Joint Board. The second sub-series contains records relating to the Textile Workers Union of America (TWUA), also known as the Amalgamated Clothing and Textiles Workers Union (ACTWU). The third sub-series cotnains local chapter files and the fourth sub-series is contains records associated with the union councils of the AFL-CIO.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_896024d345dddd6cedd60e33dc36afec" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subject Files</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.59 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1919/1989" type="inclusive">1919-1989</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial></did><arrangement id="aspace_f2dedcc0d19bed90bb27b7582a05f840"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This sub-series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_47cf545cf5396fd046f75f9d3174f057"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This sub-series contains the subject files of the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board. Included in the subject files are records relating to the organization of the Board, arbitration documents, contracts, correspondence, meeting minutes, and bylaws and constitutions. This series also contains records relating to the Berkshire Joint Board, which the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board oversaw until it left in 1969 to join the Conneticut Joint Board. This series also contains buttons that were worn by the union members to show political support.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ae810ba8e6bb401df7e3f827fafe8e63" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Textile Workers Union of America (TWUA)</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.6 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1919/1989" type="inclusive">1919-1989</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial></did><arrangement id="aspace_1d3dc74ab2008095fc00f7d2039c91b0"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This sub-series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_5c61ffa0c439215097f29029ae2ef591"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This sub-series contains records relating to the Textile Workers Union of America (TWUA). When the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board was formed in 1957 through the merger of the Columbia County and Mid-Hudson Valley Joint Boards, it was already affiliated with the Textile Workers Union of America (TWUA). The TWUA merged with the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (ACWA) in 1976 to form the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU). This series contains the records of the assistant state director of the TWUA, as well as the international representation files of the union.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4d920f95dd63d40c8861003da5d756ab" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Local Files</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5.4 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1919/1989" type="inclusive">1919-1989</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial></did><arrangement id="aspace_f25a93e5bd3f9f704517b407b23a7469"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This sub-series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_246d2b480804bb665ee0d551da606a88"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This sub-series contains the records of the local chapters of the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board. Each local chapter had  their own set of records. These records include arbitration documents, bylaws, contracts, and meeting minutes.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f645b803b5801df164327bd5ffd9287d" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Central Labor Union Councils - AFL-CIO</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.6 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1919/1989" type="inclusive">1919-1989</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial></did><arrangement id="aspace_821a182b4840ae3e60e7d7e87f9ce199"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This sub-series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_c828028a7939a5dede18755bed00f2be"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains the records of central union councils affiliated with the AFL-CIO. The TWUA, which the Hudson Valley Area was a part of, joined the AFL-CIO around 1976. Prior to the formation of the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board, the Columbia County Joint Board held the records of the Upper Hudson Area Industrial Council, CIO. The Upper Hudson Area Industrial Council became the Upper Hudson Area Central Labor Union, AFL-CIO in 1958. The records were then transfered from the Columbia County Joint Board to the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board in 1958-1959. The Hudson Valley Area Joint Board also oversaw he records of the Central Labor Union of New York, AFL-CIO.</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_ece7a6925e58128fa55b3a7f3aa88a0a" level="series"><did><unittitle>Amsterdam Joint Board</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.8 cubic feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1919/1989" type="inclusive">1919-1989</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial></did><arrangement id="aspace_6dcf744092dd427f63b1d771ace1b0dd"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_a06aaa912970d9e7577272849c3bbcf2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains the records of the Amsterdam Joint Board which was chartered in 1942. The Amsterdam Joint Board joined the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board in 1968. Included in the records are documents relating to the founding of the board and their bylaws and constitutions. The records also contain arbitration documents, constitutions, meeting minutes, and contracts of local chapters of the board.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d0d9ea51a1be7384cc45d1ee4cbe524e" level="series"><did><unittitle>Capital District Area Joint Board</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.6 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1919/1989" type="inclusive">1919-1989</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial></did><arrangement id="aspace_9eee2d0d3fae1e5fe25bbca954c6c686"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_92c4343344ab5e9543de3598328d2fb2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains the records of the Capital District Area Joint Board. The Capital District Area Joint Board which was chartered in 1937, became a part of the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board in 1968. This series contains records of the main board, including meeting minutes, bylaws, and constitutions. The series also includes local chapter arbitration documents, meeting minutes, and bylaws. This series also contains records related to the Troy Area Industrial Union Council, CIO, which was associated with the Capital District Area Joint Board.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e369f371aa7286b11ba2d12ed9eb055e" level="series"><did><unittitle>Columbia County Joint Board</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.44 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1919/1989" type="inclusive">1919-1989</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial></did><arrangement id="aspace_c93347f9204e4b5ee45d0f9821016b59"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_9ee4fa1c0b0c1975a263ecb8cd4c8cc1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains the records of the Columbia County Joint Board. The Columbia County Joint Board, which was chartered in 1947, merged with the Mid-Hudson Joint Board to form the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board in 1957. Ths series contains the main board's meeting minutes, bylaws, and contracts, as well as arbitration documents, bylaws, and constitutions for the local chapters. This series also contains a scrapbook with newspapers and photographs of the board.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_fee375aeca047c0ef74281cb8dfe6d3f" level="series"><did><unittitle>Mid-Hudson Valley Joint Board</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1919/1989" type="inclusive">1919-1989</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial></did><arrangement id="aspace_9a5a91833cec3e26a1e52f21d562e12d"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_1cf2d8de884a766eee98f1134dede117"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains the records of the Mid-Hudson Valley Joint Board. The Mid-Hudson Valley Joint Board was chartered in 1948 and merged with the Columbia County Joint Board to form the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board in 1957. This series contains meeting minutes, arbitration documents, bylaws, constitutions, and correspondence.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
