<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>apap190</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Pyle, Ralph; Papers <num>apap190</num></titleproper><author>Processed by unprocessed.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-06-04 23:00:17 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Ralph Pyle Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="local">Pyle, Ralph, 1925-2012</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>apap190</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.17 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1951/1951" type="inclusive">1951</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_33c94810d7d280a0f552d4f3287e3d4d">This collection consists of photographs of New York Governor Thomas Deweys' visit to  Korea in 1951.  U.S. Army Staff Sargeant Ralph Pyle took the photographs.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_c3b98c895fa308329901288985674619">English.</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_a3c842b26123965bda29b9cd58b863a8">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_3c8861b4befa1159451d56443400e39e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_c85036c8224341fe5467a943682e25c4">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e7eac3b60a1b66b21c8d2314adb3f179">
    <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
<p>Ralph Reeves Pyle Jr. was born in May 1925 in Ohio. Pyle was drafted in to the army during World War II. During his time in the Army, Pyle was stationed in Kentucky, California, and Hawaii. Pyle was trained as an anti-aircraft gunner. After the War, Pyle began learning photography and eventually was asked to use his skill during the Korean War when he was drafted in 1950. Pyle was sent to Korea and placed in the 51st Signal Battalion. During his time there, he photographed mission operations. Pyle took photos of various battles, peace talks, and negotiations, as well as photos of the New York Governor Thomas Dewey’s trip to Korea in 1951. </p><p>Pyle was discharged from the Army in 1951 and continued his photograph famous people and places. Pyle photographed President Ford and President Reagan, and was inducted into Indiana’s Photography Hall of Fame before his death in December 2012. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_bce152edc34d23664fc014895fde7168">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of photographs of New York Governor Thomas Deweys' visit to Korea in 1951</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_7ed6ef38f3496eeb2418ca0f1baab572">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_e4189d740dbb69ae3c0a5fcd5021ab71">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Ralph Pyle donated his papers to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections in  2004.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_e8254d4c1c92ef8f3d9a3dba5fed1872">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_04ab7881e2ae484f6f99488083eeae17">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_a777db8801db2f55ab8355cf82564031">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Ralph Pyle Papers, 1951. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Pyle Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Pyle, Ralph, 1925-2012</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
