<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap254.xml">apap254</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Hastings, James F.; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>Hastings, James F.; Papers <num>apap254</num></titleproper><author>Processed by Clancey Staldine</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2025</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-08-22 01:03:03 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Hastings, James F. Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap254</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8.68 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1956/1976" type="inclusive">1956-1976</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1956/1976" type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_8404047cac40bab2f00e99176204744e">This collection documents James F. Hastings time as a member of the New York State Assembly from the Cattaraugus County district from 1963-1965, a member of the New York State Senate from 1966-1968, and a Representative for New York in the United States House of Representatives from 1969 to his resignation in 1976.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_3bf80f483e68bc1b772d3430d6292ac5">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_61be415e29015193e951f86f0cce7f48" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_0be19fb45d166cc1cf2fc42d262a6fc8">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Clancey Staldine in 2025.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_dc91c3ce215cc5e4bee56ee8f7409802">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>
James F. Hasting was born in Olean, Cattaraugus County, New York on April 10, 1926. Hasting served in the United States Navy in flight squadrons from 1943 through 1946. After the War, Hasting was a sales representative for Procter and Gamble. In 1952, Hasting began to manage the radio station WHDL, and in 1964 he became the national advertising manager for the Times Herald, and a partner in the real estate and insurance firm of Hastings &amp; Jewell.  During this time, Hasting began to get involved in local politics and served as a member of the Allegany (N.Y.) Town Board for ten years, and Allegany police justice for five years. </p><p>Hasting, a Republican was nominated to the New York State Assembly in 1962 and sat as a member until 1965, when he earned a seat in the New York State Senate in 1966.  In this position, Hasting was a delegate to the Republican National Convention in 1968. Hasting was also a delegate to the Republican National Convention in 1972, after securing a seat in the United States Congress in 1969. Hasting was in office until 1976, and served in the 91st-94th Congresses. </p><p>Hasting resigned on January 20, 1976 to become the President of the Associated Industries Trade Group in Albany, New York. That same year, Hastings was convicted of mail fraud and filming false payroll information. Hasting served 14 months in the United States Penitentiary, Allenwood. After Hasting was released, he moved to Florida. Eventually Hasting moved back to Allegany and he died there on October 24, 2014.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_c4b1914ed4498ef691d3a1358c1873ea">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains papers from James F. Hastings time in the New York State Assembly, New York State Senate, and U.S. House of Representatives. It contains research, legislation, correspondence, and newspaper clippings throughout the years of Hastings' political career. While James F. Hastings sponsored a variety of legislation, there is a focus on background research and bills from his time in the House Subcommittee on Public Health.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_7fe586606dc7dcb94f6b2fe54ca1efa4">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged into two series – Series 1 is his time in Congress, and Series 2 is the compilation of his time in the New York State Assembly and New York State Senate. The files are arranged in chronological order.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_fce85ed3dd437f2e74b874c12e478159">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>James F. Hasting donated his papers to Syracuse University in 1968-1969. Additional materials were donated in 1976. In 2006, all materials were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_ffefc5952e5a682f843c420f1acd9ee7">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_4e86eb361f07e74f88d3fb6d0da2a958">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_fd1188b7bffd474278b05c9903ac8b83">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, James F. Hasting Papers, 1956-1976. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Hasting Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <function source="local">Hastings, James F., 1926-2014</function>
    <subject source="meg">Politics and Politicians</subject>
    <occupation source="local">New York State-- Assembly</occupation>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York State--Senate</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Bills (legislative records)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Newspaper clippings</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">United States. Congress. House</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_7e237562217463a23d5c0fba8a8b8b3a" level="series"><did><unittitle>U.S. Congress</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.21 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1963/1976" type="inclusive">1963-1976</unitdate><unitdate normal="1956/1976" type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_8c2a1287fda99c469a5cd51c69ba099d"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged chronologically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_2132c068b4df2b92ed974f2a13100611"><head>Scope and Contents</head></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_fc446f100721807f7d706b11707503df" level="series"><did><unittitle>New York State Legislature</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.47 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1956/1968" type="inclusive">1956-1968</unitdate><unitdate normal="1956/1976" type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_5b173f86fc5087e15a2e58af5cee51e0"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged chronologically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_914d8dd7e9559909fc7b0253cc6a0a0f"><head>Scope and Contents</head></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
