<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>apap269</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Peterson, Dutton S.; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>Peterson, Dutton S.; Papers <num>apap269</num></titleproper><author>Processed by unprocessed. </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-09-29 00:16:54 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Dutton S. Peterson Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap269</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">105.44 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1892/1965" type="inclusive">1892-1965</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_3581a6997faa92a567f0c09d8aef2192">Dutton S. Peterson was born in Costello, Pennsylvania on December 10, 1894. Peterson served in the U.S. Marine Corps during World War I and was a Methodist minister. Peterson was a member of the New York State Assembly from Schuyler County (1937-1942) and the New York State Senate (46th District 1953-1954, 50th District 1955-1964). Peterson died on October 20, 1964 and was buried at the Laurel Hill Cemetery in Odessa, New York. This collection contains materials relating to his time in the New York State Congress.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_b6f6038378498b8281b47d568d113dba">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_97281d2480079b38a57afa158de39307" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_602ab15a1f01a9857289bd760b95e9ff">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_d90d757cf00878f52d552f0622fa92a6">
    <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
<p>Dutton S. Peterson was born in Costello, Pennsylvania on December 10, 1894. Peterson enlisted in the U.S. Marine Corps and fought in France during World War I. When Peterson returned home, he graduated from the Practical Bible Training School in 1922, and finished his B.A. at Ohio Wesleyan University in 1924. Peterson went on to get a degree from Boston University School of Theology in 1927 and became a Methodist minister. Peterson was the pastor of the Methodist Church in Odessa, Schuyler County, New York from 1937 to 1960. Peterson was a member of Grange, American Legion, Disabled American Veterans, Sons of the American Revolution, Freemasons, Rotary, Delta Sigma Rho, and Phi Beta Kappa.</p><p>
Peterson served as a Republican member of the New York State Assembly and represented Schuyler County from 1937-1942. Peterson then went on to serve in the New York State Senate from 1953, until his death on October 20, 1964 where he was buried at the Laurel Hill Cemetery in Odessa, New York. He was survived by his wife and his six children. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_5bc4099587c2cac2bf47a02b355a3e17">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of materials from Albert Blumenthal's service in the New York State Congress, including correspondence, bills, subject files, reports, and press releases.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_d669b12a180f413adad12032c6dcd57e">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_ef469da17b4b96bd47f44128975a2758">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Dutton S. Peterson originally donated his materials to the Syracuse University Libraries in 1962. Additional materials were donated after his death in 1964 through 1969, by his wife and children. The collection was transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Colleciton and Archives in 2006.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_129e8ef4fcaab0365b7147e225838477">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_36d34c30ff0bc9d2130f41f8baa27ca7">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_dc9895b97c0a6f201edc18237a333596">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Dutton S. Peterson Papers, 1892-1965. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Peterson Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="local">Petterson, Dutton S., 1894-1964</geogname>
    <subject source="meg">Politics and Politicians</subject>
    <occupation source="local">New York State-- Assembly</occupation>
    <occupation source="local">New York State-- Senate</occupation>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
