<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap412.xml">apap412</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">New Hampshire Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty; Records</titleproper><titleproper>New Hampshire Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty; Records <num>apap412</num></titleproper><author>Jodi Boyle</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2024</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-07-24 23:01:13 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>New Hampshire Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty Records</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap412</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.33 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1997/2017" type="inclusive">1997-2017</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_798d8aa223f1b4c3a88212ac616588d8">This collection documents the day-to-day activities of the New Hampshire Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_ba081a39b13e6067690d4101b6bd0cfb">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_5dc7270cf56cfc587f0d5921fc9770db">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>This collection contains legislative files, correspondence, subject files, press releases, clippings, and financial materials for the organization.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_3cdd3fbe45e51e0d7141d5f4fc671873">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_c95db9d47deb8655f39ff1b7bfb7af4e">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_721445bd778018a2f5896587194779d2">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Barbara Keshen of the New Hampshire Caolition to Abolish the Death Penalty donated all items in this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collecitons and Archives in July 2024.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_57a6635042b67e878e4f78bb902e882a">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, New Hampshire Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty Records, 1997-2017. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the New Hampshire Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <userestrict id="aspace_78ca0a8ea8b023b59d19c4188f9d6979">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <arrangement id="aspace_923c72dc0686b730474ea5e039db96f4">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is currently unprocessed and is not yet arranged. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_1fb43dc9b9e568e2aa2ef0993a084127">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The New Hampshire Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty was comprised of numerous organizations and individuals who were committed to ending the death penalty in the state of New Hampshire through outreach, advocacy, and education. The Coalition included religious groups, human rights activists, and relatives of murder victims.</p>

<p>In May 2019, following the successful work of the Coalition and others, New Hampshire abolished the death penalty when the state Senate voted to override Gov. Chris Sununu's 2018 veto of a bill to repeal capital punishment. A week earlier the New Hampshire House also voted to override the veto.</p>

<p>Following the state's abolishment of capital punishment, the Coalition wound down from its multi-year efforts, but maintained a presence in the state to respond to any possible effort to reinstate the death penalty and to share its journey with other organizations fighting to abolish the death penalty in other states or countries.</p>
  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <function source="local">New Hampshire Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty</function>
    <function source="lcsh">Capital punishment--New Hampshire</function>
    <subject source="meg">Death Penalty</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
