<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap414.xml">apap414</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Bromley, Ray; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>Bromley, Ray; Papers <num>apap414</num></titleproper><author>Jodi Boyle</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2024</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-11-26 01:10:55 -0500</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Ray Bromley Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap414</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">71 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1953/2024" type="inclusive">1953-2024</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_7109e04fb4609c3a3f930774c70aa25a">This collection contains materials related to Ray Bromley's geography, development, and planning research and scholarship, including the planning for the building of the University at Albany.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_d880b9d91d04da4c0ab3cd8ca43801d1">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_a2a553a4b5e90c6c91694cda1ebfbe15">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>This collection contains Ray Bromley's research on architect Edward Durell Stone and Stone's projects worldwide; research on the planning and building of the University at Albany's Uptown Campus including Stone's architectural work; research on marketplaces and trade centers, including reprints and offprints of journal articles, clippings, microfilm, and working papers; geography and planning conference materials; research on capital citities; research on Patrick Geddes and Victor V. Branford, especially their partnershp in the social sciences; correspondence, reports, and clippings.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_08b0353deca60e025402edef67d4b4ad">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_37859e754e90c18f507f16e47d4d7e3a">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_084c1d9d1288012959630068c8d1417c">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Ray Bromley donated all items in this collection in 2024 and 2025.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_a17473ddc1a8c1e86b671c50b46551b4">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Ray Bromley Papers, 1953-2024. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Bromley Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <userestrict id="aspace_a189b71ef0858ea3936bd6b4d3f9facf">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <arrangement id="aspace_81870290fe4375a3075339671d5c846f">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is currently unprocessed and is not yet arranged. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_93d1426bdb9cb6c9e54603b73a7521d3">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Ray Bromley is Professor Emeritus, Geography and Planning Department at the University at Albany. Dr. Bromley received his B.A. in Geography; M.A. in Geography; and Ph.D. in Social Geography, Regional Development and Latin American Studies from Cambridge University. He has served as a professor at the University at Albany for four decades. During his tenure, he also was Vice Provost for International Education for nearly a decade.</p>

<p>Earlier in his career, Dr. Bromley was a Lecturer at Swansea University in the United Kingdom; a Visiting Associate Professor of Public Administration, and Regional Planning Consultant to the Peru Project at the Maxwell School of Citizenship and Public Affairs at Syracuse University; and a United Nations Regional Planning Consultant to the Government of Ecuador.</p>

<p>Dr. Bromley has held Fulbright Teaching and Research Fellowships to the Universidad Nacional de Ingeniería, Lima, Perú and the School of Planning and Architecture, New Delhi, India and is the author or editor of hundreds of books and articles. </p>

  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <function source="lcsh">Bromley, Ray</function>
    <subject source="lcsh">Correspondence</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Administrative reports</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
