<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>apap277</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Selkirk, Russell; Papers <num>apap277</num></titleproper><author>Processed by unprocessed.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-09-03 13:14:08 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Russell Selkirk Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap277</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">23.6 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1944/1966" type="inclusive">1944-1966</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_03f4d93e1874f6fa0996cea58ced8b6c">Russell Selkirk was born on his family's farm in Selkirk, Schoharie County on October 20, 1905. He worked for the first New York Power and Light Company and established a hardware store in 1935. He was active in the National Hardware Association, the New York State Retail Hardware Association and the Sterling Insurance Company. Selkirk was an elected member of the New York State Assembly in 1959 and held that position until 1965. In 1966, he joined the Joint Legislative Committee on the State's Economy, Imitation Food Products and Problems and Reapportionment. Selkirk died in 1993.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_98c71fca67fd18ee1036dabfdef8bea8">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_a52f5f212f722e82c36df11b939df929" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_541dd984c391b6ed237315cc9323f0d3">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_11926c5b5e9576204161e08f56204c82">
    <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
<p>Russell Selkirk was born on the family farm in Selkirk, Schoharie County October 20, 1905. He attended Albany High School and left the family farm in 1929 to work for the first New York Power and Light Corporation. In 1935, Selkirk established a retail hardware business in Cobleskill and served as president of the Selkirk Hardware, Inc. He was an active leader of the National Hardware Association and the New York State Retail Hardware Association. Selkirk served on the directory and as Vice President of the Sterling Insurance Company, as well as director of the Cobleskill Savings and Loan Association. He served on an advisory committee for the State University Agricultural and Technical Institute at Cobleskill. 
Selkirk was elected to the New York State Assembly in the 1958 General Election and held the seat through 1965. In 1966, he became a member of the Joint Legislative Committees on the State's Economy, Imitation Food Products and Problems and Reapportionment. Selkirk died in 1993.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_5161cba35f9f0484f53ee50084cd5bdf">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of materials from Albert Blumenthal's service in the New York State Assembly, including constituent correspondence, legislation, newspaper clippings, and assembly memos mailed to constituents by Assemblyman Selkirk.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_33e895872878221defbd74b35b55166b">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_37ee25b64d66263e492788d4602723e0">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Russell Selkirk donated his records to Syracuse University in 1966. In 2006, the papers were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_923bb086f372b5eb732a72b911b7b795">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_90874ef5a9fcba9b97f3a3433cd8963f">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_750289223a884ded683f7e4069e4c166">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Russell Selkirk Papers, 1944-1966. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Selkirk Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="local">Selkirk, Russell, 1905-1993</geogname>
    <geogname source="meg">Politics and Politicians </geogname>
    <occupation source="local">New York State-- Assembly</occupation>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
