<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap383.xml">apap383</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Stein, Eleanor; Papers <num>apap383</num></titleproper><author>Jodi Boyle</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2020 January</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-08-12 23:00:05 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Eleanor Stein Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="local" source="local">Stein, Eleanor, 1946-</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>apap383</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">16.0 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1962/2018" type="inclusive">1962-2018</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_fa9cb87e4b1c1d1a21bade2280e623ab">The Eleanor Stein Papers contain professional and personal materials primarily related to Stein's commitment to enviornmental justice and her work in the field of climate change law.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_336cc8c9a150ca3b29815b4a05f312b4">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_2a6955419a86d2f0cdc0027b39ffa2a1">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_1d8dc37bfb53e6fd9e0d91323c61a890">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>The collection includes Eleanor Stein's scholarly writings, biographical materials, her Albany Law teaching materials, her University at Albany teaching materials, awards and ephemera, research materials, writings, notes, and books.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_415ea8ecdbf035b03dff0b99b4fe4ecf">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The collection is currently unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_f47356aa498aebf2757679b91a14d824">
    <head>Arrangement of Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_28ce59975f24cf9096a0e4011cf94e6b">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>For more than 25 years, Eleanor Stein worked at the New York State Public Service Commission, serving for two of those decades as an administrative law judge and mediator.  Among her accomplishments, Stein presided over New York’s Consolidated Edison climate adaptation and resiliency collaborative, managed the state’s Renewable Portfolio Standard and Energy Efficiency Portfolio Standard proceedings, and mediated the prudence investigation into the consolidated Edison summer 2006 Queens power outage.  During her tenure at the Commission, Stein was part of the Climate Action Council and a member of the leadership team that crafted strategies to reach a target of 80% greenhouse gas reduction for New York State by 2050.  Stein retired from her position in 2015.  </p><p>Stein continues to lecture on climate change in the courts and climate change law at the University at Albany and at Albany Law School.  She is a board member of the Rocky Mountain Institute eLab and of EcoViva.  Stein also consults on clean energy and climate change.</p><p>Stein attended Barnard College and received her Bachelor of Arts degree from the University of Manchester.  She attended Columbia Law School and received her Juris Doctor from the City University of New York School of Law.  Stein also holds a Master of Laws LLM in Climate Change Law and Policy from the University of Strathclyde, Glasgow.</p>  </bioghist>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_0668c8ea25979dceec2488410b9ffa2b">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Eleanor Stein donated materials in this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in December <date normal="2019">2019</date> and February <date normal="2020">2020</date>.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_7ee48c6207f44717561b1910792613f2">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_210f671ac6c5fb260c4350e95aa5320c">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_8cd8eb74790ffda128622980e81dedd7">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Eleanor Stein Papers, 1962-2018. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Stein Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="local">Stein, Eleanor, 1946-</geogname>
    <subject source="meg">Albany, New York</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Conservation and the Environment</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Social Activists and Public Advocates</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
