<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>apap281</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Terry, John Hart; Papers <num>apap281</num></titleproper><author>Processed by unprocessed. </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2020</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-10-28 18:33:05 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection Level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>John Hart Terry Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap281</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">41.8 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1962/1972" type="inclusive">1962-1972</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_0d23af9ec64a31342e67d792ecf31596">John Hart Terry was a U.S. Representative from New York. Terry was born in Syracuse, NY on November 14, 1924. Terry was elected and reelected to six terms on the Onondaga County Board of Supervisors, 1948-1958; appointed assistant secretary to the Governor of New York, 1959-1961; a member of the Inter-Group Relations Advisory Council of the New York State Division of Housing and Community Renewal, 1961-1962; and elected to five terms as a member of the New York State Assembly, 1963-1970. His papers contain records relating to his work as a politician in New York State.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_bd08bc7a34ecf72bf7670b9dcf41aafc">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_5bf735cdec995ce03c9e8cea9d702609" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_2fac76f0f6c78f97644045ea1d9cbdc3">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Collection is unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_29e793c2af4fa42cdda13d972fbaba28">
    <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
<p>John Hart Terry was a U.S. Representative from New York. Terry was born in Syracuse, NY on November 14, 1924. He attended public and private schools in Syracuse and was a pre-law candidate at the University of Notre Dame in1945. Terry entered the U.S. Army in September 1943 as a private and served in the European Theater of Operations with the rank of regimental sergeant major. He received the Bronze Star with clusters and the Purple Heart before being discharged with the rank of first lieutenant in 1946</p><p>After his time in the United States Army, Terry received a LL.B. (J.D.) from Syracuse University in 1948. Terry was admitted to the New York Bar in 1948 and commenced practice in Syracuse. He was also admitted to the bar of the United States Supreme Court and the District of Columbia. Terry was elected and reelected to six terms on the Onondaga County Board of Supervisors from 1948-1958.  While he was on the Board of Supervisors, he was also the assistant secretary for the New York State Republican Convention in 1958. After this position Terry was appointed assistant secretary to the Governor of New York from 1959-1961. Terry was also a member of the Inter-Group Relations Advisory Council of the New York State Division of Housing and Community Renewal from 1961-1962.</p><p> Terry was elected to five terms as a member of the New York State Assembly from 1963-1970. In this position, Terry was chairman of the New York State United Services Organization and served as a delegate for the New York State Republican Convention delegate in 1962. Terry was elected as a Republican to the Ninety-second Congress (January 3, 1971-January 3, 1973); and was not a candidate for reelection in 1972. In his free time, Terry was senior vice president, general counsel and secretary of Niagara Mohawk Power Corp., (1973-1987), and resumed the practice of law in Syracuse after his time in public office. John Hart Terry died on October 20, 2001 in Syracuse, New York. Terry was survived by his wife Catherine Jean and their four daughters, one who he adopted from his wife's first marriage, from which she was a widow. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_bf7f1f724cc1e051461cd2a2ba579d6b">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of materials from John Hart Terry's service in the New York State Assembly and U.S. Congress, including correspondence, bills, subject files, reports, and legislation.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_c445fdf874bdd478ef5c190c827c4c50">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_24e9909302898d2104a6c89ee19e4590">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>John Terry donated his records to Syracuse University in 1969-1970. Additional accessions were donated in 1972-1974 and 1982. In 2006, the materials were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_1151d1ae7d3d3f13bd29a817baae90fe">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_ab650617f69545aec9fd800531200ea6">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_2cdb6da9068e220f0c7dd1c2ee9366e8">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, John Hart Terry Papers, 1962-1972. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Terry Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="local">Terry, John Hart, 1924-2001</geogname>
    <subject source="meg">Politics and Politicians</subject>
    <occupation source="local">New York State-- Assembly</occupation>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
