<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap348.xml">apap348</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Scheuerman, William; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>Scheuerman, William; Papers <num>apap348</num></titleproper><author>unprocessed</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2016</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-11-20 01:03:34 -0500</date>.</creation></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2016 December 26</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Brian Keough</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>William Scheuerman Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap348</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4.5 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1982/2025" type="inclusive">1982-2025</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_52ef55817f6084139262fd0d44a33bfb">This collection contains material related to William Scheuerman, a local, state, and national labor leader.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_c1f04680882cc0f7567861430eadee78">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_bca7cef270bcb1e5831c8aa6b819f4ad" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_617537b1d0186a2ff81fe9575e23869c">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2016 by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_9d772fe4a89faff28fc7fc2671d7d18d">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_3622228a69904bd5c8d5a736f703a572">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_3b39e6fd3a7f9dddd2be9a15fafbf99a">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by William Scheuerman in 2014, and 2016-2019.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e72d35fd3302c1ad25d1ad7cbff8d67c">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>William Scheuerman is a local, state, and national labor leader. He has served as president of the National Labor College, president and vice president for academics of and chief negotiator for United University Professions, and on the board of directors and as an executive committee member for New York State United Teachers among others. He also was professor in the Department of Political Science at the State University of New York at Oswego.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_2320e6d7e0a3f8a0dddd9431291feec9">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains material related to William Scheuerman's labor union work, including United University Professions, correspondence; articles, speeches, photographs, commentaries, letters to the editor, political materials, including those from the 1996 and 2000 Democratic National Conventions, awards, and VHS tapes.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_620073eaa10e3bfbf241a4db0833f409">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_cf87fcc8ce8971ff65f9e1f8cae66af5">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, William Scheuerman Papers, 1982-2010. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Scheuerman Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_77e182aa31be36b3fc27fbdad377c9ca">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>The archivist transferred one monograph: <title><emph render="italic">A New American Labor Movement: Decline of Collective Bargaining and the Rise of Direct Action</emph></title> by William Scheuerman to the book division of Special Collections. It will be catalogued and included in the University Library Catalog.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
