<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="unprocessed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap397.xml">apap397</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Zahavi, Gerald; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>Zahavi, Gerald; Papers <num>apap397</num></titleproper><author>Jodi Boyle</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2022</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-10-26 01:10:37 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Gerald Zahavi Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap397</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.5 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="2000/2006" type="inclusive">2000-2006</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_a38038d38a375cf55561ef0adc6a39f4">This collection predominantly includes Professor Gerald Zahavi's oral history project files.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_c22144b0f50425e3f3d46876199fc455">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_6eb6f3946ca560dfe634a7d1f010708c">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>This collection predominantly includes oral history project files, many created by Professor Zahavi's students. Each file may consist of audio cassettes or CDs with oral histories, an interview transcript, background material on the subject, and a release form. The collection also contains a small amount of material related to Professor Zahavi's historical research, planned digital initiatives, and project works.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_9fd21b2e4a81c3582858ded2e8acf105">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Dr. Gerald Zahavi is Professor of History and Director of the Documentary Studies Program at the University at Albany, SUNY, where he has been a member of the faculty since 1985. Professor Zahavi received his bachelor's degree from at Cornell University and his master's degree and PhD from the Maxwell School at Syracuse University.  </p><p>Professor Zahavi has taught classes at the University in documentary studies, oral/video history, public history, quantitative methods for historians, historical radio/audio documentary production, film/video documentary production, as well as U.S. social and economic history, American labor and modern U.S. business history, U.S. local and regional history, and a number of general American. history courses. In 2006, he helped create the History Department's Documentary Studies Program. Three years later, he helped introduced a History and Media master's track in the department which is now incorporated within the Public History Program.</p><p>Professor Zahavi is the author of numerous books and articles and the creator of numerous oral histories, documentaries, and digital projects. His research interests include welfare capitalism; the history of General Electric; labor and political radicalism in modern America; Cold War science and politics; and oral/aural history. In 1998, he co-founded the <emph render="italic">Journal for MultiMedia History</emph>, an online, peer-reviewed journal devoted to presenting and reviewing non-print and electronic works of history.</p><p>Beyond his academic responsibilities and interests, Professor Zahavi also seeks to engage a broad audience in history. He hosted <emph render="italic">Talking History</emph>, a weekly radio program broadcast online and on FM for almost 20 years. As a member of the executive committee of the Essex County Historical Society &amp; Adirondack History Museum, Professor Zahavi has helped curate exhibits, served as a media consultant, and worked as an oral/video history project director.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_6f1298cd5ec878ac95b1b434a10799cc">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_577cf503977a2099e0dacdf042488971">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Dr. Gerald Zahavi donated all materials in this collection in 2015, 2017, and 2022.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_38df55f50e7cbf620c3a2e8f8fa1a6d6">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is currently unprocessed and is not yet arranged.</p>  </arrangement>
  <processinfo id="aspace_9bddc60ff1a830bf8dd3620107357069">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The collection is currently unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_3132371e1d1b75f17ca709b1d6cc2e17">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_84c1075b6b3ddd7063614d5c030bf46b">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Gerald Zahavi Papers, 2000-2006. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Zahavi Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <function source="lcsh">Zahavi, Gerald, 1951-</function>
    <geogname source="meg">Albany, New York</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Oral history--New York (State)</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
