<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>apap295</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Meltsner, Michael; Papers <num>apap295</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.
Processed by unprocessed.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-10-28 18:33:32 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Meltsner, Michael Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap295</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1973/2005" type="inclusive">1973-2005</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_6976c592b050c5170830d0434a112969">Michael Meltsner is a prominent lawyer and civil rights activist. Meltsner is also an opponent of the death penalty. The collection contains assorted capital punishment materials including clippings, journal articles, correspondence and files used in writing the death penalty chapters of Michael Meltsner's book, The Making of a Civil Rights Lawyer.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_86068b49fdf4f71a363c47545f050418">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_cc51a4aa7e28b7f09897c88b4a69a99e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_ea55fb47c156f92b06f7727988db8ced">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_5163bd1f6c71d3d4ee4dd3dc0d0e7558">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Michel Meltsner was born in 1937. Meltsner went to Oberlin College and earned his J.D. at Yale Law School. Meltsner was the first assistant counsel to the NAACP Legal Defense and Education Fund. In this positon, he helped lead the integration of Southern hospitals and medical facilities. Melstner also represented Mohammad Ali during a case. </p><p>An opponent of the death penalty, Meltsner also received the Hugo Bedau Award for capital punishment scholarship. Meltsner has also won the Berlin American Academy Prize Fellowship, the Guggenheim Fellowship, and the American Bar Association Silver Gabel media award, as well as a Honorary Doctor of Laws from John Jay College in 2012. A former dean of the Northeeastern University School of Law, he is currently the George J. and Kathleen Waters Matthews distinguished University Professor of law at the University.  Meltsner has published many books on topics like Civil Rights, and the death penalty. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_f4f35a54f19bd922e6669f31683e05b2">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection contains assorted capital punishment materials including clippings, journal articles, correspondence and files used in writing the death penalty chapters of Michael Meltsner's book, The Making of a Civil Rights Lawyer</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_7a5a50aef15f465c4001f7db2a90ee13">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_668d7040733ae551a9552607f016dfd9">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>In 2007, Michael Meltsner donated his papers to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_8b32979e660d1dbe16de1096cb8c55be">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_4d1f457ba559d1673494c5a234e4b3be">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_d621960b937d0cc64c2ae6cbf661d0e6">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Michael Meltsner Papers, 1973-2005. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Meltsner Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="local">Meltsner, Michael., 1937-</geogname>
    <geogname source="meg">Politics and Politicians </geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Civil Rights</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
