<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>apap378</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Harris, Raymond and Sara; Papers <num>apap378</num></titleproper><author>Sheri Sarnoff</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2019</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-05-14 23:00:17 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Raymond and Sara Harris Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="lcsh">Harris, Raymond, 1919-1989</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="lcsh">Harris, Sara, 1921-</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>apap378</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">20 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1942/2016" type="inclusive">1942-2016</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_f584775c5f25ccc8d78e06566f86d363">This collection documents the personal and professional lives of Dr. Raymond and Sara Harris and their involvment in the Albany, N.Y. community.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_271fdc36c3badd62083f06a441d0eee9">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_3d28e3ac4c40965913dcfcd24e397ca5">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_82e9dd21f22b09ca307da03b3a8e1f29">
    <head>Content Description </head>
<p>This collection documents the professional and personal lives of Dr. Raymond and Sara Harris and their work in the Albany community through St. Peters Hospital, the Center for the Study of Aging of Albany N.Y., the Albany Inter-racial Council, and the Albany Jewish Community Center. Materials consist of published articles, books, correspondence, lecture notes, various council meeting minutes, studies on gerontology, newsletters, and family history. The collection also contains audio and visual material related to the field of gerontoloty.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_3be99f32bbfbf828dd1ed6c085eea6f7">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection is currently unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_a795fb3e59f342156dbaf3ea219016eb">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Dr. Raymond and Sara Harris were active members of the Albany, N.Y. community. In 1957, the couple co-founded the Center for the Study of Aging of Albany, N.Y. </p><p>Dr. Raymond Harris was born in Brooklyn, N.Y. on June 26, 1919. A gaduate of Cornell University and Albany Medical College, Harris also served in the Army Medical Corps at the Walter Reed Hospital during the Second World War. Dr. Harris, a published author and seasoned lecturer, was the chief of the sub-department of Cariovascular Medicine at St. Peters Hospital in Albany N.Y. Elected president of the Albany Jewish Community Center, Dr. Harris was active in the field of gerontology, as well as an active member of the Albany community until his death on August 25, 1989. </p><p>Sara Harris was born in Cleveland, Ohio in 1921. After attending the Girls Latin School in Boston, Massachusetts, Harris went on to study at the Unversity of Chicago and the Arts Students League in New York City. An active member in the Albany community, Harris was the executive director of the Center for the Study of Aging of Albany, N.Y., tried to set up a daycare in the Albany area, and sat on the board of directors for the Albany Inter-racial Council. Sara Harris was also a prominent artist in the area and nominated for awards for her skills in painting in drawing. Harris also enjoyed writing poetry and published a book on exercise for people over 50. Sara Harris died on May 15, 2016. </p><p>Both Dr. Raymond and Sara Harris are survived by their children and grandchildren.</p>  </bioghist>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_b6f5ad4b1d3a7b5c6214b32eda0eb109">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>The children of Raymond and Sara Harris donated all materials in the collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 2018.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_ba204558c38b3fb01ab41d3e90f5ea9d">
    <head>Acess</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b9d36e6f4290096d454e0153287fa70c">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_c3b89ad4ff3b98bb302032486b7008b4">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Raymond and Sara Harris Papers, 1960-2007. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Harris Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical care</subject>
    <geogname source="local">Albany (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Gerontology</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Harris, Raymond, 1919-1989</geogname>
    <subject source="meg">Medicine and Health Care</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Harris, Sara, 1921-</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_dbbcf74dcb812ebaa5639e55cfd6d7b3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Biographical</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.83 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1942/2016" type="inclusive">1942-2016</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_d09273f2a6bea3168eea4866e6fde98e"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_d03a53f37aca638c836598844020a3b0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains personal correspondence, personal documents, and photographs of Raymond and Sara Harris. Included in the correspondence are letters to their children, their friends, and other members of their immediate family. Included in the correspondence are family updates and poetry written by Sara Harris. The series also includes information on the lesiure activities enjoyed by the Harris family including tennis games and country clubs. The series also features documents related to the couples involvement in the Albany Jewish Community Center and their temple. The series also features information on Raymond Harris's time in the army, as well as records of the art shows Sara Harris participated in.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_bce4950ff55ff0e3ba9587b0e8902869" level="series"><did><unittitle>Medical Papers</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.0 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1942/1990" type="inclusive">1942-1990</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_945ac0b3e7aca33476441e4e44f885c1"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_ca312873939157f657632f381483d3d2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains the medical files and publications of Raymond Harris during his time in the medical community. Raymond Harris was a cardiologist at St. Peters Hospital in Albany, N.Y. and sat on a variety of committees. Included in this series are medical publications and correspondence between co-workers. This series is restricted because it is unprocessed.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_cf81a7b14aa688c278996610c34ff803" level="series"><did><unittitle>Conferences/Lectures</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.33 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1950/1996" type="inclusive">1950-1996</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_a306c0dfe5ca1056cee79c39585e58a4"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_3fcbe08c802f9265dfb4676aaa2a825e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains the conferences and lectures that Raymond and Sara Harris participated in and attended. The conferences and lectures focused on gerontology and cardiovasular health. Both Raymond and Sara Harris gave lectures to members of the medical community, the Gerontological Society of America, and members of the Albany area. Included in the series are documents from conferences in Japan, China, Italy, and Israel. These records include travel itineraries, postcards, and souvenirs.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_567c37e2eea63e0b632f4e0c1546c499" level="series"><did><unittitle>Center for the Study of Aging</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.17 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1950/2015" type="inclusive">1950-2015</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_43bc4547fc49f21f0b4f3189f9961cb0"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_7fdb20e6e39d16f501fd2415e141287f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains documents related to the Center for the Study of Aging opened by Raymond and Sara Harris. Sara Harris, who was the executive director of the center, was active in the elderly community in Albany, N.Y. Located on Madison Avenue, the Center for the Study of Aging provided programs, lectures, and a community space for the elderly community. Included in the series are documents related to the founding of the center, program events, correspondence related to the center, information about its non profit status, and articles and news clips related to the events that the center hosted. The series also includes published books written by Sara Harris and other members of the gerontology community, as well as publications relating to the centers findings and activities.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_38c6894973d35d21a412e98282eaf429" level="series"><did><unittitle>Albany Activism </unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.0 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1950/1990" type="inclusive">1950-1990</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_541c03e328e4710ec3bdd0945b847af2"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_40bb44f93b5c41cba60c968baaead833"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains documents related to the Harris's involvement in the Albany Community. Both Raymond and Sara Harris were active in the Albany Area Chapter of the American Red Cross and the Democratic Party in Albany. Sara Harris also sat on the Board of the Directors of the Albany Interracial Council which provided services like a day care center, a pool, and a community center to the people of Arbor Hill. Included in the series is correspondence with members of these organizations, documents showing the racial injustices that the Interracial Council fought against, and information about the Albany community at large. This series is restricted because it is currently unprocessed.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7ba9c5e2802727182b4941285e820630" level="series"><did><unittitle>Publications</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.0 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1950/2011" type="inclusive">1950-2011</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_3e3b875c7d8a8271b497f3317ccf113c"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_ff745f2ba360318bbefb33385fd90227"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains publications related to gerontology and cardiovascular health. These publications speak to the interests of Raymond and Sara Harris who subscribed to newsletters and journals to keep updated on the various discoveries in their fields.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
