<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="unprocessed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap380.xml">apap380</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Capital District Regional Planning Commission; Records <num>apap380</num></titleproper><author>Jodi Boyle</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2019</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-10-01 23:01:39 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Capital District Regional Planning Commission Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="lcsh">Capital District Regional Planning Commission</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>apap380</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">41 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1965/2001" type="inclusive">1965-2001</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_45169e8e955298b76eab6dddd47f3504">This collection documents the comprehensive planning work of New York's Capital District Regional Planning Commission across several decades.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_c917f00cfa78bac6ebbc9bb566e68b24">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_31fd64a3100f4b6bb42c756ea59dd082">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>The collection contains plans; proposals; maps; reports; studies; booklets on codes, regulations, and zoning laws; and correspondence.  The materials discuss plans for cities and counties in New York's Capital Region as well as the Adirondacks.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e6e4141bee1f5f2bca68a80b5848c67d">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>The Capital District Regional Planning Commission (CDRPC) is a regional planning and resource center, established pursuant to New York State law, serving Albany, Rensselaer, Saratoga, and Schenectady counties.  CDRPC was created in 1967 by a cooperative agreement amongst these four counties. Its original purpose was to perform and support comprehensive planning work, including surveys, planning services, technical services, and the formulation of plans and policies to promote coordinated development of the entire Capital Region. Over time, the mission of the CDRPC evolved in response to changes in the needs of the Capital Region, funding sources, organizational structures, and information technology. While continuing to provide a wide variety of comprehensive planning services, CDRPC has also assumed the functions of Data and Information Center, Economic Development District, Foreign-Trade Zone Administrator, Climate Smart Communities Coordinator, and Water Quality Manager.</p>  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_e263047660e991efa5edf9950f7aa4db">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection is currently unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_ee697176effbd9677b6c2727566f23e7">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_3355ebd283d1234c47718a40540bc71e">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Mark A. Castiglione, executive director, Capital District Regional Planning Commission, donated all materials in this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in July <date normal="2019">2019</date>.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_360f38dd2ff9a1b7a912f0d1585c2ab3">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_29a84f6ffaa30a87d542cdb62a5d5aab">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_05cca7707f163af71e745118c632ab5c">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Capital District Regional Planning Commission Records, 1965-2001. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Capital District Regional Planning Commission Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Capital District Regional Planning Commission</geogname>
    <geogname source="meg">Albany, New York</geogname>
    <subject source="meg">Rensselaer County, New York</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Schenectady, New York</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Regional planning--New York (State)</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_cac61e3e2ccee87ae2f020b289b65bcd" level="series"><did><unittitle>Albany County</unittitle></did></c><c id="aspace_39ea9061a9010bfd0f38df40b6e76aeb" level="series"><did><unittitle>Saratoga County</unittitle></did></c><c id="aspace_bf5e0ff722b2250aa30b6e0e8a9707c6" level="series"><did><unittitle>Rensselaer County</unittitle></did></c><c id="aspace_a97fca3d5ea5add839c9a6b23c89abd3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Capital District </unittitle></did></c><c id="aspace_6f0335aaf78711b932a723732a73df3f" level="series"><did><unittitle>Greater Region </unittitle></did></c><c id="aspace_b7f027bed59eee78415878febe67205b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Schenectady County</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.8 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1948/2008" type="inclusive">1948-2008</unitdate></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
