<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap356.xml">apap356</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Murray, William J.; Papers <num>apap356</num></titleproper><author>unprocessed</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2015</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-06-12 02:54:14 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2014</date><item>EAD file created</item></change><change><date>2015</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Jodi Boyle</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>William J. Murray Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="local">Murray, William J., 1908-1995</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>apap356</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4.83 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1936/1978" type="inclusive">1936-1978</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_8e5de32d5ae3453ae610bdadb1634ba3">This collection documents the professional work of William J. Murray, who served as assistant administrative director of the New York State Department of Civil Service from 1946-1952 and then administrative director of the Department from 1952 until his retirement in 1971.  </abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_02e153386670f53de5eca40e40743f6b">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_9e946bfce69fd8ba0822ce1c2610bb19">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_50db1398b4f8e9f47461a910aecf0981" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_0cfa60f1725cd0f0ef08a8714c2716c2">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2015 by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_2e968e9872e0eed33cc149544a837da0">
    <head>Biographical History</head>
<p>Born in Brooklyn, William John Murray (1908-1995) became an Albany resident in 1946. He served as assistant administrative director of the New York State Department of Civil Service from 1946-1952 and then administrative director of the Department from 1952 until his retirement in 1971.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_4511429807e9c245c31f198f036dada7">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection contains meeting minutes, correspondence, pocket calendars, legislative materials, speeches, reports, and subject files, the majority related to William J. Murray's service as assistant director and then director of the New York Department of Civil Service from 1946-1971.  A significant portion of the collection is related to Murray’s “Role ONE Over” (RONEO) or daybooks.  There are several files relating to consulting work Murray completed after his retirement from the Civil Service.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_2b87ad52bca4077a6ea3891a4e52b5d1">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is arranged alphabetically.  There are no series.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_311a330ad4f04461866863f4d2f6541b">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>J. Michael Murray donated the collection of his father's papers to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives in <date normal="2015">2015</date>.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_4eef441f15151aa86c13e2781b5f4242">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_9efeee33016f0bba1b38f3fe70f3d875">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_10fd8bb6492c3d5f4f3cfdb1fcec5abd">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, William J. Murray Papers, 1936-1978. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Murray Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_9516903e1df40489b997f2f7d80a0ed8">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>The archivist transferred several monographs, including <title><emph render="italic">Staff Report on the Department of Civil Service, State of New York, Temporary State Commission on State Activities</emph></title> and <title><emph render="italic">The Administration of the New York State Civil Service Law</emph></title> to the book division of Special Collections. They will be catalogued and included in the University Libraries' Catalog.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
