<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap244.xml">apap244</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Dunne, John R.; Papers <num>apap244</num></titleproper><author>unprocessed</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2016</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-09-09 23:41:38 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>John R. Dunne Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap244</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">27.2 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1965/1969" type="inclusive">1965-1969</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_cd60858a05a570d73b7321b9ff223a86">This collection documents John R. Dunne's first years of service in the New York State Senate in the mid-late 1960s.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_5395eabe84a33be988f91cbdab01444d">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_f58f0f0ed88befc3549cc870ce887cfe" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_8acdb440a59acf1dddb1430d9e25565f">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2016 by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_e94dd655fa644d24da7b7e3998c39a98">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_be6d70a3ae9a96b04ea52223bc77d3fd">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_19872b811ddcab3e51f44df603dd9cdf">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>John R. Dunne initially donated his papers to Syracuse University in a series of acquisitions in 1969-1970. The papers were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in <date normal="2006">2006</date>.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_261a2c47155188a754e1d407bd5fab3d">
    <head>Biographical History</head>
<p>John R. Dunne was born on January 28, 1930, in Baldwin, New York. He graduated from Georgetown University in 1951 and received a law degree in 1954 from Yale Law School. </p><p>Dunne from Garden City, Nassau County, New York, was a leading political figure in New York. He was a Republican member of the New York State Senate from the 6th District from 1966 through 1989. </p><p>Dunne was much remembered for his involvement in the Attica Prison riots. During the 1971 riots, Dunne was the chairman of the Senate Corrections Committee. This committee is charged with overseeing the prison system. Dunne was famous for entering the prison during the riots with a New York Times editor Tom Wicker and Assemblyman Arthur Eve to try to negotiate with some of the prisoners. </p><p>Dunne retired from the State Senate in 1989 to practice law.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_85b66e35823c1bed4e150bd694b0abe0">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection includes correspondence, legislation, and subject files.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_87e09b0d1cbe908aabd992f183131171">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_c922576804bb1e70293bd6e7d17d3c04">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, John R. Dunne Papers, 1965-1969. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Dunne Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">Politics and Politicians</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Politicians--New York (State)</subject>
    <persname source="lcsh">Dunne, John R.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
