<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap357.xml">apap357</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Legislative Correspondents Association of New York State; Records <num>apap357</num></titleproper><author>Melissa McHugh</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2016</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-12-03 23:00:21 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2016 October 13</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Jodi Boyle</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>The Legislative Correspondents' Association of the State of New York Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="lcsh">Legislative Correspondents' Association of the State of New York</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>apap357</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10.41 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1892/2014" type="inclusive">1892-2014</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_4c0565c02019751e8809690c9499a944">This collection contains materials about The Legislative Correspondents' Association of the State of New York, especially its celebrated annual dinner held since 1900.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_bea66c0907fc764276942c3d63c2aea0">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_e9304c801e4f08bad9bc98764ca60b33">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_ff71598be4246ba0bacd80798f198a38" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_8d02cad459d41aaf897d132d1a10107a">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2018 by Melissa McHugh.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_f4df1311b9ed276166aa7847a995fe97">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_56cf356e27df07a9fb3138c789c9e75d">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p> The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_783e621ebb39001bf545f5aff445f9a8">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Current and former members of The Legislative Correspondents Association of New York State Susan Arbetter, Kyle Hughes, and Ron Kermani donated the materials in this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives in <date normal="2015/2016">2015-2016</date>.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_41ec0f50221d51d24b64dae2aca1fe7b">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Legislative Correspondents' Association of the State of New York (LCA), which began in 1890, is composed of journalists covering the State Capitol in Albany.  It is said to be one of the oldest organizations of newspapermen in the country.  It was not until 1965 that women were permitted to join the LCA, although they were correspondents at the capital at the time.  This Collection reflects the organization as a whole rather than specific reporters, with the exception of those referenced in the subject files. </p><p>The LCA holds a dinner and satirical show each year, since the inaugural one given for Governor Theodore Roosevelt in 1900, poking fun at New York politics and politicians.  The program has grown from the simple beginnings of dinner and hijinks to the elaborate show put on for several hundred state politicians and guests that we have today.  The proceeds from the show go to help local charities throughout New York State.   </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_daab54cfbe93623058e618c5a070d2c1">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection includes administrative and financial records, correspondence, photographs, slides, and member files from The Legislative Correspondents' Association of the State of New York (LCA). The majority of the collection, however, consists of materials from the LCA's annual dinner and show, including invitations, tickets, seating charts, programs, scripts, video, audio, film, and songs.</p><p>Please note that not all dates are inclusive.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_d2ea0af38edf3888cd39542d70b080da">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The materials are arranged chronologically within each of the three series.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_a707cbba7995d4b91c79a5d055a92ed9">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, The Legislative Correspondents' Association of the State of New York Records, 1892-2014. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the The Legislative Correspondents' Association of the State of New York Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Legislative reporting--New York (State)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Journalists--New York (State)</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Souvenir programs</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Admission tickets</genreform>
    <geogname source="meg">Albany, New York</geogname>
    <subject source="meg">Politics and Politicians</subject>
    <corpname source="lcsh">Legislative Correspondents' Association of the State of New York</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_1c484d89d20a92b06b5587ad17c49db7" level="series"><did><unittitle>Administrative</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.35 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1892/2007" type="inclusive">1892-2007</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_469858e572bcabc83acedc56b6eba58b"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged chronologically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_5cdbffa05ed511aa231928ec43d3a049"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The Administrative series consists of Board and business meeting minutes, constitutions, proposed changes to the constitution, annual and executive meeting files, files of some Club Presidents, some show planning, finances, and budgets.  It houses some of the earliest records about the organization. This series also contains information about membership, but not in depth information on specific reporters.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6c6dfa35886cdf64a80b5b871a6659a5" level="series"><did><unittitle>LCA Show</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7.16 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1902/2014" type="inclusive">1902-2014</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_32a1e8070288e8d43c02bb25cdf5d635"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged chronologically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_407a705cc4f93f1354c222536cb9c50f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains information specific to the LCA's annual show.  The files contain information about a specific year's show including: finances, invoices, program, script, invitations, correspondence, committees, attendees, menus, videos, photographs, and slides.  This series contains the bulk of the collection starting with the earliest show program dated 1902.  </p><p>Some early show information may also be found in the administration series, where it was comingled with executive and membership materials.  </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6d6ecc0cdaa758ea0bb7602b335f04dd" level="series"><did><unittitle>Reference and Subject Files</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.9 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1900/1994" type="inclusive">1900-1994</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_ba40e1b502b495d81f5513e2c10a31bf"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged chronologically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_08db31b9f6a6c699853fea726fdd82fc"><head>Scope and Contents</head></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
