<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>apap071</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Lumbard, Eliot H.; Papers <num>apap071</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-10-19 23:00:17 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2017</date><item>Additional processing and EAD finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Lumbard, Eliot H. Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="lcsh">Lumbard, Eliot H.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>apap071</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">52.55 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1943/2006" type="inclusive">1943-2006</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_3a4d7776c1ffc6c7623947866b8d30d5">This collection documents the professional and personal life of Eliot H. Lumbard.  </abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_f905b2bcb2f0a01d606f8d9b69c831b8">English.</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_77ed12fa0e73a8aa02c42726ddc55958">The materials are located onsite in the department. </physloc>
    <container id="aspace_cf8b9d125d6ab0e3939ae11cb3642fb5" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_2aa6e57d2b0c683964cffec5fd3ea4e3">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>This collection is unrestricted with the exception of select folders in Series 7, Subseries 1 and 2.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_3da892dc2f3fec96ff2ebba02cdadae4">
    <head>Copyright Statement</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital  objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other websites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder. </p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws if copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S> Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing, and trademarks. </p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future. </p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_e65da510ff543dd2c7c8e6465d648a5e">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Beginning in 1972 and continuing during the mid 1970's, portions of this manuscript group were donated to the University at Albany by Eliot Lumbard. Lumbard transfered additonal materials in 1999, 2005, and 2006 to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives. Additional accessions were deposited by Martin Greenberg in 2002.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_3be5a8f0363cc46c1432da6da307a61f">
    <head>Historical Note </head>
<p>Eliot Howland Lumbard practiced law for 40 years as an associate or partner in various New York and Pennsylvania firms. In addition to his private practice, he compiled a distinguished record in government service, including service on several commissions to investigate, combat, and control crime, and as a key advisor on crime to New York State Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller. </p><p>Lumbard was born in Fairhaven, MA on May 6, 1925. He received a B.S. from the Merchant Marine Academy in 1945, a B.S. in Economics from the Wharton School of Finance and Commerce at the University of Pennsylvania in 1949 and his J.D. from Columbia University in 1952. He was admitted to the New York State Bar in 1953 and the U. S. Supreme Court Bar in 1959. In addition, in 2005 he received an honorary Doctorate of Science from the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</p><p>Following his admission to the Bar, he began his legal career in government service. From 1953-1956 he was an Assistant United States Attorney in the Southern District of New York. During this time, he was assigned to a wide variety of both civil and criminal matters. From 1958-1961 he was Chief Counsel of the New York State Commission of Investigation. Governor W. Averell Harriman signed the Commission of Investigation into law on April 25, 1958 and charged the Commission with the duty and power to conduct investigations in connection with organized crime and racketeering, the conduct of public officers and public employees and any matter concerning the public peace, public safety and public justice. In his role, Lumbard organized and directed many large and complex investigations, including the investigation of the police departments in Buffalo, Rochester, and Syracuse, as well as investigating organized crime, harness racing, bingo, the New York City school construction program, and Albany real estate tax delinquencies. In 1961 Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller hired Lumbard as Special Assistant Counsel for Law Enforcement, a position he held until 1967. As a key Rockefeller advisor, Lumbard discussed many ideas and issues related to the socials problem of crime and crime control. Lumbard organized the Oyster Bay Conferences on Organized Crime (1963-1967), developed the New York State Information and Intelligence System (NYSIIS) which was the first computer-based criminal justice record system that included individual criminal histories and proposed creating a school of criminal justice, eventually established at the University at Albany in 1965.</p><p>During his career in private practice, Lumbard worked on many cases of commercial litigation on finance and bankruptcy matters. Some of his cases included: counsel to Charles Seligson and trustee in bankruptcy of Ira Haupt and Co. (1964-1973), a large Wall Street case known as the salad oil debacle in 1963; trustee in bankruptcy of Universal Money Order Co., Inc. (1977-1982) which was the nation’s largest consumer bankruptcy; and trustee in Roy Cohn proceedings who was accused of professional misconduct. In the early 1970s, he represented the Center for Reproductive and Sexual Health (CRASH), located in New York City and at the time the largest freestanding abortion clinic in the world. CRASH opened in 1970 after New York legalized abortion.</p><p>Lumbard worked in academe as a lecturer at the New York University Law School from 1963-1965 and as an Adjunct Professor of Law and Criminal Justice at John Jay College from 1975-1985. From 1967-1969, Lumbard researched and wrote an unpublished work titled “Harm to Each Other: Crime and Crime Control in America”.</p><p>In addition, Lumbard served as director or trustee of many organizations including the New York Police Foundation, Inc. (1971-1991) and the New York State Maritime Museum (1969-1980). Lumbard was a member of many professional organizations including the Association of the Bar of the City of New York, the International Bar Association, the New York Bar Association and the American Bar Association.</p><p>Currently, he is retired and living in Nashua, NH.</p>  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_920f2e6b7550adc0d52377a42c8e964a">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_5d43ba8ae9de461390bfe740b33c7c70">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Eliot Lumbard Papers document the life’s work of a lawyer who devoted himself towards both public service and private practice with equal vigor and success. The collection is arranged into 12 series: Series 1: U.S. Attorney’s Office, Southern District of New York; Series 2: New York State Commission of Investigation; Series 3: Special Assistant Counsel for Law Enforcement to New York State Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller; Series 4: Other Public Service, Professional Associations and Organizations; Series 5:Publications- Harm to Eachother: Crime Control in America; Series 6: Other Publications;  Series 7: Private Practice; Series 8: Teaching; Series 9: Correspondence; Series 10: Personal Files; Series 11: Subject Files; Series 12: Audio/Visual. Series 6 is further divided into two subseries each.</p><p>The Lumbard papers are useful to scholars, students and historians studying New York State government of the 1960s, bankruptcy cases, SUNY Albany, and criminal justice. The entire collection totaling nearly 53 cubic feet contains records from his public and private sector work which he had commercially bound. The collection includes: correspondence, memorandum, press releases, reports, court proceedings, notes, speeches, journal articles, academic papers, drafts, newspaper clippings, and background research.</p><p>All of the significant positions that Lumbard held are represented in this collection including his service as Assistant U.S. Attorney 1953-1956, Chief Counsel for the New York State Commission of Investigation, 1958-1961, and Special Assistant Counsel for Law Enforcement to New York State Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1961-1967. Also of significant interest are his records from private practice cases including: counsel to Charles Seligson and trustee in bankruptcy of Ira Haupt and Co. (1964-1973); formation of the University at Albany’s School of Criminal Justice; review panel to disbar to Roy Cohn, accused of professional misconduct; and representation of the Center for Reproductive and Sexual Health in the early 1970s. </p><p>Access to some individual legal case files in Series 7 are restricted. Consult the head of the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives for details. </p>  </scopecontent>
  <prefercite id="aspace_da67e43e0eec38cf34025521cc6308fe">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <function source="lcsh">Lumbard, Eliot H.</function>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State)--Politics and government</geogname>
    <function source="lcsh">Law enforcement-- New York (State)</function>
    <function source="lcsh">Practice of law--New York (State)</function>
    <subject source="lcsh">Correspondence</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Legal documents</genreform>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Manuscripts for publication</genreform>
    <subject source="meg">Albany, New York</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Criminal Justice and Prisons</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Public Servants</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_47affcb8657ddf17181e38421506e39e" level="series"><did><unittitle>U.S. Attorney’s Office, Southern District of New York</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.06 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1952/1989" type="inclusive">1952-1989</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_09deb15c36d8b972f10950ec1140768c"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_39ef8da48b6623f211dfad28fd68da29"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series consists of records from Lumbard’s position as Assistant United States Attorney in the Southern District of New York. During this time Lumbard was assigned to a wide variety of both civil and criminal matters. This series is organized alphabetically and includes memorandum, news clippings, trial briefs, procedures and forms.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_250cef9d112779f152346a4539b7c5a2" level="series"><did><unittitle>New York State Commission of Investigation</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5.43 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1957/1991" type="inclusive">1957-1991</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_352e704a02428e10b2c7ceebc1d01e38"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series consists of records from Lumbard’s position as chief counsel for the New York State Commission of Investigations. During this time, Lumbard organizied and directed many large and complex investigations. This series contains records of investigations of police departments, organized crime, and gambling. It is organized alphabetically and includes notes, memorandum, correspondence, speeches, reports, press releases, news clippings, court proceedings, and public hearings.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7478d966946c27e380a884d7511ba5cd" level="series"><did><unittitle>Special Assistant Counsel for Law Enforcement to New York State Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10.17 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1956/1996" type="inclusive">1956-1996</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_067b11d985a32cf8acab4823d166d1be"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arragned alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_faa930410f6dc9e5bb66427befe38a88"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series consists of records from Lumbard’s position as special assistant counsel for law enforcement to Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller of New York. Lumbard served the governor in many capacities. He was an advisor on the social problems of crime and crime control, as well as a liaison from the executive chamber to criminal justice agencies and the courts in New York State. This series is organized alphabetically and contains records regarding the programs Lumbard organized and/or initiated including: the Oyster Bay Conference on Crime also known as the Governor’s Conferences on Crime; the New York State Information and Intelligence System (NYSIIS); investigations into organized crime and gambling; and State Department of Crime Control. The series also contains correspondence, biographical information about Nelson A. Rockefeller and research into issues such as racial violence, politics, and criminal justice.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_eea1087eaaccafd541638b45c0077256" level="series"><did><unittitle>Other Public Service, Professional Associations and Organizations</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7.5 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1952/2006" type="inclusive">1952-2006</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d2e62a4fcb1333a7b990cc29b975e379"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series consists of records from Lumbard’s other positions in public service, with professional associations, and other organizations. He worked as Chief Criminal Justice Consultant to the New Jersey State Legislature, 1967-1969, and an advisor to Charles McCurdy Mathias Jr. of Maryland during his successful 1968 Senate campaign. He was a member of several professional associates including: the Association of the Bar of the City of New York, the American Bar Association and the International Bar Association. He also worked in a wide variety of organizations during his professional career, including the New York City Police Foundation (trustee 1971-1991, chairman 1971-1974, 1977) and the New York State Maritime Museum (trustee 1969-1980). He was a member of the Citizen’s Crime Commission, the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council, John Lindsay for Mayor, and the Republican National Committee, Task Force on Crime. This series is arranged alphabetically and contains folders and bound volumes and includes such materials as: reports, press releases, meeting minutes, directories, new clippings, academic papers, press packets, newsletters, photos, memos, transcripts and notes.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1e6f125aa05feb491e579b7cb7c6ae64" level="series"><did><unittitle>Publications: Harm to Each Other: Crime and Crime Control in America</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12.0 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1956/1996" type="inclusive">1956-1996</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_2f0ba1dcb29abb8c69875f15f0fb8bcf"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_ad1cc8cc0be5d8212f429c5294067244"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains several years of research material and drafts of an unpublished manuscript “Harm to Each Other: Crime and Crime Control in America.” The research is organized alphabetically and encompasses a wide variety of subjects including: street crimes, organized crime, juvenile delinquency, racial issues, police departments, courts and law, parole, citizen action, and federal, state, and local government interaction.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9d061ec048155df577240e318b49c55b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Other Publications</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.66 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1963/1987" type="inclusive">1963-1987</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_fcebf5c6a3907bb8dbfa12581118f856"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_eb449b4ac6e4e0634ce36f4f2e5ecec8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series is organized alphabetically and contains some of Lumbard’s published materials and other research, including his work on another manuscript with Philip John Stead entitled, “World Criminal Justice Systems.”</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a4bcd4efac8b5e1ef0a36da22af1c91d" level="series"><did><unittitle>Private Practice</unittitle><unitdate normal="1951/1999" type="inclusive">1951-1999</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_a4bd55c337c12cc8beeac7a5ef4d6812"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_19381d31e607ebbc09d739b9ff918268"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series concerns Lumbard’s career as an attorney where he specialized in general commercial litigation, including serving as legal representation for brokers, investment bankers and on bankruptcy matters. Some of his significant cases were: counsel to Charles Seligson, trustee in bankruptcy of Ira Haupt and Co.; trustee in bankruptcy of Universal Money Order Co., Inc; Chairman of the Board, Palisades Life Insurance Company, formerly Equity Funding Life Insurance Company of New York; special master in admiralty of Hellenic Lines, Ltd.; counsel to Cyprus Minerals Company; trustee in Roy Cohn proceedings. He also represented the New York City abortion clinic, the Center for Reproductive and Sexual Health (CRASH). Please consult the head of the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives for details about restricted individual legal case files.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_89e99c55ca2e42c9f6368e10a61e96d6" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Cases</unittitle><unitdate normal="1951/1999" type="inclusive">1951-1999</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_a7ef287ddc7a172f642ba3ad4b8572d4"><head>Arrangement</head></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_774a2d6ebc02a6e6bf93191fc0f880b9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This subseries is organized alphabetically and includes court proceedings, statements, transcripts, memos, notes on court strategies, motions, and news clippings.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9e3f1fab9026227cd27db36a51b50f96" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Firms</unittitle><unitdate normal="1963/1990" type="bulk">1963-1990</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_c932ac0c35fe10888a449d2ee3db77f0"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_80d242fa68afdae53329ac440144f338"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This subseries is organized alphabetically and contains directories, manuals, financials, correspondence, and reports from various law firms that Lumbard worked at.</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_b713d7e4fc642063772dfef7ca678a7f" level="series"><did><unittitle>Teaching</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.22 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1962/1999" type="inclusive">1962-1999</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_22648d8405b69d7c6ebab727bcf3c19e"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_99d863badbda5333c80203934c67e9da"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series concerns Lumbard’s work as an adjunct professor and lecturer at John Jay College, Rutgers University, and SUNY Albany. It is organized in alphabetically and contains course readings, lecture notes, course booklets, bulletins, academic papers, and correspondence.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1f399e4fea1fc44f9e94668945186318" level="series"><did><unittitle>Correspondence </unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.72 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1960/1996" type="inclusive">1960-1996</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_64c237e6fd1f3993fe966fdb4f178498"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_d5153f8bf9c84bf8dd279278b91158c1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains Lumbard’s general, office and personal correspondence. It is arranged alphabetically.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2ebc9345ce9ee6f32dbf5842590fa27b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Personal Files </unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.50 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1943/2001" type="inclusive">1943-2001</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_d3a1c97ba1c3caa3a5b15e07568d3855"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_64bd48b5a9633a8c8d216118243e1dc2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains Lumbard’s personal files. It contains his military papers, professional certificates and awards, curriculum vitae, FBI File, directories, as well as other personal items.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_617cd39f19f5158912aa307b5f0a39ea" level="series"><did><unittitle>Subject Files </unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.33 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1960/2001" type="inclusive">1960-2001</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_95438524cddce551cb238236dec83039"><head>Arrangement</head></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_796341aa93ff916d6a7a162569a2101b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains criminal justice material that Lumbard devoted his life towards studying. The series, which is organized alphabetically, includes journal articles, booklets, pamphlets, press releases, memos, news clippings, academic papers and reports.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b99289406595befc0de6c4a62804a140" level="series"><did><unittitle>Audio</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.26 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1963/1971" type="inclusive">1963 -1971</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_528f007ea48212d1a17ada06e705843e"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_9255238d01ee906893fbf1058d50f4f4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains 7” audio reels concerning criminal justice organized alphabetically.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
