<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap314.xml">apap314</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Kerr Ross, Patricia; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>Kerr Ross, Patricia; Papers <num>apap314</num></titleproper><author>Brian Keough</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2016</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-06-30 23:00:04 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2016 December 22</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Brian Keough</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Patricia Kerr Ross Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap314</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12.1 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1967/1997" type="inclusive">1967-1997</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_71c4f7ded042ce68da5a85c5473251e1">This collection contains records of Patricia Kerr Ross as Director, State University of New York (SUNY) Programs in the Arts.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_25867873a5a6c82acd22dc39d766aca3">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_d8cf2868949be7ef0d032d57020b952a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_078167cf30d34aeb11e181da25879090">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection is unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_fd65c0e60c19a8301b194bc9ff596436">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_433d18a7a819d492dca61247ca3a1680">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_72a172ed965ee628a492479489bbf822">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The majority of items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 2009. In 2022, Darcie Abbatiello of the University Art Museum donated a small addition to the collection.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_f9cfcd4528727ad8768df64747a12bfa">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The University-Wide Programs in the Arts was established in 1965. It worked with the New York State Council on the Arts to sponsor touring programs in dance, music and theatre, documentary and film programs on SUNY campuses, exhibits of faculty and student painting, illustration and sculpture, and sponsored annually and biennially arts festivals.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_f6475a6019bda2eed530bed352bcc4db">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains records of Patricia Kerr Ross as Director, State University of New York (SUNY) Programs in the Arts including performance/exhibit programs, brochures, posters, photographs, and video tapes of some programs sponsored by the SUNY Programs in the Arts. Also included are catalogs of art exhibits, and books and pamphlets on arts programs, primarily in New York, withdrawn from the Program in the Arts Office. The collection also includes Kerr Rosss correspondence/subject files on Program in the Arts initiatives, program reviews, correspondence with colleagues regarding programs and grant proposals, minutes of SUNY University-Wide Committee on the Arts, 1978-1982, 1988-1990, and the New York State Council on the Arts.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_4ed325d75e5515f739715d8c826bbd72">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_14c8da0f474b975ba9d9f0fa9676c038">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Patricia Kerr Ross Papers, 1967-1997. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Kerr Ross Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
