<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap385.xml">apap385</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper type="filing">Children's Music Network; Records</titleproper>
        <titleproper>Children's Music Network; Records <num>apap385</num></titleproper>
        <author>Kathy Merring-Darling</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2026</date>
        </p>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2026-04-30 01:01:21 -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Children's Music Network Records</unittitle>
      <unitid>apap385</unitid>
      <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/resources/1045</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9.8 cubic ft.</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1974/2011" type="inclusive">1974-2011</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_194f5cc73fed09a1e5910c5f1145e78e">This collection documents the activities of the Children's Music Network, a music education and community building organization, since its establishment in 1987.</abstract>
      <physloc id="aspace_247388cded0aa5465d0b1a715f0aec2d">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <langmaterial><language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_3392cd7d02e514683a26624de2f7c2fb">
      <head>Content Description</head>
      <p>This collection contains administrative records, the Children's Music Network's organizational publication entitled <emph render="italic">Pass It On</emph>, files on the annual national gathering/conference, fund raising materials, subject files such as regional guidelines and events and project files, and  photographs. In addition to the physical materials there is also born  digital content and material donated on CDs and floppy disks which provide additional information on the above referenced.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <bioghist id="aspace_33a540c3234a870644c047871a64c568">
      <head>Organizational History</head>
      <p>Established in 1987 by children's music performers, the Children's Music Network has its roots in the People's Music Network. The organization believed that music could help children better understand,  think about, and use their voices to express their views about challenging global issues like the environment, war, discrimination and bigotry. Early supporters were children's music performers but also teachers, radio hosts, parents, and songwriters. In its first year, the organization began publishing a newsletter, <emph render="italic">Pass It On</emph>, and held its first gathering, separate from a People's Music Network conference.</p>
      <p>Today, the Children's Music Network continues its work to educate, build community and empower children through quality and multicultural music. The organization is a nonprofit with members in chapters across the United States and Canada. Members include full-time and part-time performers, songwriters, classroom teachers, music educators, librarians, storytellers, record producers, distributors, broadcasters, parents, grandparents, and children. An international annual conference along with regional and local gatherings continue to be held. </p>
    </bioghist>
    <processinfo id="aspace_03ab63dbfa00a825e9440f1af2deabf0">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>The collection is processed.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_e2a0289720d132028b86e39033ab4b9c">
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_7f255ec6134d61a1e5c3aaf0e059feb6">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
      <p>Carl Foote donated all materials in this collection on behalf of the Children's Music Network in 2024 and 2025.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_af6be01a84500fc9d85954c15eb1a5e0">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Children's Music Network Records, 1987-2011. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Children's Music Network Records).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <userestrict id="aspace_36af3ccbfbb5d2f78a1172c1898d4673">
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
      <p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
      <p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <arrangement id="aspace_947964282a2b1c9a9357af243798d1f6">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is arranged in eight series all of which are arranged alphabetically.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <controlaccess>
      <function source="lcsh">Children's Music Network</function>
      <subject source="meg">Music</subject>
      <subject source="aat">Correspondence.</subject>
      <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">By-laws</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">sheet music</genreform>
      <function source="lcsh">Music--Instruction and study</function>
      <genreform source="lcsh">Newsletters</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Directories</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Fundraising</genreform>
      <genreform source="lcsh">Administrative records</genreform>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_c8dfa85010a527078e8a370f18f6d5c8" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Administrative Records</unittitle>
          <unitid>1</unitid>
          <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/357861</unitid>
          <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.2 cubic ft.</extent>
          </physdesc>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1989/2010" type="inclusive">1989-2010</unitdate>
          <langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_32e6c0db693028d5f845329019740659">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The administrative series contains paper and born digital records including board meeting minutes, meeting agendas, board member roles, and elections which provide insight into the decision making of the organization. The series highlights the development and design of the Children's Music Network's website as well as reports on their online presence through such sites as MySpace, YouTube, and FaceBook. Other materials provide insight into contracts and the responsibilities of the administrative coordinator.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_f88ebb36ce33d21cd22f5c4cbe4a96d7" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records</unittitle>
          <unitid>2</unitid>
          <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/357862</unitid>
          <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.2 cubic ft.</extent>
          </physdesc>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1987/2011" type="inclusive">1987-2011</unitdate>
          <langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_3c8f88500d3c77c01b627292b20d3d35">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The paper and digital financial records provide an overview of the organization's finances through such documents as designated funds and year-to-date summaries. There also are bookkeeping reports, budgets, resource and preparation documents that detail how to prepare the budget, various financial reports, nonprofit accounting procedures, and regional financial reports. The financial reports provide comparisons to previous years, allowing one to see the changing net worth of the organization over several years.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_25d62782382eed2657a8f69cfaff543f" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Fundraising</unittitle>
          <unitid>3</unitid>
          <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/357869</unitid>
          <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.4 cubic ft.</extent>
          </physdesc>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1989/2010" type="inclusive">1989-2010</unitdate>
          <langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_2dba74f550fed1fbc47e34ced8fe3cd3">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The fundraising series, with paper and digital materials, highlights the ways in which the organization raised funds through grants and more creative methods such as selling quilt squares. The Children's Music Network also solicited donations from businesses, held fundraising concerts and silent auctions, and hosted special events such as Keys to Success and Give A Gig. The digital materials also highlight the work of the fundraising committee.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_5148d2a2192da92d368ddbf207cd7381" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Gatherings</unittitle>
          <unitid>4</unitid>
          <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/357870</unitid>
          <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.0 cubic ft.</extent>
          </physdesc>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1989/2010" type="inclusive">1989-2010</unitdate>
          <langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_823a9a36a3f8c6944664b61386957963">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series provides information on the planning and organization of annual and conference gatherings held by the Children's Music Network. These gatherings were held in a different state every year, for example, Petaluma, California or Albany, New York. The gatherings occurred over two days and brought together members from the various regions. Gatherings were well organized and provided numerous activities for participants such as workshops, song swaps, round robin, and the Magic Penny Award. One can find numerous photographs of these activities within the Images series as well as digital copies on CD. Other digital materials associated with this series include information pertaining to the budget, workshops, scholarships, committtes, press packets, teacher credit, and Magic Penny Award. There is also information about the keynote speaker and attendance records. The gatherings were also written up in the organization's newsletter Pass It On which can be found in the Publication series.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_0d87c4e403c0bea16eb4d28d83068a35" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Images</unittitle>
          <unitid>5</unitid>
          <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/357871</unitid>
          <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.4 cubic ft.</extent>
          </physdesc>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1991/2006" type="inclusive">1991-2006</unitdate>
          <langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_9ff4c09ffa11e62126bbc859aea07deb">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The image series contains photographs from national conferences and gatherings that provide a visual representation of the activities and events that occured. They provide additional context to the materials found within the Gatherings series. There are also CDs with numerous photographs from several gatherings providing additional visual context surrounding specific events, such as the Magic Penny Award ceremony. These images are also used within the organization's newsletter Pass It On which can be found in the Publication series.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_5027af3fc3da4cf6cd8fd34202efad7f" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Publications</unittitle>
          <unitid>6</unitid>
          <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/357872</unitid>
          <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.0 cubic ft.</extent>
          </physdesc>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1974/2010" type="inclusive">1974-2010</unitdate>
          <langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_680c125f9cc4018b4cc467b828e19adb">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series contains the organization's newsletter <emph render="italic">Pass It On !</emph> from its first issue through 2010. <emph render="italic">Pass It On !</emph> highlighted what was happening in each region, provided information about upcoming events, songs, and a feature article. There are also within this series membership directories as well as materials about the search for a newsletter editor. There are digital materials which include the materials used in each newsletter issue as well as several complete issues available in PDF form. The digital materials also provide information about the organization's decsion for moving to a digital format with <emph render="italic">e-pio</emph>. Issues 40 and 44 were both special All Songs Issues. In addition to the newsletter, they also produced a CD of all the songs within each issue both CDs are available for listening. The newsletter also highlighted the gatherings that happened each year with photographs and a write-up about the event. To learn more about either of these, one can look at the Gatherings or Images series.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="aspace_a2be1e4b00454fa7f28ce1f76b45cb12">
          <head>Arrangement</head>
          <p>The Thumbdrive reflects the Children's Music Network's organization of the materials.</p>
        </arrangement>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_df56ffb534f9c5547a4c45250a4a2946" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Subject Files</unittitle>
          <unitid>7</unitid>
          <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/357873</unitid>
          <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.4 cubic ft.</extent>
          </physdesc>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1982/2010" type="inclusive">1982-2010</unitdate>
          <langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_d06b2f61751c43f257c78477251cb06a">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The subject files contain materials related to the history and founding of the organization. There are brochures in both Spanish and Braille. The series also consists of documentation about the Magic Penny Award, which is an award given at the annual gathering to a deserving musician. More information about the Magic Penny Award can be found within the Gatherings, Images, and Publications series. The series also includes correspondence, such as copies of letters from Pete Seeger; the originals are stored separately. There is also information from the regional affiliates and the work to develop new regions. This series contains digital materials such as office procedures, flyers, project ideas, songs, regions, membership forms, outreach, articles of incorporation, mission statement, and the twentieth anniversary of the organization.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_a8c77b5362b3193256c3b3599c7a0977" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Trademark</unittitle>
          <unitid>8</unitid>
          <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/357874</unitid>
          <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.6 cubic ft.</extent>
          </physdesc>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1987/2009" type="inclusive">1987-2009</unitdate>
          <langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_c2d335b3281316a3d6268b68f5abb25d">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series highlights the steps taken by the organization to secure the trademark for their newsletter <emph render="italic">Pass It On</emph> and to the acronym of the Children's Music Network, CMN. There is also information about trademarking their logo. The series provides a detailed account of the court proceedings and communications with their lawyer to acheive this. There is also information related to the costs associated with attaining the tradmarks as well as the schedule of when these need to renewed. This series contains digital materials that in conjunction with the hard copies allow for a more comprehensive understanding of the organization's work to obtain the trademark for their logo, newsletter, and name. One can learn about how the organization engaged in methods to protect their trademark rights and whether to pursue trademark in Canada. These resources also provide an overview of the registrtion process. It also provides an example of how the Children's Music Network protected their trademark from use by other organizations such as the Music Educators National Conference (MENC).</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
