<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap364.xml">apap364</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Rhoda Fox Graves Papers <num>apap364</num></titleproper><author>Amanda Partridge</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2018</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-05-10 13:27:33 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2016 October 18</date><item>Initially encoded in EAD by Jodi Boyle</item></change><change><date>2018 April 13</date><item>Finding aid updated and expanded by Amanda Partridge</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Rhoda Fox Graves Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="local">Rhoda Fox Graves, 1877-1950</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>apap364</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">14.03 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1906/1948" type="inclusive">1906-1948</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_40961cd7f68805911b806bd05d128a87">This collection documents Rhoda Fox Graves' service in the New York State Assembly and Senate. It also contains some personal materials from her life.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_19b56286a14cb7bbaee6f337198ddfb9">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_7ca4fcf9d701b0c6fcea037009ea679f">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_6e2234b82a72307f9c5e9b5eacf291c8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_ef469501057d9c08b563c4491c41c173">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2018 by Amanda Partridge.
Duplicate and financial materials removed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_dbf85975cdeb29848e45a7e6261e041f">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_e6d40efea2dad6a00618ad33ed64c8f3">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p> The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_8c1772c9619e492acab65dabcf1551a1">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives from the Gouverneur Museum, <date normal="2016-06-30">2016 June 30</date>.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_141603df7c81d345482a7fa59bac457f">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>Rhoda Fox Graves (1877-1950) was prominent in public affairs in the North Country of New York and the first woman elected to New York State Senate. Graves was first elected to the New York State Assembly from St. Lawrence County in 1924 and served from January 1, 1925 until December 31, 1932. She held that positon longer than any woman of her time. Two years later, she was elected to the New York State Senate where she served continuously until she resigned in ill health December 31, 1948.</p><p> Rhoda Fox married Perle A. Graves in 1905 and had two sons, Paul and Marcus. All three survived her. When she resigned from her State Senate seat, Paul was elected to succeed her.</p><p> Graves achieved a number of firsts in her career. She was the first woman to become vice president of the St. Lawrence County Republican Committee. She was the first woman to be elected from a northern county to the New York State legislature. She was the first woman to serve in the New York Sate Senate, the first woman to preside over that legislative body, and to head a Senate Standing Committee (Agriculture). </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_f29fb645141c898f993f268ad6c518fa">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Rhoda Fox Graves Papers contain records that were generated during her time as a representative of Northern New York in the State Assembly and State Senate. The collection is heavy in correspondence, both professional and personal, mostly regarding matters of importance to her constituents such as agriculture. Included are legislation, campaign materials, and committee records. The collection also contains scrapbooks, subject files, and artifacts.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_677975f8fd3bdcfa354e44f53b063921">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>Original order was maintained or reclaimed when possible, but a majority of the collection was disorganized so an order was imposed.</p><p>The Assembly Files are in their original alphabetical order. The Senate Files are arranged chronologically and the Subject Files are arranged alphabetically. </p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_42a832c8a4b0e84fa9f6dc919cc99692">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Rhoda Fox Graves Papers, 1906-1948. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Graves Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Politicians--New York (State)</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Bills (legislative records)</genreform>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Files by subject</genreform>
    <persname source="local">Rhoda Fox Graves, 1877-1950</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
