<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap316.xml">apap316</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Mishler, Mark; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>Mishler, Mark; Papers <num>apap316</num></titleproper><author>unprocessed</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2016</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-09-28 23:28:46 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2016 December 23</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Brian Keough</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Mark Mishler Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap316</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1975/2008" type="inclusive">1975-2008</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_e871563b16a866bc83a622a5af2788cf">This collection contains the papers of Mark Mishler, a practicng attaorney in Albany, New York.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_7d80ff09e49222cb5cee39b06b2932c8">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_4380f1c8bad9aae7933896f54cf9cb6c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_969286bdbc036785da97e2aef410ba29">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2016 by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_dd2ee0b4646cab700555ad3299d70974">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Per the memorandum of agreement with the donor, access to this collection is currently restricted because the collection is unprocessed.  There may be a small number of confidential and sensitive records containted in the collection.  Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_e54c1637ca9f5de7f43c7da17b80169b">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_355bc07f026252d917fb0723541401ae">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>All items in this collection were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 2010 by Mark Mishler.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_8ad8c605fa711230058a469ab44fcbd5">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>Mark Mishler has practiced law in Albany, NY since 1981, first as director of student legal services at the University at Albany for six years and then as an attorney in private practice. In 2000 he ran for Albany County District Attorney, endorsed by the Working Families Party and the Green Party.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_e4fae10dbfbf15d5abbb4c6df1220458">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection documents three decades of Mishler's political, community, and legal work on issues involving the city police force, police misconduct, and police practices with regard to civilian rights. Included are case files, court records, subject files, correspondence, clippings, reports, notes, background research, newsletters, and flyers for community events. The files detail Mishler's involvement with a variety of community organizations, such as the Albany Community Police Relations Board, the Albany branch of the NAACP, and the local chapter of Citizen Action. There is a small number of audio/video cassettes, and a small group of photographs. In addition, there are files and memorabilia documenting Mishler's 2000 political campaign for district attorney.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_7aa379e297426707dd4b30db46c9b410">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_5f3d7383f2ae1634020bffbcd860b17e">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Mark Mishler Papers, 1975-2008. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Mishler Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">Social Activists and Public Advocates</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Public Servants</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Albany, New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Social Activist</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
