<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>apap194</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>North American Fiddlers Hall of Fame and Museum; Collection <num>apap194</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.
Processed by unprocessed. </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-04-01 23:00:04 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>North American Fiddlers Hall of Fame and Museum Collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="local">North American Fiddlers Hall of Fame and Museum</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>apap194</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12.5 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1970/1989" type="inclusive">1970-1989</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_f047780e840ac8e06de70746a5163179">The North American Fiddler’s Hall of Fame was created in 1973 in the Central New York area. Now called, the New York State Old Tyme Fiddlers’ Association and North American Fiddlers Hall of Fame and Museum, the Association’s mission is to preserve, promote, and perpetuate, the art of old time fiddling and the dances pertaining to this art. This collection contains tapes of interviews with significant fiddlers. The tapes located at the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives are the preservation copies that were created in 1999, while the originals reside at the North American Fiddler’s Hall of Fame. </abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_7c97fd284c05dcc2b91416ed6e0397b5">English.</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_ee18bb4b717c9fd865867975ad33792b">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_ba5df5cf3cd91e301be18a459cfed312" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_550b1247da4633a85d7fb42e4c89aad3">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_3018746fe0a6d0aeffe0d563c59a2bdb">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The North American Fiddler’s Hall of Fame was created in 1973 in the Central New York area. What started out as a picnic, eventually grew into a permanent settlement in Osceola, Lewis County, New York in 1975. By 1976, the New York Old Tyme Fiddlers’ Association (NYSOTFA) and the North American Fiddlers’ Hall of Fame and Museum Institute was officially formed as a non-proft 501 (c)(3).  Every last full weekend in July, the NYSOFTA holds its annual Fiddlers’ Picnic. </p><p>The NYSOTFA purchased a Museum site in 1981, where they have exhibits and historical artifacts. In 1994, the NYSOTFA purchased a pole barn to hold free Sunday concerts during the summer. The stage, now called “The Fiddlers Pavilion,” includes a dance floor and brick patio. The NYSOTFA continues to host events for all age groups in Osceola, New York.   </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_df11a1d492959affb89c52b3ac18bac1">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains 160 open reel tapes consisting of interviews with significant fiddlers. Tapes are preservation copies created in 1999 from originals. Digital copies and originals reside at the North American Fiddler's Hall of Fame.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_10f34ce1f8f8ed735c900b52be48683f">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_76fb1dfadb5109b8bc9e91ba380c9bc7">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Ellen McHale of the New York State Folklore Society donated the records in April 2005.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_3f68716c72d45ebf424c79646f558e5c">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_956e812510bfe5049738e0cf34056c1c">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_e97840c4ea3ea21d5dc71c1b7cb45f8d">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, North American Fiddlers Fall of Fame and Museum Papers, 1970-1989. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the NYSOFTA Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="local">North American Fiddlers Hall of Fame and Museum</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
