<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap381.xml">apap381</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Shapard, Sandra; Papers <num>apap381</num></titleproper><author>Jodi Boyle</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2020 January</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-03-02 01:03:03 -0500</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Sandra Shapard Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap381</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.26 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1972/2008" type="inclusive">1972-2008</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_01d3ffca9945f6d075320d86f7fbd623">The Sandra Shapard Papers consist of Ms. Shapard's (largely political) button collection.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_43162e1edd1c82731ae45b2711714599">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_92c6ceef961a67052f262ec6ce784ded">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>This collection contains 173 buttons collected by Sandra Shapard related to New York State politics, organizations, issues, and history.  It also includes U.S. presidential election buttons.  While the majority of buttons in the collections are of a serious nature, some are satirical.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_1bba0ae53eb0b2241555abd8edbc48e6">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection is currently unprocessed at the item level, although description is available to researchers from the donors.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_977241dad51e9543223e77c35136cf9f">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>Born in Mississippi, Sandra M. Shapard (1939-2018), was a longtime resident of New York State, a political strategist, and public servant.  She earned a bachelor's degree from Mississippi State College for Women, attended graduate school at Vanderbilt University, and later received a master's degree in Public Administration from Harvard University's John F. Kennedy School of Government.
Beginning in the 1970s, Ms. Shapard became increasingly involved in politics, initially as a volunteer.  She coordinated several election campaigns including those of Phil Magnarella for New York State Assembly, Lucille Pattison for Dutchess County Legislature and Pattison for county executive.
In 1976, she began working for the Democratic majority in the New York State Assembly, eventually serving as special assistant to the speaker for Intergovernmental Affairs.  In 1981, Ms. Shapard took a position as assistant to the county executive in Dutchess County.  Later, Ms. Shapard worked at the New York State Assembly Ways and Means Committee, rising to deputy director of Budget Studies.  In 1989, she became deputy Assistant Commissioner for Transit at the Department of Transportation.  She then moved to the Division of the Budget, later serving as first deputy budget director.  Ms. Shapard joined the Office of the State Comptroller as deputy comptroller for Budget and Policy Analysis in 1995. 
Ms. Shapard also was a volunteer for many organizations including the League of Women Voters and the NAACP, and, following her retirement in 2001, a board member for the Dormitory Authority of the State of New York, Albany Senior Services, the Bethlehem Industrial Development Agency, and the Humanities Institute for Lifelong Learning.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_def9d0a15aec4e03b0c983099008f58f">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The buttons in this collection are currently arranged by subject (all Dutchess County, all U.S. Presidential, all New York State organizations, all New York Congressional, etc.)</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_5d8e6d578416d1d295fa809a432e2e79">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Mara Elliott and David Shapard, children of Sandra Shapard, donated all materials in this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in <date normal="2019-12">December 2019</date>.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_2836fb2bef9546fbae897b94f711d6af">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_1436bd99dd46d8487e7a1458bd2f5c0b">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_6e43c85aa8fe85ee62d5b0624113f488">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Sandra Shapard Papers, 1972-2008. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Shapard Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York State New York (State)--Politics and government.</geogname>
    <subject source="meg">Social Activists and Public Advocates</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
