<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>apap325</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Kiepper, James; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>Kiepper, James; Papers <num>apap325</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.
Processed by unprocessed.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-09-29 00:18:04 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Kiepper, James Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap325</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1964/1988" type="inclusive">1964-1988</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_a4b3cc941df5028e3ba990a71364e0d1">Dr. James "Jim" Kiepper served on the faculty in the School of Education at the University at Albany for 35 years. During the 1960s, he also was special assistant to Michigan Governor George Romney, and New York Governor Nelson Rockefeller in his national bid for the U.S. Presidency in 1968. This collection documents Kiepper's long-time interest and work in politics. It includes a significant amount of memorabilia (dresses, stickers, pins, balloons, posters, fans) related to the Romney and Rockefeller presidential campaigns in 1964 and 1968. It also features Kiepper's personal notebooks from the 1964 Republican National Convention and from his work as an advance man for Rockefeller in 1968 as he traveled the country seeking a presidential bid. There also are materials from other 20th Century U.S. Presidential and Congressional political campaigns. In addition, the collection features news clips, calendars and schedules, notes, lectures and teaching materials. Kiepper is the author of Styles Bridges: Yankee Senator (2001) and previously edited the papers of Bridges and U.S. Representatives Perkins Bass and James Cleveland.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_65fd3e1748ddc6fe084bdef7f49bb375">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_6b9c175640a99323585e1701c5b2a6ac" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_a118cb802e6becf0b43477d81e9b8c85">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_52f0a1344c4f735a8cb7c04f18d0dd3e">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Dr. James "Jim" Kiepper was born in 1933 in Syracuse, New York. Kiepper grew up on a dairy farm in New Hampshire and graduated from Hopkington High School in 1951. After attending Gordon College for two years, he transferred to England College. Kiepper taught at Columbia High School and eventually accepted a position at the State University of New York's School of Education where he worked for 35 years. While working at the University, Kiepper also completed his P.H.D. </p><p>During the 1960s, Kiepper also was special assistant to Michigan Governor George Romney, and New York Governor Nelson Rockefeller in his national bid for the U.S. Presidency in 1968. Kiepper was given the opportunity to travel to Latin America with Nelson Rockefeller to promote goodwill at the direct action of President Nixon. Kiepper also wrote for the Times Union and worked as a consultant for NYSUT. Kiepper is the author of Styles Bridges: Yankee Senator (2001) and previously edited the papers of Bridges and U.S. Representatives Perkins Bass and James Cleveland. Dr. Kiepper died on June 12, 2017 in Delmar, New York and was survived by his children and grandchildren. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_be27a619cec199063653b69bb2055d93">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection documents Kiepper's long-time interest and work in politics. It includes a significant amount of memorabilia (dresses, stickers, pins, balloons, posters, fans) related to the Romney and Rockefeller presidential campaigns in 1964 and 1968. It also features Kiepper's personal notebooks from the 1964 Republican National Convention and from his work as an advance man for Rockefeller in 1968 as he traveled the country seeking a presidential bid. There also are materials from other 20th Century U.S. Presidential and Congressional political campaigns. In addition, the collection features news clips, calendars and schedules, notes, lectures and teaching materials.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_add5ebc4107ccd965cb0b44061d7a6c0">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_1f8201f31000b1354adab50eeb180cbe">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Dr. James. Kiepper and John Yolksh, his healthcare proxy,donated his papers in 2011-2012. Additional materials were donated in 2015 and 2017.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_af11d25630864681b010da7dcf00e9f1">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_51b80ef90723ab9e8e60014496f5696e">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_1179b98fedf5f4412a105a6ec0b97495">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, James Kiepper Papers, 1964-1988. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Kiepper Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="local">Kiepper, James.,1933-2017</geogname>
    <subject source="meg">Politics and Politicians</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">State University of New York -- Faculty.</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
