<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap128.xml">apap128</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">League of Women Voters of Albany County; Records</titleproper><titleproper>League of Women Voters of Albany County; Records <num>apap128</num></titleproper><author>Original: Anna Appleman, Jennisse Pichardo, Sarah Campbell, Amy C. Schindler

Revised: Gabriella Baratier</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2003; 2026</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2026-03-26 01:00:02 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2014</date><item>EAD file created</item></change><change><date>2015</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Conversion and encoding by ArchProteus</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>League Of Women Voters of Albany County Records</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap128</unitid>
    <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/resources/89</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">34.28 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1939/2023" type="inclusive">1939-2023</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_7c0186a1a34daff53061aea1b66f0fdc">This collection consists of the records of the League of Women Voters of Albany County (LWVAC), as well as material from the League of Women Voters of New York State (LWVNYS) and the League of Women Voters of the United States (LWVUS).</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_72b7fd192e3adb7637072403cdfdff4e">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_230b16b44733f8673ce69f7c55c06b7f">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_9ac601cbe0f232e1803a2fc1932a566d">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The League of Women Voters of Albany County first donated records to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, in 2002. Subsequent donations were made in 2003, 2004, 2012, 2022, and 2023.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <altformavail id="aspace_dc8a0248574b0bfbfffc2f81a749962d">
    <head>Existence and Location of Copies</head>
<p>A small number of images are available for viewing online from the University at Albany Libraries' Digital Collections database.</p>  </altformavail>
  <arrangement id="aspace_748226aed84c0cc8cafe70556faaa32e">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is arranged into eight series: Administrative Files, Voter Services, Local Program Studies, Albany County Government, Study and Action, Subject Files, Publications, and Memorabilia.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_00ad6b3835c1d7a64839012637fac849">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
The League of Women Voters of Albany County (LWVAC) was founded on March 6, 1922. It is a local chapter of the statewide League of Women Voters of New York (LWVNYS, founded 1919) and national League of Women Voters of the United States (LWVUS, founded 1920). According to the organization's by-laws, the LWV is a nonpartisan, volunteer-led political organization whose purpose is to "promote political responsibility through informed and active participation of citizens in government." The League fulfills this mission through voter services and study and action related to local, state, and national public policy issues. The LWVAC both adopts items of study set forth by the LWVNYS and LWVUS, and sets its own unique policies, priorities, and areas of study related to the Capital Region, as proposed by members, approved by the Board of Trustees, and carried out by committees. The LWVAC has informed citizens about public policy issues through a variety of methods, including publishing articles in the newspaper, hosting radio and television series, creating and disseminating publications, and hosting forums, debates, and events. The current organizational website can be found here: <https://lwvalbany.org/>.  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_922e97cf1eb00c5fd253f46c764081da">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, League of Women Voters of Albany County (LWVAC) Records, 1939-2023. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the LWVAC Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_77c6702d73a0600b70c6a40a53e6181a">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Initially processed in 2003 by Anna Appleman, Jennisse Pichardo, Sarah Campbell, and Amy C. Schindler. </p><p>Reprocessed in 2025-2026 by Gabriella Baratier. Reprocessing activities undertaken include interfiling newly accessioned material, deaccessioning out of scope material, and interfiling the records of two prior form-based series according to their subject matter: Photographs/Scrapbooks and Audiovisual. Additionally, all floppy disks were imaged. Those that were duplicates of paper records were deaccessioned.</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_8ce8dd5f88de3e72b117ab782182ac35">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>ME Grenander also holds the records of several other local chapters of the League of Women Voters: the LWV of Rensselaer County (apap103), the LWV of Schenectady County (apap210), and the LWV of Saratoga County (apap339).</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_b98218f008af7fc5f589a34511e9e29d">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection documents the activities of the League of Women Voters of Albany County (LWVAC) from the 1940s to the 2020s. The LWVAC was founded in 1922, but the earliest records of the organization have been lost. Material about the administrative history of the LWVAC includes annual reports, bylaws, Board of Directors meeting minutes, membership lists, and president's correspondence. Primarily, the materials in this collection relate to the LWVAC's involvement in voter services and public policy issues at the local level throughout the Capital Region. Local projects and areas of study that the LWVAC pursued include voter outreach and registration, candidate forums and debates, mental health services, financing education, land use, open meeting law, waste management, and the Albany County government, in particular revisions to the Albany County charter. The LWVAC also participated in studies and action about various public policy issues at the state and national levels in conjunction with the LWVNYS and the LWVUS, including court reform, human resources, international relations, and the environment. Materials that document the projects and studies of the LWVAC include correspondence, brochures and pamphlets, secondary research materials, news clippings, photographs, audiovisual material, and LWVAC-produced reports and publications. The collection additionally includes historical accounts of League history compiled in celebration of milestone anniversaries, and newsletters produced and disseminated by the LWVAC, LWVNYS, and LWVUS.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_a7ce702fbf6e495c9a53cc7ee44ae2c9">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">Women</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Social Activists and Public Advocates</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Senior Citizens</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Public Servants</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Medicine and Health Care</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Education</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Conservation and the Environment</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Albany, New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Election law--New York (State)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Elections--New York (State)--Albany</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Local government--New York (State)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Political planning--New York (State)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Voter registration--New York (State)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Voting--New York (State)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women political activists--New York (State)</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Minutes</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Newletters</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Studies</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Reports</genreform>
    <persname source="lcsh">Corning, Erastus, 1909-1983</persname>
    <persname source="lcsh">Ryan, James</persname>
    <corpname source="lcsh">League of Women Voters of New York State</corpname>
    <corpname source="lcsh">League of Women Voters (U.S.)</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_8fd467ee9ceb7f36e4a891c993a4cf9a" level="series"><did><unittitle>Administrative Files</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/356560</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5.13 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/2021" type="inclusive">1940-2021</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_b8fd80e581fae31c94bc165f0e8110f9"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_9d1fef325ba711fb3d458706856cf292"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The Administrative Files series consists of organizational records which document the activities of the board. These records include annual reports (1940-2021, not inclusive), monthly meeting minutes (1941-2003, not inclusive), and president's correspondence (1963-2002, not inclusive). Agendas and treasurer reports are often interfiled with the meeting minutes. This series also includes the by-laws that govern the LWVAC, along with amendments to those by-laws. Lists of the board of directors and the members of the organization over the years can be found in this series as well. Material regarding campaigns for membership and finance drives are also included. Furthermore, there are minutes from meetings of the Inter-League Organization (ILO) which consisted of the Albany, Rensselaer, Saratoga, Schenectady, and Shenendehowa Leagues of New York State (1975-1986).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_56777d7e7f45aeca1b3c814b7691ecbf" level="series"><did><unittitle>Voter Service</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/356561</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5.25 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/2019" type="inclusive">1945-2019</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_15d916165af2a8d179ff9fde1ac37f0e"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_1802bbb34402a279c9fb00776c31f065"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains materials related to Voter Service, the LWVAC's most active program. Voter Service activities undertaken in Albany County and the broader Capital Region by the LWVAC include: voter registration drives, participating in poll watching during elections, sponsoring candidate debates, surveying polling place accessibility, studying election law and procedures, campaigning for Permanent Personal Registration and the Motor Voter Law, and publishing pamphlets with information about candidates and about citizens' voting rights. Also included in this series are records documenting the activities of the Speakers Bureau (1961-1985, not inclusive), the LWVAC committee that spoke to other local groups and informed them about voting procedures and upcoming elections, and records documenting the Power the Vote Campaign of 1996, including correspondence, posters, meeting minutes, photographs, a collage, VHS footage, and a final report.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c10bcb3d79c3e281b9716f0e6ef6e673" level="series"><did><unittitle>Local Program Studies</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/356562</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.33 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1948/2021" type="inclusive">1948-2021</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_599db9adc78460a07c5495e0d4fbd0a7"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_1f6c0dca0fc3ff99b92b38a1ec34d642"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Local Program Studies are studies and projects done by the LWVAC that concerned the local area and its citizens. Some of the major areas of study for the LWVAC that resulted in concrete action include mental health facilities, libraries, open meeting law, and household hazardous material. The group began studying mental health facilities in 1955, aided in the creation of the Albany County Mental Health Board in 1958, and continued to study the county's mental health services through the 1980s. In 1961, the LWVAC surveyed the library services available to citizens in the county. The group determined that the Town of Colonie was in greatest need of a public library and took part in a door-to-door campaign called Libraries for Albany County Knocking (LACK). In cooperation with 45 other organizations, the LWVAC aided in the founding of the Colonie Library Association in November 1961. The Observer Corps (1982-1987), an LWVAC committee, observed meetings of the local governments to monitor compliance of those governments with the New York State Open Meeting Law and Freedom of Information Law following an Open Meeting Survey conducted by the group in 1980. From their study of household hazardous material, the LWVAC produced <emph render="italic">Household Hazards: A Guide to Detoxifying Your Home></emph> in 1988 and 1990, which is housed in this series rather than with publications in Series 7. Other local items of study include financing education, land use, redistricting the city and county of Albany, solid waste management, and the use of the ANSWERS incineration plant. Also included in this series are records relating to the LWVAC's participation in the LWVNYS initiative Students Inside Albany, an annual conference designed to teach high school students about New York State government. The LWVAC selects 1-2 high school students from Albany County to participate each year.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_be752d39117f2fd5981a4fa0096e1e39" level="series"><did><unittitle>Albany County Government</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/356563</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.4 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/2016" type="inclusive">1953-2016</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_ad5043ceff7d16d26c9247bb7ab73a70"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement></c><c id="aspace_8e7689348556bbfcdba76562f4d24f52" level="series"><did><unittitle>Study and Action</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/356564</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/2019" type="inclusive">1943-2019</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_b9b43be02cec235a91783cc296c59d2a"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_77b9e5e6bff40c738d4a2f56e9f0bf3e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains material related to public policy issues that are broader in scope than the Local Program Studies. The LWVAC takes part in studies and lobbies on a wide range of topics pertaining to the state and national LWV programs. Statewide topics in this series include court reform and universal health care, as well as records pertaining to the LWVAC's involvement in the New York State Constitutional Convention of 1967 and subsequent proposed referendums in 1997 and 2017. National items include apportionment, campaign finance, criminal justice, international relations, and national security. The environment and financing education were also topics of study at both the state and national levels. Materials under the heading "Legislative Action" include calls for action, memos, statements at public hearings, and correspondence to and from legislators relating to items the LWV lobbied for or against. Additionally, this series documents the LWVAC's participation in two LWVUS programs where international women were sponsored to visit the United States and meet with local Leagues: <emph render="italic">Project Demokracia: Building Citizen Participation in Hungary</emph> (1994) and <emph render="italic">Strengthening Women's Rights in the Newly Independent States Internship Program</emph> (1995). Material documenting these projects includes: the successful applications submitted by the LWVAC to be one of the participating local Leagues, background research material used to construct the applications, correspondence with LWVUS representatives about the logistics of each program, itineraries and daily schedules for each program, notes, photographs, and final reports after the conclusion of each program.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_956167e449099514cfcd760afbbd1ac5" level="series"><did><unittitle>Subject Files</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/356565</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4.59 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/2022" type="inclusive">1939-2022</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_2f4f9d50246559f8e091a9049e712af6"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_15f2e14826e74802480036a965c65f42"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The Subject Files series is an arbitrary organization of materials collected by the LWVAC that are not related specifically to the functions of administration, voter service, or informing citizens about public policy issues. Included in this series are planning and advertising materials for social events hosted by the LWVAC; items from other organizations that the LWVAC partnered with or sponsored, like the Center for Fiscal Equity, the New York Coalition Against Pesticides (NYCAP), and the Rockefeller Institute of Government; projects led by other organizations that the LWVAC took part in, like the Environmental Shopping Program (1990-1991), State Communities Aid Association Grant Program (1982), and Good Government Week (1976); convention materials from the state and national LWV; news clippings about the LWV; the files of the Public Relations director; and history and anniversary campaign material. Of note are the audiocassette tapes of oral histories with long-time LWVAC members, who discuss their childhoods, how they became members of the League, and issues in which they were involved.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d9aa46d27c05f516860594afd89c2eed" level="series"><did><unittitle>Publications</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/356566</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5.8 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1944/2022" type="inclusive">1944-2022</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_9a989b56e4d94d5c68bbc33c8a773375"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Subseries 1 (LWVAC publications) is arranged chronologically. Subseries 2 (LWVNYS publications) and Subseries 3 (LWVUS publications) are arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_9bb427c2afae1a496b2a6ec4f7de42f5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The publications series is arranged into 3 subseries: publications by LWVAC, publications by LWVNYS, and publications by LWVUS. There is a relatively comprehensive collection of the LWVAC monthly newsletter, which has been known by the following names across time: The Active Voter (1944-1989), Albany County Newsletter (1990-1991), Educate, Participate, Advocate (1992-2011), and Bulletin (2012-2022). Other publications by the LWVAC such as Voters' Guides, <emph render="italic">Household Hazards: A Guide to Detoxifying Your Home,</emph> and <emph render="italic">This is Albany County</emph> are included in Series 2, Series 3, and Series 4, respectively. Publications by the LWVNYS and LWVUS include newsletters, brochures and pamphlets, books, briefings, VHS tapes, and board reports sent to the local Leagues.  Many of the publications from the LWVNYS and LWVUS helped inform and guide LWVAC stances and action on public policy issues.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_93043087d3e3e32b7e41ab97a394ad5f" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>LWVAC</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/356567</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.2 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1944/2022" type="inclusive">1944-2022</unitdate></did></c><c id="aspace_e36a041af6db46a3780cd0471c79e708" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>LWVNYS</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/356568</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.6 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/2020" type="inclusive">1952-2020</unitdate></did></c><c id="aspace_f34c94679dc5c2e183a55a9933b4e02f" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>LWVUS</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/356569</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/2007" type="inclusive">1945-2007</unitdate></did></c></c><c id="aspace_b10cbe33a737995638ee02c8a416850f" level="series"><did><unittitle>Memorabilia</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/356570</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.78 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/2017" type="inclusive">1981-2017</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_7e47524edb3a8ba6de5055c344134efd"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged alphabetically by format.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_9f62f5f162ce9d84f79467c7cc444cad"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series consists of awards given to the organization, LWVAC stationery, novelty plastic bags, a license plate cover, a wristband, and buttons/pins.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
