<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap253.xml">apap253</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Hanks, Paul; Papers <num>apap253</num></titleproper><author>Alyssa Weickel</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2020</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-11-04 23:00:18 -0500</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Paul Hanks Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap253</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9.9 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1944/1966" type="inclusive">1944-1966</unitdate>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1944/1966" type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_dfd709db30c633203e01f30770f9635f">Paul B. Hanks Jr.'s papers document his last years as a Republican assemblyman in the New York State Legislature for Monroe County (N.Y.)'s 3rd District (1960-1964).</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_0094ad794b53b4f97f67a0df4fdb4f10">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_0301936012056a0da2a8722f978e009d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_4ff2ea9d380c7edc65d2956e7a4e2aa1">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains materials from Paul B. Hanks Jr.'s last years in the New York State Assembly, 1960-1964. In Series 1, Subject Files, the most significant topics include his correspondence and information on the Ways and Means Committee, upon which Hanks served, and constituent correspondence. These correspondences range from letters with the general public ones with companies, schools, and churches. There is much information about education, which includes budget, further education, adult education, and the State University budget.</p><p>Series 2, Legislation, consists of legislation introduced in the Assembly by Hanks. There are many memoranda from Hanks to/from outside businesses and associated groups with information on this legislation being introduced. </p><p>Please note the collection does not include materials from Hanks' earlier years in the Assembly.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_34b47b400a8d80ce538191a285722f89">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2020 by Alyssa Weickel.  Box and folder list to be added.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_fdb2288afaca13056f5441a6e6df5ebd">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_a6e6c69454e8d14a173f7560a8581f74">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_183e9ea92499eddaeae8fafb227058f4">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Paul Hanks initially donated his papers to Syracuse University in 1967.  In 2006, all the papers were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_829cb3704a120d3f1f44631856147179">
    <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
<p>Paul B. Hanks Jr. was born on March 4, 1923. He graduated from the University of Rochester with a BA degree. Hanks also graduated from Cornell Law with an LLB. He was also a World War II veteran and served as a radar navigator in the Pacific Theatre. Hanks was a member of the New York State Bar, Harsch-Crisp Seaman Post, No. 379, American Legion, V.F.W., Brockport Volunteer Fire Department, Phi Delta Phi Legal Fraternity and many other organizations. </p><p>Constituents from Monroe County's 3rd District elected Hanks to the New York State Assembly in 1952.  A Republican, he served in the Assembly until 1964.  Hanks served as chair of the Military Affairs Committee and was a member of the Ways and Means Committee, Banks Committee, Canals and Waterways, and Villages Committee.  Hanks was also the vice-chair of the Joint Legislative Committee on Unsatisfied Judgment Fund and Compulsory Automobile Insurance and a member of the Joint Legislative Committee on Winter Tourists and Interstate Cooperation.</p><p>The Hanks files document his passion for education. There are extensive materials about education budget, further education, adult education, and state university budget. Hanks wanted to give everyone a chance to learn at an affordable price. Not only did he want education to be accessible for adults, but he also wanted the school budgets to be used wisely. </p><p>Hanks also was passionate about the alcohol beverage control laws (A.B.C. Laws), and seat belt laws. Hanks compiled countless reports on the effects that alcohol had on young people and how it led to more motor vehicle accidents. Hanks wanted to cut down this effect by changing the A.B.C. laws and by raising the drinking age to 21. Hanks' papers also discuss the elevated damage that not wearing a seatbelt could result with vehicle accidents. Hanks was quite forward-looking with these ideas. The drinking age was not raised to 21 in New York until 1985. The first mandatory seat belt law went into effect in 1984 in New York.</p><p>Hanks passed away on September 17, 2002. He was survived by his two sons, daughter, six grandchildren, and one great-grandchild.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_2b956c5d1ca4520f37cc3a8f439e5f66">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is organized into the following series: Series 1, Subject Files, and Series 2, Legislation.  Both Series 1 and 2 are arranged alphabetically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_74a3f8a0a8c0abfc0180f6fa56e8d264">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: and Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Paul B. Hanks Papers, 1953-1964, 1974. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, the State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Hanks Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="local">Hanks, Paul B. (1923-2002)</geogname>
    <subject source="meg">Politics and Politicians</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Politicians--New York (State)</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_e71b5f29f2670dcecf8497c5fcc988b6" level="series"><did><unittitle>Subject Files</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8.6 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1944/1966" type="inclusive">1944-1966</unitdate><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1944/1966" type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ce0ecc5b127c1bce4276022a09099ccd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Series 1 contains Subject Files, which includes correspondence with the general public and organizations, budget information, education information, and information and correspondence about the Ways and Means Committee. There are also assorted newspaper clippings, reports, and notes taken by Hanks.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_1eacbbb1f2fcb49bb0d71e54cdf24401"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement></c><c id="aspace_6149a29b371132854700e30c307b8677" level="series"><did><unittitle>Legislation</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.3 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1961/1965" type="inclusive">1961-1965</unitdate><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1944/1966" type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_701498e2044bc6cb5b571ed8ac8c7337"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Series 2 contains legislation introduced by Hanks as well as support from his constituents. It also includes background information on the laws being introduced and Hanks' evidence on why they should be adopted.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_7f11f74d02bfeb1ff5106150d4a20126"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged  alphabetically.</p></arrangement></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
