<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap385.xml">apap385</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Nepo, Mark; Papers <num>apap385</num></titleproper><author>Jodi Boyle</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2020</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-06-30 23:00:04 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Mark Nepo Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="lcsh">Nepo, Mark</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>apap385</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.0 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1978/1991" type="inclusive">1978-1991</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_cdedb133f69cf2fefe12a56a9cb472d2">The Mark Nepo Papers contain a manuscript and research materials related to his literary career.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_3b690fc9b9de02b763b02532bc5e888b">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_eca013ea5aa489e436e43626f8444611">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_20a578efbf9162079e74b7511d1fd2bb">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>This collection includes hand written research notes and drafts, poems, and publications.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_e2696782ef829c050ddc46f6992c37e3">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>Mark Nepo donated print and audio books that he authored that will be separately cataloged for the book division of Special Collections.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <processinfo id="aspace_da789c59e5969b99cef1eb48783166cf">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The collection is currently unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_3fa28880959e73f8e02ad0d1d3220c6c">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is currently unprocessed.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_b8c72b314ffbe5ddae91ddf0f5c749f3">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Mark Nepo is a poet and philosopher who has taught in the fields of poetry and spirituality for more than 30 years. A <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph> best selling author, he has published 22 books and recorded 15 audio projects.  </p><p>Nepo graduated from  the University at Albany with a Doctor of Arts in English in 1980 and taught in the English Department for 18 years. </p>  </bioghist>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_e2ab4a44c9f941748d6cb4e18c0d451b">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Mark Nepo donated all materials in this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in December <date normal="2019">2019</date>.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_032a8b3a63017ad07742d5faa1fe694d">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_d054f9228d6720a3d637011e2d487e6a">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_a626e72e40595d357a5c473e87654fe3">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Mark Nepo Papers, 1979-1991. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Nepo Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Nepo, Mark</geogname>
    <subject source="meg">Literature</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
