<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap390.xml">apap390</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Society of Indian Psychologists; Records</titleproper><titleproper>Society of Indian Psychologists; Records <num>apap390</num></titleproper><author>Jodi Boyle</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2021</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-02-02 23:00:29 -0500</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Society of Indian Psychologists Records</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap390</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">176 Digital Files</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2015/2020" type="inclusive">2015-2020</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_149c03b88ffec101eb3b45316bec5ccf">This collections documents the operations of the Society of Indian Psychologists.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_6d67e2988823f7330b1a1560a424140c">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_cfe0872441cfc2b64a7168e20ce8ddde">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>This collection includes hundreds of digital files created by Society of Indian Psychologists' leadership in recent years. Materials include administrative records, newsletters, subject files, and correspondence.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_f14910078c7507b206959df9a0635d71">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_a8c18c40d26e9b2e41e4828c3f9d967d">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_0761380fa84e858870d6fd3a2a2058df">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Past President Gayle Morse, PhD (Mohawk) donated all materials to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in March 2021.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_02e4da4e0eb7cece5a8553481811d1c0">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_34c2ccec188ad4b681eded81941974c3">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_e079c8c14a1ee3f58e97602a8a63dca8">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Society of Indian Psychologists Records, 2015-2020. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Society of Indian Psychologists Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="aspace_8162338618cc5b5b7d22d9b5f4059d63">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Society of Indian Psychologists (SIP) is an organization for Native American Indigenous people who advocate for the mental well-being of Native peoples by increasing the knowledge and awareness of issues having an impact upon Native mental health.</p><p>Per SIP's By-laws' the term "Indian" refers to the Indigenous people of the Americas. Individual members of SIP who are Indigenous usually prefer to be identified by their traditional tribal names. Other group names sometimes referred to are Indigenous, Alaska Native, American Indian, Native American, Native Hawaiian, First Nations, Aboriginal people, and Native people.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Indians of North America--Psychology</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Medicine and Health Care</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
