<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap399.xml">apap399</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Zonta Club of Albany; Records</titleproper><titleproper>Zonta Club of Albany; Records <num>apap399</num></titleproper><author>Kathy Merring-Darling</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2023</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2023-07-20 23:00:37 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Zonta Club of Albany Records</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap399</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9.6 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1929/2021" type="inclusive">1929-2021</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_586237defca214f4201d41b9128e2da7">This collection documents the day-to-day activities of the Zonta Club of Albany, a service organization in the Captial Region of New York, comprised of executives, professionals, and businesswomen, as well as documenting the activities of the Club within Zonta International.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_35cd336ad2360d74533da6ad6c27c23b">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_2817cb4a6e251182985b98e9c23e6d57">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>The collection includes materials such as newsletters, meeting miinutes, member directories, club history, and records associated with the club's charitable activities both on a local and international scale.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_0114574ccb668f9495ad7e9fdba6a9c5">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2023 by Kathy Merring-Darling.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_0251ea98b4d0c0a6469548d2c3d7064f">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is made up of three series that are arranged alphabetically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_31660c2394f68c4219e11ba19d9c3e85">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Club archivist Rita Cousino donated all materials in this collection to the M.E. Grenandner Department of Special Collections and Archives in 2022.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_29b60fffe74820fef12e75387245346c">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_0da7f73d5c5cb44552e7b3d0ed40fc8b">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_ad4271c150351dea160b1d1e32ef9ec7">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Zonta Club of Albany Records, 1929-2021. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Zonta Club of Albany Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="aspace_6a8dda573eb2ed1af4995d9411dfc372">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>On May 27, 1929, 15 women met to plan the organization of a Zonta Club in Albany, New York. On October 30, 1929 the first women's service club in Albany officially became a Zonta Club. The Club is a member of the worldwide Zonta International which has 33,000 members in 1,242 clubs in 68 countries. The goal of the Club is to advance the status of women and girls. Zonta was founded in 1919 in Buffalo, New York. </p>

<p>Throughout its history, the Zonta Club of Albany has engaged in outreach, conducted fundraising, volunteered, and implemented projects to benefit Capital District women and girls. These efforts have included the building of an interfaith chapel at Memorial Hospital in Albany; contributing toward the formation of the Albany Girls Club; and supporting such local programs and organizations as Mercy House, The Next Step, Inc., Albany Medical Center, Albany County Jail Women's Project, the Capital City Rescue Mission's Women and Children's Center, the Equinox Domestic Violence Shelter, and many more. In addition, the Zonta Club of Albany participates in district and international award programs. Local awards include the Frances Wodward/Helena Roscoe Nursing Award and the Zelda Uthe Award given to a law student. </p>

<p>The Zonta Club of Albany also was instrumental in the establishment of other local Zonta clubs including ones in Troy, Montgomery/Fulton, Columbia/Greene, and Kingston. </p>
  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <function source="local">Zonta Club of Albany (N.Y.)</function>
    <function source="lcsh">Zonta International</function>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women in nonprofit organizations--New York (State)--Albany</subject>
    <geogname source="meg">Albany, New York</geogname>
    <subject source="meg">Women</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Neighborhood and Community Associations</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State)--Social conditions</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Fundraising--New York (State)--Albany (N.Y.)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women in charitable work--New York (State)--Albany</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women--New York (State)--Albany--Societies and clubs</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Minutes</subject>
    <genreform source="local">Scrapbooks</genreform>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Newsletters</genreform>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Administrative records</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Membership lists</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Conference reports</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Financial Records</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Programs</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Banners</genreform>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Photographs</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_8f3518cc81caa823d711cd18f52b6f8b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Administration</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.4 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1929/2019" type="inclusive">1929-2019</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial></did><arrangement id="aspace_0740d587ad4e73ceb05d6498e5396646"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_e3b9d59fcbccb354e13534ca8629617a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The Administrative series contains: account book, budget and financial reports, by laws, charters, correspondence relating to the administration of the club, and meeting minutes. The materials provide information regarding the structure of the club, how meetings were conducted, and the election of officers.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_02411ece01d9c2a6518c120870cf5412" level="series"><did><unittitle>Subject Files</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4.8 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1936/2021" type="inclusive">1936-2021</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>.</langmaterial></did><arrangement id="aspace_e19151c9c4972ec223c6617f65a6d6f4"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_7f289c8b8f32c5111ae398b4d24594d7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The Subject series contains materials relating to the club's history, member directories, photographs, conference and seminar materials, correspondence (Thank You notes), and programs. The series also contains flat files and oversize boxes which house scrapbooks one of which documents the Clubs's involvement with the Memorial Chapel, banners, and a sash. This series provides information about how the Club worked within the local community as well as with other area clubs.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_660ed9533d562ef2b2258e62f083482e" level="series"><did><unittitle>Publications</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.4 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1939/2019" type="inclusive">1939-2019</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>.</langmaterial></did><arrangement id="aspace_d68e31614b738a31edbf4eba4dba4372"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_c18cdaf34b42a3caef163e465ced2312"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The Publications series includes both local and international materials such as: <emph render="italic">The Dope Sheet</emph>, <emph render="italic">The Albany Zontian</emph>, and <emph render="italic">Zontian</emph>, <emph render="italic">The Zontian Biennial Issue</emph>, <emph render="italic">Zonta International Program Issue</emph>, <emph render="italic">Zonta International Foundation Biennium Highlights</emph>, and <emph render="italic">Zonta International Newsletter</emph>. These publications highlight the activities of the Zonta Club of Albany as well as those associated with international Zonta Clubs.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
