<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap415.xml">apap415</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">White, Patricia E.; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>White, Patricia E.; Papers <num>apap415</num></titleproper><author>Jodi Boyle</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2024</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-10-11 23:00:12 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Patricia E. White Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>apap415</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.10 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">165.28 MB</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1982/1983" type="inclusive">1982-1983</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_be5c4d45dd83bb30a4176f5501627f80">This collection contains images of women's events in the Capital Region of New York in the early 1980s.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_83671bd329cbebbf6989b25faf1a38dc">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_439bbd773fc033e65cd2a1aa2d83fe8b">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>This collection contains digital images from Women's Day in Washington Park in Albany from August 1982; a Wallflower Order Dance Collective Performance from November 1982; and a Hudson, NY Women's History storefront display from March 1983 along with the negatives and contact sheets of the images.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_67d0992fb326aef7508817267ef73144">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_91cacb96ddd4a39427389818c654cd64">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_42cdf5599f1995e8f091a9cc910ca623">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Patricia E. White donated all items in this collection in 2024.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_d1809f6834938f4a125c34dfdd8c633e">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Patricia E. White Papers, 1982-1983. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the White Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <userestrict id="aspace_c199bc556ee8be9f3c2c8cfba60b83c5">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <arrangement id="aspace_32b3018d035239827fc0b712912707d9">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is currently unprocessed and is not yet arranged. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_184c892c646ec3922d2de9218fc54c6a">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>A former resident of the Capital Region of New York, Patricia E. White was active in the women's movement and photographed all the events in this collection.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <function source="lcsh">International Women's Day--New York (State)--Albany</function>
    <subject source="meg">Albany, New York</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Women</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
