<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>apap176</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>National Advisory Committee on Criminal Justice Standards and Goals, Various Task Force; Records <num>apap176</num></titleproper><author>Jodi Boyle</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2020</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-06-16 23:00:03 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>National Advisory Committee on Criminal Justice Standards and Goals, Various Task Force Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="lcsh">United States. National Advisory Committee on Criminal Justice Standards and Goals</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>apap176</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1967/1972" type="inclusive">1967-1972</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_20696c1813fec999e9f3e58ba7076b07">The collection contains materials from three separate national criminal justice task forces all from the National Advisory Committee on Criminal Justice Standards and Goals.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_e047b74498c4dbf5857dc86ef7e92ab2">English.</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_2c2d50cca73cb6703f4b3de56e74907a">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_ccec49616d0d6761d15df59e3fa1eb6d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_19682a5d9957fd5131ab01bcdc8b05a4">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Jodi Boyle.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_3a3a1d38fb49aa59069cf4ca563a923b">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection contains reports and materials from national task forces from the National Advisory Committee on Criminal Justice Standards and Goals. This includes the four volume Report on the Task Force on Corrections, the Report of the Task Force on Information Systems and Statistics, and note cards on the Task Force Report on Organized Crime. There also are related subject files.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_b43a57d7897bbe8f310c9c8f9c99a049">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged chrontologically.  There are no series.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_d7cdda44e635f319bd4e50be7d4de6f5">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_722dd3c839edb0809cb00c6a0677ae92">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_89824e8e46b2fdf053b4c4d59c53a3bd">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, National Advisory Committee on Criminal Justice Standards and Goals, Various Task Force Records, 1967-1972. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Corrections Task Force Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_4a22a49aaf357705046dd409619008e4">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The provenance of this collection is unknown.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_6a656aa6799b344825012f9762a45c93">
    <head>Historical Sketch</head>
<p>Appointed in 1971 by the Administrator of the Law Enforcement Assistance Administration, the National Advisory Commission on Criminal Justice Standards and Goals was tasked with creating the first-ever national criminal justice standards and objectives for crime reduction and prevention at the state and local levels.  The 1971 Commission’s work built upon the report of the 1967 Presidential Commission on Law Enforcement and Administration of Justice entitled "The Challenge of Crime in a Free Society," and the reports of its task forces.  In 1973 the National Advisory Commission issued six reports each developed by a separate task force with dozens of staff members.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Criminal justice, Administration of</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Reports.</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">United States. National Advisory Committee on Criminal Justice Standards and Goals</geogname>
    <subject source="meg">Criminal Justice and Prisons</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
