<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE ead SYSTEM 'ead.dtd'>
<ead id="nam_apap113">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="apap014" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/apap113.html">nam_apap113</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>INTERNATIONAL ASSOCIATION OF MACHINISTS AND AEROSPACE WORKERS (IAMAW), LODGE 1145 RECORDS (APAP113)<date normal="1971/1998" type="inclusive">1971-1998</date></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="2015" type="publication">Copyright 2015 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation audience="internal">Jodi Boyle<date normal="2015">2015</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date normal="2014">2014</date>
        <item>EAD file created</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_apap113</unitid>
      <unittitle>International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers (IAMAW), Lodge 1145 Records<unitdate normal="1971/1998" type="inclusive">1971-1998</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">The collection includes vouchers, bills, correspondence, administrative records, and related material from the International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, Lodge 1145.  </abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <corpname encodinganalog="110" source="local">International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, Lodge 1145 (Selkirk, NY)</corpname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">4.5</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage: ">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="meg" encodinganalog="650">Labor</subject>
    </controlaccess>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Biographical History</head>
      <p>The International Association of Machinists &amp; Aerospace Workers (IAMAW), Lodge 1145, is based in Selkirk and DeWitt, NY.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>The collection includes vouchers, bills, correspondence, administrative records, and related material from the International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, Lodge 1145.  </p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement>
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>John Flaunders donated the collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives.<date normal="2001-05">2001 May</date></p>
    </acqinfo>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers (IAMAW), Lodge 1145 Records, 1971-1998. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the IAMAW, Lodge 1145 Records).</p>
    </prefercite>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
