<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead id="nam_apap365">
  <eadheader audience="external" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="##" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/apap365.html">nam_apap365</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>HOLDING OUR OWN RECORDS (APAP365)<date normal="1983/2006" type="inclusive">1983-2006</date></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="2016" type="publication">Copyright 2016 by the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Jodi Boyle<date normal="2016-11-07">2016 November 7</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>Holding Our Own Records<date normal="1983/2006" type="inclusive">1983-2006</date></titleproper>
      <publisher/>
      <date type="publication">Copyright 2016 by the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      <p>For reference queries contact Grenander Department Reference staff or (518)-437-3934</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_apap365</unitid>
      <unittitle>Holding Our Own Records<unitdate label="Date:" normal="1983/2006" type="inclusive">1983-2006</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">This collection documents the day-to-day activities of Holding Our Own, an organization established to incite and support feminist social justice in New York's Capital Region.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <corpname encodinganalog="110" source="local">Holding Our Own (Albany, N.Y.)</corpname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">15</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage:">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
      <p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
      <p>The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Carmen Rau.<date normal="2016">2016</date></p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>Established in 1982, Holding Our Own's supports feminist social justice.  A multiracial, multicultural philanthropic foundation led by women of color, Holding Our Own, Inc. awards grants to organizations and projects in New York's Capital Region which benefit women.  Special attention is given to grassroots organizations and those which represent women who face bias or have limited access to traditional funding sources.  Past grants included funding of reading groups for children of color, a recreation project for women with AIDS/HIV, carpentry training for battered women, and a cooperative tutoring project involving a public housing tenant group and a local college.
</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>This collection contains meeting minutes, grant materials, award ceremony files, subject files, conference materials, administrative records, project reports, and other administrative files.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Holding Our Own Records, 1983-2006. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University  Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Holding Our Own Records).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <corpname source="local" encodinganalog="610">Holding Our Own (Albany, N.Y.)</corpname>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Women--New York (State)--Social conditions</subject>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Minutes</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Files by subject</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Grant proposals</genreform>
    </controlaccess>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
