<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE ead SYSTEM 'ead.dtd'>
<ead id="nam_apap259">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="apap014" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/apap259.html">nam_apap259</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>EUGENE JAMES KEOGH PAPERS (APAP259)<date normal="1937-1972" type="inclusive">1854-1858</date></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="2015" type="publication">Copyright 2015 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation audience="internal">Conversion and encoding by ArchProteus, <date normal="2014">2014</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date normal="2014">2014</date>
        <item>EAD file created</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_apap259</unitid>
      <unittitle>Eugene James Keogh Papers<unitdate normal="1937-1972" type="inclusive">1854-1858</unitdate><unitdate normal="1937/1972" type="bulk">1937/1972</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">This collection consists of papers from Keough's career as a New York State Assemblyman and U.S. Representative from New York. </abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcsh">Keogh, Eugene J. (Eugene James), 1907-1989</persname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">171</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage: ">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Biographical History</head>
      <p>Keogh graduated from the school of commerce of New York University in 1927 and from the school of law of Fordham University in 1930. Keogh worked as a teacher in the New York City public schools in 1927 and 1928, a clerk with New York City Board of Transportation 1928-1930; law clerk in 1930 and 1931; was admitted to the bar in 1932 and commenced practice in New York City; member of the New York State assembly in 1936; elected as a Democrat to the Seventy-fifth and to the fourteen succeeding Congresses (January 3, 1937-January 3, 1967); chairman, Committee on Revision of the Laws (Seventy-sixth through Seventy-ninth Congresses); was not a candidate for reelection in 1966 to the Ninetieth Congress; resumed the practice of law; member, New York State Racing and Wagering Board, 1973-1976; was a resident of New York City until his death there on May 26, 1989.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>This collection consists of papers from Keough's career as a New York State Assemblyman and U.S. Representative from New York. </p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement>
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this manuscript group were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Syracuse University. <date normal="2005">2005</date></p>
    </acqinfo>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Eugene J. Keogh Papers. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University  Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <subject source="meg" encodinganalog="650">Politics and Politicians</subject>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcsh">Keogh, Eugene J. (Eugene James), 1907-1989</persname>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">U. S. Congress</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Keogh plans--Law and legislation</subject>
    </controlaccess>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
