<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead id="nam_apap240">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="apap014" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/apap240.html">nam_apap240</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>GEORGE DE LUCA PAPERS (APAP240)<date normal="1949/1964" type="inclusive">1949-1964</date></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="2015" type="publication">Copyright 2015 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation audience="internal">Jodi Boyle<date normal="2015">2015</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date normal="2014">2014</date>
        <item>EAD file created</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_apap240</unitid>
      <unittitle>George De Luca Papers<unitdate normal="1949/1964" type="inclusive">1949-1964</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">The collection consists of materials from George De Luca's professional career and personal life.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcsh">De Luca, George B., 1889-1983</persname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">17.2</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage: ">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="meg" encodinganalog="650">Politics and Politicians</subject>
    </controlaccess>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Biographical History</head>
      <p>George De Luca of Bronx, NY was a Democrat and served as Lieutenant Governor of New York from 1955 to 1959. DeLuca served as a delegate to the Democratic National Convention from New York in 1956 and 1960.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>The collection contains correspondence (professional and personal), bills, subject files, clippings, scrapbooks, proceedings of New York State Democratic Conventions, and materials related to George De Luca's legal career.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement>
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <chronlist>
        <chronitem>
          <date normal="1963/1977">1963-1977</date>
          <event>George De Luca initially donated his papers to Syracuse University in a series of four accessions.</event>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date normal="2006">2006</date>
          <event>The papers were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives. </event>
        </chronitem>
      </chronlist>
    </acqinfo>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, George De Luca Papers, 1949-1964. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the De Luca Papers).</p>
    </prefercite>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
