<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead id="nam_apap307">
  <eadheader audience="external" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="##" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/apap307.html">nam_apap307</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>MICHAEL ROBERT MCNULTY  (APAP307)<date normal="1988/2008" type="inclusive">1988-2008</date></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="2016" type="publication">Copyright 2016 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Brian Keough<date normal="2016-12-21">2016 December 21</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>Michael Robert McNulty <date normal="1988/2008" type="inclusive">1988-2008</date></titleproper>
      <publisher/>
      <date type="publication">Copyright 2016 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      <p>For reference queries contact Grenander Department Reference staff or (518)-437-3934</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_apap307</unitid>
      <unittitle>Michael Robert McNulty <unitdate label="Date:" normal="1988/2008" type="inclusive">1988-2008</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">The collection contains the records from Michael Robert McNulty's tenure as a U.S. Representative from New York from 1989 to 2009. He served in Congress for ten terms and was a member of the House Ways &amp; Means Committee, where he was chairman of the Subcommittee on Social Security. He chose not to run for reelection in 2008. </abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcsh">McNulty, Michael R. (Michael Robert), 1947- </persname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">73</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage:">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this collection is restricted. The entire collection is closed until January 2029.  The constituent case files are closed until January 2039.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
      <p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
      <p>The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 2008.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>Michael Robert McNulty was a U.S. Representative from New York. A Democrat, he represented New Yorks 21st Congressional District (which encompasses Albany, Schenectady and Troy as well as portions of Fulton, Montgomery and Schoharie Counties) from 1989 to 2009. McNulty was born in Troy in 1947 and graduated from the College of the Holy Cross in Worcester, MA in 1969. He served as town supervisor of Green Island, N.Y. from 1969 to 1977 and as mayor from 1977 to 1983. That year he was elected to the New York State Assembly, where he served until 1988. When Congressman Samuel Stratton withdrew from the 1988 Congressional race, McNulty replaced him as the Democratic candidate and was elected. He served in Congress for ten terms and was a member of the House Ways &amp; Means Committee, where he was chairman of the Subcommittee on Social Security. He chose not to run for reelection in 2008. </p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>The collection  spans and documents McNulty's tenure in the House of Representatives. It includes subject files, bills introduced by McNulty, briefing books and background reports for Congressmen, travel folders of materials related to Congressional delegation visits around the world, legislative profiles, legislative action guides, legislative calendars, photographs (both framed and unframed), newsletters, news clips, correspondence, books, certificates of appreciation from constituents and groups, and audio/video materials.  Per the memorandum of agreement, this entire collection is closed until January 2029.  The constituent case files are closed until January 2039.  </p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Michael Robert McNulty , 1988-2008. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University  Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Michael Robert McNulty ).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <subject source="meg" encodinganalog="650">Politics and Politicians</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Politicians. </subject>
    </controlaccess>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
