<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" id="apap346">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap346.xml">apap346</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Wanger, Eugene G. and Marilyn M. Wanger Death Penalty; Collection <num>apap346</num></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2016</date>
        </p>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-04-12 15:51:41 -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2016 April 20</date>
        <item>Encoded in EAD by M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Eugene G. Wanger and Marilyn M. Wanger Death Penalty Collection<unitdate normal="1754/2015" type="inclusive">1754-2015</unitdate></unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname source="lcsh">Wanger, Eugene G.</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>apap346</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">147.2 cubic ft.</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract id="aspace_fd1cfa84a64d20b4107620a5d25906be">Over the course of 50 years, Eugene G. Wanger created or collected the materials about capital punishment that comprise the Eugene G. Wanger and Marilyn M. Wanger Death Penalty Collection. The collection includes a wide range of materials on the death penalty documenting its history, efforts to abolish or reinstate the practice, its psychological impact, compatibility on religious, moral or ethical grounds, and its operation.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_91b1b3eeb7de34ad0391a9a075117d7c">English</langmaterial>
      <physloc id="aspace_1109e1bee0e10e5a6042a9910d44ce41">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <container id="aspace_e0d9c29979ed75ce27edec2b084d640a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
    </did>
    <processinfo id="aspace_d2199046d27f71634efb79a2953558a2">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed in 2016 by unprocessed.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_ea0f2df67b395c77e68bc76c66dc40e6">
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>The collection is open for use by qualified and responsible researchers.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_aeaee65dd90c87f40344e4023e94d9bd">
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from the collection without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_bdd9fcaf01c474d42ab78a264de2d688">
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Eugene G. Wanger in installments<date normal="2014/2016">2014-2016</date>.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_c0df4732727515a863582a4871d5d689">
      <head>Biographical Note</head>
      <p>A graduate of Amherst College and The University of Michigan Law School, Eugene G. Wanger returned home to Lansing, Michigan to practice law after obtaining his degree. In 1961-1962 fellow voters from Lansing elected him the youngest delegate from his political party to Michigan’s Constitutional Convention where, among other provisions, he authored the section of the state constitution which bans capital punishment. Mr. Wanger later served as Lansing's City Attorney and chairman of Ingham County's Board of Commissioners.</p>
      <p> Beginning in 1972, Mr. Wanger has co-chaired the Michigan Committee Against Capital Punishment, co-founded the Michigan Committee Against the Death Penalty, and been active in numerous historical organizations. In 2005, he received the Champion of Justice Award from the State Bar of Michigan for superior professional accomplishments benefiting the state and nation, including his work on capital punishment.</p>
      <p> Marilyn G. Wanger, born Marilyn Morris in Mason, Michigan, is a graduate of Michigan State University and The University of Michigan Law School where she met Mr. Wanger. During her professional career, she served as a Michigan Assistant Attorney General and then as a Commissioner of Michigan's Court of Appeals. </p>
      <p> Married for more than 50 years, Eugene and Marilyn Wanger continue to reside in Lansing, Michigan.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_233f6295ad2cb6f1929bef9fdb71210b">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>The Eugene G. Wanger and Marilyn M. Wanger Death Penalty Collection contains a wide variety of materials that document the history and debate about capital punishment as well as discuss the criminal justice system surrounding it. The collection includes books, artifacts and ephemera, pamphlets, audio and video, prints, posters, buttons, reports, testimony, correspondence, files by subject, advocacy materials, and clippings. Mr. Wanger created or collected the materials himself.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_1ddc620315c091664ff81d2f28e16226">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection was arranged by the donor.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite id="aspace_079358a0da277b10f269da7152d631ea">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Eugene G. Wanger and Marilyn M. Wanger Death Penalty Collection, 1754-2015. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Eugene G. Wanger and Marilyn M. Wanger Death Penalty Collection).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="meg">Death Penalty</subject>
      <subject source="meg">Criminal Justice and Prisons</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Capital punishment--Political aspects--United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Capital punishment--Social aspects--United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Executions and executioners--United States</subject>
      <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Pamphlets</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Clippings</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Printed ephemera</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Books</genreform>
      <persname source="lcsh">Wanger, Eugene G.</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc/>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
