<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" id="apap326">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap326.xml">apap326</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>New Yorkers for Alternatives to the Death Penalty Records; Records <num>apap326</num></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2016</date>
        </p>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-04-14 11:45:17 -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2016 December 26</date>
        <item>Encoded in EAD by Brian Keough</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>New Yorkers for Alternatives to the Death Penalty<unitdate normal="1984/2011" type="inclusive">1984-2011</unitdate></unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname source="lcsh">New Yorkers for Alternatives to the Death Penalty</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>apap326</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">14 cubic ft.</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract id="aspace_facb577433a4fa911198392d46b4dc35">This collection contains the records of New Yorkers for Alternatives to the Death Penalty (NYADP).</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_e9d582d5467a614a85810d4f1eda9dd1">English</langmaterial>
      <physloc id="aspace_ce6c3b6331610d4f4a7fdf37881bedb1">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <container id="aspace_34abcf2c33438742fac3c1b55b5899ab" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
    </did>
    <processinfo id="aspace_63352b1379164503974e2d4db615b623">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed in 2016 by unprocessed.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_703cb6366d85568d7eb0502ff02cf02a">
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_f7ba82bb3a5a1c82b6f8abfbd9ea61ef">
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
      <p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
      <p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_0c029f75181942e82304a1e9f292b678">
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_33d1d4ba04dc6b277f2d7eb2588398cc">
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>New Yorkers for Alternatives to the Death Penalty (NYADP), founded in 1992 as New Yorkers Against the Death Penalty, was a nonprofit, nonpartisan organization that in 2008 expanded its mission after achieving its primary objective of the effective abolition of capital punishment in New York. Led by executive director David Kaczynski, NYADP supports effective, rational, and humane approaches to the problem of violent crime in a post-death penalty environment. This collection documents both the organizations current and earlier mission.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_8be9135802f19ffc0aa046cba39d0f32">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>The collection contains correspondence, interviews, news clippings, newsletters, awards, materials related to conferences, speaking opportunities and meetings, photographs, scholarly articles, audio/video, buttons, and materials from national death penalty abolitionist groups.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_7af68fd6d508e81a8aaedbd3d5811ac6">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite id="aspace_73b16ef86c1a881bac04bcba218d8c94">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, New Yorkers for Alternatives to the Death Penalty , 1984-2011. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the New Yorkers for Alternatives to the Death Penalty ).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="meg">Death Penalty</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Capital punishment</subject>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc/>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
