<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead id="nam_apap175">
  <eadheader audience="external" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="DC">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/apap175.xml" identifier="##">nam_apap175</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>MALCOLM WILSON PAPERS (APAP175)<date normal="1971/1974" type="inclusive">1971-1974</date></titleproper>
        <author>Chris Batista</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date type="publication" normal="2006">Copyright 2006 by the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Michele Tuohy<date normal="2014">2014</date>
			</creation>
      <langusage>
        <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="Language">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>MALCOLM WILSON PAPERS (APAP175)<date normal="1971/1974" type="inclusive">1971-1974</date></titleproper>
      <publisher> M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
      <date type="publication">2006</date>
      <p>For reference queries contact Grenander Department Reference staff or (518)-437-3934</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_apap175</unitid>
      <unittitle>Malcolm Wilson Papers<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971-1974" label="Date:"> 1971-1974</unitdate></unittitle>
      <origination>
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcsh">Wilson, Malcolm, 1914-2000</persname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">0.4</extent>
        <physfacet>processed to date</physfacet>
      </physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">This collection contains papers related to Malcolm Wilson and political 
	  career as governor of New York.  Included are news articles, press conferences and other materials 
	  relating to his political career during the years 1971-1974.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <physloc label="Storage:">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access</head>
      <p> Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright.
        Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will
        provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal
        determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish
        material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and
        Archives. </p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All the items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E.
        Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
      <p>Charles Malcolm Wilson was born on February 26, 1914. Wilson was a graduate of 
	  Fordham University (1933) and Fordham Law (1936). He became a member of the New York 
	  State Assembly in 1939 and in 1958 he left office to run for lieutenant governor 
	  on the ticket with Nelson A. Rockefeller. Wilson’s first run for public office was in 
	  1938 when he was elected to the State Assembly from Yonkers. Wilson was re-elected to 
	  the Assembly for nine additional terms from a predominantly Democratic district. As a 
	  member of the State Assembly, he introduced 1,250 bills of which 432 were passed in 
	  both houses of the legislature and signed by the governor. One of the more significant
	  bills to be passed was the creation of the Higher Education Assistance Corporation 
	  providing for a state guaranteed loan program for students attending public or private 
	  colleges. Wilson served as lieutenant governor under Nelson Rockefeller until 
	  Rockefeller’s resignation in 1973. Rockefeller recognized Wilson as the man who pushed 
	  for revenue sharing as well as working with local and state government. Wilson served 
	  as governor from 1973 through 1974.</p>
      <p>On June 1, 1974, Wilson delivered a speech on his candidacy to run for governor, 
	  stating: “What I am and have been throughout my public service: progressive in meeting 
	  human needs and conservative in handling the people’s tax dollars.” Wilson ran for 
	  governor in 1975, but lost the election to Hugh Carey of Brooklyn. After retirement 
	  from political life, Wilson served as CEO of Manhattan Saving Banks. Wilson died on 
	  March 13, 2000.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>This collection contains papers related to the political life of Malcolm Wilson and 
	  his tenure as governor of New York. The collection includes a selection of speeches and 
	  addresses by Wilson. Wilson’s swearing in address as the 50th governor of New York State 
	  is one of the highlights of the collection.</p>
      <p>Wilson’s work with the Women’s National Republican Club is documented in the collection. 
	  Wilson was a strong supporter of women’s rights. He emphasized that as a Republican, he 
	  was committed to the rights and freedoms of individuals. The collection also includes 
	  transcripts of press conferences from 1973-1974. Also included is the transcript of a press 
	  conference regarding the Watergate Scandal in which Wilson commented on the president, the 
	  nation, and his thoughts about how the situation was handled.</p>
      <p>The remarks folder includes the remarks of Governor Wilson on the issues of the day. Some 
	  of the more interesting documents relate to Wilson’s work in Harlem and the erection of a 
	  state office building in uptown Manhattan. Wilson believed that this was a historic moment 
	  because of the participation of African Americans in a state government project.</p>
      <p>Wilson’s remarks when announcing his candidacy for the governorship of New York in 1974 is 
	  also in the collection. In the press conference transcript, Wilson is questioned about his 
	  campaign and his preparations for the upcoming election. Wilson discusses the needs of New 
	  York State and the state budget which he wanted to divide between local and state government. 
	  Wilson was also questioned about ethnic groups and minorities in New York City and he responded 
	  by stating that he was not concerned about political affiliation or race, but rather the job he 
	  was doing for the people of New York.</p>
      <p>The New York State budget is always a cause for concern in order to balance the needs of the 
	  citizens of New York. One of Rockefeller’s and Wilson’s main concerns was the increased taxation 
	  in New York State and the services which needed to be provided for the people of New York. Along 
	  with Assembly Speaker Perry Duryea, Wilson attempted to make sure that New Yorkers were getting 
	  their tax dollars back in through public services.</p>
      <p>News clippings are also a vital part of the collection. In this section of the collection you 
	  can find articles related to Malcolm Wilson and his initiatives. One of the news clippings is a 
	  New York Times article discussing Rockefeller’s work that Wilson continued after he assumed the 
	  position of governor.</p>
      <p>In this collection you will also find Wilson’s message to the Legislature from 1974, in which 
	  he addresses the needs of New York State. He cited the energy crisis and improving the 
	  administration of justice as areas in need of improvement.</p>
      <p>Related collections in the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives can 
	  be found at the Subject Guides for the New York State Modern Political Archive and Public Servants 
	  and Politicians.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is organized alphabetically. There are no series.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <subject source="meg" encodinganalog="650">Public Servants </subject>
      <subject source="meg" encodinganalog="650">Politics and Politicians</subject>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcsh">Wilson, Malcolm, 1914-2000 </persname>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Politics</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Governors</subject>
      <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">New York (State)</geogname>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">News Clippings</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Remarks</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Press Conference</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Speeches (documents)</genreform>
    </controlaccess>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Malcolm Wilson Papers,  1971-1974. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as [shortened name]).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>Container List</head>
      <c01 id="nam_apap175-1">
        <did>
          <container type="Box">1</container>
          <container type="Folder">1</container>
          <unittitle>Budget Cuts</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1971">1971</unitdate>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="nam_apap175-2">
        <did>
          <container type="Box">1</container>
          <container type="Folder">2</container>
          <unittitle>Candidacy and Nomination</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1974">1974</unitdate>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="nam_apap175-3">
        <did>
          <container type="Box">1</container>
          <container type="Folder">3</container>
          <unittitle>Message to the Legislature</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1974">1974</unitdate>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="nam_apap175-4">
        <did>
          <container type="Box">1</container>
          <container type="Folder">4</container>
          <unittitle>News Clippings</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1971/1974">circa 1971-1974</unitdate>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="nam_apap175-5">
        <did>
          <container type="Box">1</container>
          <container type="Folder">5</container>
          <unittitle>News Clippings</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1971/1974">circa 1971-1974</unitdate>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="nam_apap175-6">
        <did>
          <container type="Box">1</container>
          <container type="Folder">6</container>
          <unittitle>Press Conferences</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1973">1973</unitdate>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="nam_apap175-7">
        <did>
          <container type="Box">1</container>
          <container type="Folder">7</container>
          <unittitle>Press Conferences</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1974">1974</unitdate>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="nam_apap175-8">
        <did>
          <container type="Box">1</container>
          <container type="Folder">8</container>
          <unittitle>Press Conferences</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1974">1974</unitdate>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="nam_apap175-9">
        <did>
          <container type="Box">1</container>
          <container type="Folder">9</container>
          <unittitle>Remarks of Governor Malcolm Wilson</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1974">1974</unitdate>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="nam_apap175-10">
        <did>
          <container type="Box">1</container>
          <container type="Folder">10</container>
          <unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1973/1974">1973-1974</unitdate>
        </did>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
