<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='eadcbs6-su1_gw_no_series.xsl'?> 
<!DOCTYPE ead SYSTEM 'ead.dtd'>
<ead id="nam_apap112">
  <eadheader audience="external" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="##" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/apap112.html">nam_apap112</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>PAUL H. APPLEBY PAPERS (APAP112)<date normal="1944/1956" type="inclusive">1944-1956</date>
        </titleproper>
        <author>Amy C. Schindler</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="2002" type="publication">Copyright 2002 by the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Jodi Boyle<date normal="2016-12">2016 December</date>
      </creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date/>
        <item/>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>Paul H. Appleby Papers<date normal="1944/1956" type="inclusive">1944-1956</date>
      </titleproper>
      <publisher>
			</publisher>
      <date type="publication">Copyright 2002 by the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      <p>&amp;contact</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_apap112</unitid>
      <unittitle>Paul H. Appleby Papers<unitdate label="Date:" normal="1944/1956" type="inclusive">1944-1956</unitdate>
        </unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">The Paul H. Appleby collection is composed of correspondence and Appleby's writings and speeches from his experience in government service. </abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcsh">Appleby, Paul H., (Paul Henson), 1891-1963</persname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc label="Physical Characteristics:">
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">0.17</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage:">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
	    <userestrict>
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
      <p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
      <p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were donated to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives before <date normal="2000">2000</date></p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Biographical History</head>
      <p>Paul Henson Appleby was born in Greene County, Missouri on September 13, 1891, to Andrew B. and Mary (Johnson) Appleby. He earned his A.B. from Grinnell College in 1913. He married Ruth Meyer on October 4, 1916. The couple had three children, Margaret Finley, Mary Ellen Sarbaugh, and L. Tom.</p>
      <p>Appleby began his career as a newspaper publisher in Montana, Minnesota, and Iowa from 1914 through 1920. He was the editor of Iowa Magazine in Waterloo, Iowa from 1920-1924 and an editorial writer at the Des Moines Register and Tribune from 1924 until 1928. The family moved to Virginia in 1928 where Appleby again worked as a newspaper publisher until accepting a position with the U.S. government. Appleby served as the Executive Assistant to the Secretary of Agriculture from 1933 through 1940 and the Under Secretary of Agriculture from 1940 until 1944. He was also the Assistant Director of the U.S. Bureau of the Budget from 1944 through 1947. In 1947, Appleby moved to Syracuse, New York and became the Dean of the Maxwell School of Citizenship and Public Affairs.</p>
      <p>Appleby also served as the Chief of the Food Mission to Great Britain in 1941-1942, chair of the International Wheat Conference in 1942, chair of the International Wheat Council from 1942 through 1944, Special Assistant to the Lend-Lease administrator from 1942-1943, and the Special Assistant to the Secretary of State in 1943. He was the U.S. delegate to the Hot Springs Food Conference in 1943, the U.S. member of the Interim Committee on Food and Agriculture for 1943-1944, a member of the Contributions Committee of the United Nations in 1946, a member of the board o the Institute of Public Affairs from 1947-1950, a board member of the Franklin D. Roosevelt Foundation in 1953, and other boards.</p>
      <p>Paul H. Appleby died in 1963.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>The Paul H. Appleby collection is composed of correspondence and Appleby's writings and speeches from his experience in government service. Correspondents included John M. Gaus, Joseph P. Harris, and Donald Stone from 1944 through 1946. Appleby's manuscripts on government and public administration cover the years 1944-1956. A broad range of topics are discussed from the military to the Tennessee Valley Authority.</p>
      <p>Additional information about Paul Appleby is available from an online guide of References for Paul Appleby created by the National Agricultural Library as part of the USDA History Collection.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is organized alphabetically.  There are no series.</p>
      <list type="simple">
        <item>Subseries: no series </item>
      </list>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Paul H. Appleby Papers, 1944-1956. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University  Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Appleby Papers).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
	<head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcsh">Appleby, Paul H., (Paul Henson), 1891-1963</persname>
      <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">United States--Bureau of the Budget</corpname>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Public administration</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Budget--United States</subject>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Manuscripts</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>Container List</head>
	  <c01 id="nam_apap112-1">
        <did>
          <container type="Box">1</container>
          <container type="Folder">1</container>
          <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1944/1946">1944/1946</unitdate>
        </did>
      </c01>
	  	  <c01 id="nam_apap112-2">
        <did>
          <container type="Box">1</container>
          <container type="Folder">2</container>
          <unittitle>Writings</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1944/1956">1944/1956</unitdate>
		  <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1944/1956">Undated</unitdate>
        </did>
      </c01>
	  	  	  <c01 id="nam_apap112-3">
        <did>
          <container type="Box">1</container>
          <container type="Folder">3</container>
          <unittitle>Writings</unittitle>
		  <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1944/1956">Undated</unitdate>
        </did>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
