<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead id="nam_apap335">
  <eadheader audience="external" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="##" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/apap335.html">nam_apap335</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>MAURICE HINCHEY PAPERS (APAP335)<date normal="1992/2012" type="inclusive">1992-2012</date></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="2016" type="publication">Copyright 2016 by the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Jodi Boyle<date normal="2016-10-18">2016 October 18</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>Maurice Hinchey Papers<date normal="1992/2012" type="inclusive">1992-2012</date></titleproper>
      <publisher/>
      <date type="publication">Copyright 2016 by the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      <p>For reference queries contact Grenander Department Reference staff or (518)-437-3934</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_apap335</unitid>
      <unittitle>Maurice Hinchey Papers<unitdate label="Date:" normal="1992/2012" type="inclusive">1992-2012</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">This collection documents Maurice Hinchey’s service as a Congressman from New York. </abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcsh">Hinchey, Maurice D.</persname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">194</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage:">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Per the memorandum of agreement governing this collection, all constituent casework files and any materials related to organized crime are closed until January 1, 2043.  Even following this date, no constituent casework files may be photocopied, scanned or duplicated in any way.</p>
      <p>Access to this entire collection, however, is currently restricted because it is unprocessed. Other portions of the collection may also contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
      <p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
      <p>The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Maurice Hinchey and his Congressional office staff.<date normal="2012/2013">2012-2013</date></p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>Maurice Hinchey (born 1938) served in the New York State Assembly from 1975 until 1992 and then in the United States Congress from 1993 until his retirement in 2013.  He first represented the 26th Congressional district of New York and then the 22nd after redistricting.  Both are in the Hudson Valley.  Hinchey is a member of the Democratic Party.

</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>This collection contains official correspondence, Congressional Committee files, leadership files, photographs, awards, subject files, case files, VHS tapes, clippings, and legislative files.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Maurice Hinchey Papers, 1992-2012. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University  Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Hinchey Papers).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <persname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="600">Hinchey, Maurice D.</persname>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Politicians--New York (State)</subject>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Files by subject</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Clippings</genreform>
    </controlaccess>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
