<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" id="apap366">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap366.xml">apap366</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Audrey Seidman; Papers <num>apap366</num></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2016</date>
        </p>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-04-12 15:51:53 -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2016 October 13</date>
        <item>Encoded in EAD by Jodi Boyle</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Audrey Seidman Papers<unitdate normal="1988/1998" type="inclusive">1988-1998</unitdate></unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname source="local">Seidman, Audrey</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>apap366</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.0 cubic ft.</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract id="aspace_34f4ffafbd830d7bfd585b527171e000">This collection documents the activism and interests of Audrey Seidman of Albany, especially her work with Holding Our Own, a foundation dedicated to supporting feminist social justice.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_aab583ae7e2d4fdab4f0cb77e2e632e9">English</langmaterial>
      <physloc id="aspace_38789be8becf5c04cdf8510172009b2b">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <container id="aspace_3346d65ef0501186b33ec264b433a519" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
    </did>
    <processinfo id="aspace_2c70002bdd2c6c2d7b60d8a8e25db011">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed in 2016 by unprocessed.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_bb58bdc821a21e10000594366a777967">
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_243e05ca84315bb973c74630440a9baf">
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
      <p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
      <p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_f7a41b8617a970c99815b1a00702075d">
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Audrey Seidman in <date normal="2016">2016</date>.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_4abc97749fb001ec93df9a162b1ffa35">
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>Originally from New York City, but a longtime resident of Albany, Audrey Seidman worked at the Jewish Board of Family and Children's Services and the Jewish Association for Services for the Aged; the Center for Women in Government, part of the University at Albany, SUNY; and retired from the office of the New York State Comptroller. Seidman has been active in women's and community organizations for decades.</p>
      <p> Seidman holds a MA from the Newhouse School of Communications at Syracuse University and a BA, magna cum laude, from the University at Albany, SUNY.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_d26a22eb50a8137cbe2cb6058016be8d">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>This collection includes materials from the organizations Holding Our Own and the Women's Building. Audrey Seidman served as a board member for Holding Our Own. The collection contains meeting minutes, press releases, correspondence, and special event files.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_dd6d3eef3cef548ab8d753b9788c7566">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite id="aspace_13679b63f0eb6002f6c231ae9875b0d6">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Audrey Seidman Papers, 1988-1998. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Seidman Papers).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Women--New York--Social Conditions</subject>
      <genreform source="aat">Minutes</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Files by subject</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
      <persname source="local">Seidman, Audrey</persname>
      <corpname source="local">Holding Our Own, Inc. (Albany, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc/>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
