<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" id="apap016">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap016.xml">apap016</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Empire Typographical &amp; Mailer Conference, Communications Workers of America; Records <num>apap016</num></titleproper>
        <author>Geoffrey A. Huth</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>1990 May 31</date>
        </p>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-04-14 09:57:55 -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2015 December</date>
        <item>Converted to EAD</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date>2015</date>
        <item>Encoded in EAD by Gregory Wiedeman</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Empire Typographical And Mailer Conference Communications Workers Of America Records<unitdate normal="1919/1990" type="inclusive">1919-1990</unitdate></unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname source="local">Empire Typographical And Mailer Conference,
Communications Workers Of America</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>apap016</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Reels</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract id="aspace_cffec0f53d1e85c2f7fc3eaacd224418">Records of the Empire Typographical and Mailers Conference, CWA, a biannual New York State conference for union printers and mailers.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_8b2292dabfd414561134ea639ef63812">English</langmaterial>
      <physloc id="aspace_16f01cb3fb50ffcac77f83e904ff268b">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    </did>
    <processinfo id="aspace_cf91614de4b9d7afe785d2cfdcec4ad5">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed in 1990 May 31 by Geoffrey A. Huth.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_02b45347d701620de7b72fe246991a8a">
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_337327a8114f67078d561310b147463c">
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites. </p>
      <p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks. </p>
      <p> The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_e51abf446204b9b87d8e951bed0db5d1">
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this manuscript group were lent to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives,by the Empire Typographical and Mailers Conference and subsequently microfilmed as a part of the Harry Van Arsdale, Jr., Labor History Project. The originals have been returned tothe Empire Typographical and Mailers Conference.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_89b55365cf48cff3b87e71d4ed752f44">
      <head>Biographical History</head>
      <p>This Conference was originally organized in 1918 as the Empire Typographical Conference. On August 25, 1918, representatives from eight printers' locals met at Syracuse, New York, to discuss the formation of a New York State Conference for union printers. A month later on September 28, 1918, twelve locals were represented at the first official conference, during which the Conference's constitution was prepared. The objects of the Conference were to improve the employment and wages of union printers, to organize local typographical unions, to provide a forum for printers' unions to discuss common problems, and to promote the ideals of the International Typographical Union in particular and unionism in general.</p>
      <p> In 1972 the Conference changed its name to the Empire Typographcical and Mailer Conference to recognize the contribution of the member mailers' unions. The members of this body hold biannual conferences in the spring and fall. In 1986 the International Typographical Union merged into the Communications Workers of America (CWA), and hence the Empire Typographical and Mailer Conference has been a subordinate to this union. (Shiesley, Stanley E. "History of the Empire Typographical and Mailer Conference." 122nd Semi-Annual Empire Typographical and Mailer Conference, Binghamton, New York, Local 232, October 26, 27, 28, 1979.)</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_7197128ca7d89288b1b724029304e10d">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>The proceedings of the semi-annual conferences (1934, 1938-75) are the most helpful of these records. Each attending local gave a presentation on the state of its affairs, and this information is printed for each conference. However, 1975 was the last year for which the Conference printed its proceedings. Conferences retain their semi-annual schedule, but interest and attendance at the local has been encouraged by ensuring that these are the only ways to learn about what is happening in the state's printers' unions. For the early years of the Conference, the bulletins (1919-20, 1930, 1935-36, 1938) document the activities of the member locals. For the most part, the bulletins give information identical in type to that of the proceedings. The bulletins, however, were designed to be posted in union halls and workplaces so that rank and file members would have easy access to the information. </p>
      <p> There is little information on the Conference since 1975. The only record the conference makes of its activities is in its official calls to conference (1983, 1985-88, 1990). These calls give little information besides the dates and place of conferences, and since 1983 all conferences have been held in Syracuse (a central location in New York State) unless another local makes a bid to host the conference.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_2adca6e57b3d6eb3610b9400bec241d1">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection has no series, arranged chronologically.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite id="aspace_173e25c71a08a5669254a21322013c59">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Empire Typographical And Mailer ConferenceCommunications Workers Of AmericaRecords, 1919-1990. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Empire Typographical and Mailers Conference, CWA Records.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="meg">Labor</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Printing industry -- New York (State)</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Printing industry -- Employees -- Labor unions -- New York (State)</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions -- New York (State)</subject>
      <corpname source="lcsh">Communications Workers of America.</corpname>
      <corpname source="lcsh">International Typographical Union.</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_56bfc4070687b94abcbcf1a91dc62f36" level="otherlevel">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Bulletin</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1919/1920" type="inclusive">1919-1920</unitdate>
          <unitdate normal="1930/1930" type="inclusive">1930</unitdate>
          <unitdate normal="1935/1936" type="inclusive">1935-1936</unitdate>
          <unitdate normal="1938/1938" type="inclusive">1938</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_a931fc8b03208934ca44ad2a344ec8ed" label="Mixed Materials" type="Reel">1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_01ced977e8e3736cb246ba45bd459ddc" level="otherlevel">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Newspaper Clippings</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1929/1933" type="inclusive">1929-1933</unitdate>
          <unitdate normal="1937/1937" type="inclusive">1937</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_786c5538ef964b72745d22fbb71536a8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Reel">1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_cd6004fe911f7ff28fa0c4f3a8ab2693" level="otherlevel">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Official Calls for Conferences</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1983/1983" type="inclusive">1983</unitdate>
          <unitdate normal="1985/1988" type="inclusive">1985-1988</unitdate>
          <unitdate normal="1990/1990" type="inclusive">1990</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_ed93140cb5a5b0f2eda56fb3b930f893" label="Mixed Materials" type="Reel">1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_f4cda5bc114b96c43f7e9c4932ec0b82" level="otherlevel">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Proceedings</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1934/1934" type="inclusive">1934</unitdate>
          <unitdate normal="1938/1947" type="inclusive">1938-1947</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_8cf479febbff68bf045db56ead3f4361" label="Mixed Materials" type="Reel">1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_a1cfea34eb204d1544eb8d95ed1edc6e" level="otherlevel">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Proceedings</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1948/1960" type="inclusive">1948-1960</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_f9458802d96f7fa95484cf687f5111c1" label="Mixed Materials" type="Reel">1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_e9b26c36ac6767b023d5c05fc82e28e2" level="otherlevel">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Proceedings</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1961/1966" type="inclusive">1961-1966</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_20beaaf0a57fc27b5294658ee87e91de" label="Mixed Materials" type="Reel">1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_7ae0ee23bf5986f1083ad12a69d535ad" level="otherlevel">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Proceedings</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1967/1972" type="inclusive">1967-1972</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_53deb69cdaa90a0544994f1425b6f639" label="Mixed Materials" type="Reel">1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_82aa13a3adbfdb12664d603aa88c3701" level="otherlevel">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Proceedings</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1972/1975" type="inclusive">1972-1975</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_816b29c729f6fa6b645bcc2270f55fec" label="Mixed Materials" type="Reel">1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_c17d88a62a151e765563ef5d759168b8" level="otherlevel">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Program for Conference</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1970/1970" type="inclusive">1970</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_dabc7b698b56ef9bc553c68c9d3f6ab2" label="Mixed Materials" type="Reel">1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
