<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE ead SYSTEM 'ead.dtd'>
<ead id="nam_apap346">
  <eadheader audience="external" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="##" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/apap346.html">nam_apap346</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>EUGENE G. WANGER AND MARILYN M. WANGER DEATH PENALTY COLLECTION (APAP346)<date normal="1754/2015" type="inclusive">1754-2015</date></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="2016" type="publication">Copyright 2016 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All
          rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives<date normal="2016-04-20">2016 April 20</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>Eugene G. Wanger and Marilyn M. Wanger Death Penalty Collection<date normal="1754/2015" type="inclusive">1754-2015</date></titleproper>
      <publisher/>
      <date type="publication">Copyright 2016 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights
        reserved.</date>
      <p>For reference queries contact Grenander Department Reference staff or (518)-437-3934</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_apap346</unitid>
      <unittitle>Eugene G. Wanger and Marilyn M. Wanger Death Penalty Collection<unitdate label="Date:" normal="1754/2015" type="inclusive">1754-2015</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">Over the course of 50 years, Eugene G. Wanger created or collected
        the materials about capital punishment that comprise the Eugene G. Wanger and Marilyn M.
        Wanger Death Penalty Collection. The collection includes a wide range of materials on the
        death penalty documenting its history, efforts to abolish or reinstate the practice, its
        psychological impact, compatibility on religious, moral or ethical grounds, and its
        operation.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcsh">Wanger, Eugene G.</persname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">147.2</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage:">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special
          Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>The collection is open for use by qualified and responsible researchers.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from the collection
        without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some
        materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.)
        and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about
        U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted
        by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy
        and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander
        Department of Special Collections and Archives by Eugene G. Wanger in installments<date normal="2014/2016">2014-2016</date>.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Biographical Note</head>
      <p>A graduate of Amherst College and The University of Michigan Law School, Eugene G. Wanger
        returned home to Lansing, Michigan to practice law after obtaining his degree. In 1961-1962
        fellow voters from Lansing elected him the youngest delegate from his political party to
        Michigan’s Constitutional Convention where, among other provisions, he authored the section
        of the state constitution which bans capital punishment. Mr. Wanger later served as
        Lansing's City Attorney and chairman of Ingham County's Board of Commissioners.</p>
      <p>Beginning in 1972, Mr. Wanger has co-chaired the Michigan Committee Against Capital
        Punishment, co-founded the Michigan Committee Against the Death Penalty, and been active in
        numerous historical organizations. In 2005, he received the Champion of Justice Award from
        the State Bar of Michigan for superior professional accomplishments benefiting the state
        and nation, including his work on capital punishment.</p>
      <p>Marilyn G. Wanger, born Marilyn Morris in Mason, Michigan, is a graduate of Michigan State
        University and The University of Michigan Law School where she met Mr. Wanger. During her
        professional career, she served as a Michigan Assistant Attorney General and then as a
        Commissioner of Michigan's Court of Appeals. </p>
      <p>Married for more than 50 years, Eugene and Marilyn Wanger continue to reside in Lansing,
        Michigan.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>The Eugene G. Wanger and Marilyn M. Wanger Death Penalty Collection contains a wide variety
        of materials that document the history and debate about capital punishment as well as
        discuss the criminal justice system surrounding it. The collection includes books, artifacts
        and ephemera, pamphlets, audio and video, prints, posters, buttons, reports, testimony,
        correspondence, files by subject, advocacy materials, and clippings. Mr. Wanger created or
        collected the materials himself. </p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection was arranged by the donor.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Eugene G. Wanger and Marilyn M.
        Wanger Death Penalty Collection, 1754-2015. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections
        and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York
        (hereafter referred to as the Eugene G. Wanger and Marilyn M. Wanger Death Penalty
        Collection).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <persname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="600">Wanger, Eugene G.</persname>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Capital punishment--political aspects--United
        States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Capital punishment--social aspects--United
        States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Executions and executioners--United
        States</subject>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Pamphlets</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Clippings</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Printed ephemera</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Books</genreform>
    </controlaccess>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
