<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead id="nam_apap331">
  <eadheader audience="external" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="##" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/apap331.html">nam_apap331</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>THE NEW YORK CIVIL LIBERTIES UNION RECORDS (APAP331)<date normal="1951/1995" type="inclusive">1951-1995</date></titleproper>
        <author>partially processed</author>
        <sponsor>The arrangement and description of this collection was partially made possible through New York State Archives Documentary Heritage Program Arrangement and Description Grants.</sponsor>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="2016" type="publication">Copyright 2016 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Melissa McMullen<date normal="2016-07-14">2016 July 14</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>The New York Civil Liberties Union Records<date normal="1951/1995" type="inclusive">1951-1995</date></titleproper>
      <publisher/>
      <date type="publication">Copyright 2016 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      <p>For reference queries contact Grenander Department Reference staff or (518)-437-3934</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_apap331</unitid>
      <unittitle>The New York Civil Liberties Union Records<unitdate label="Date:" normal="1951/1995" type="inclusive">1951-1995</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">The New York Civil Liberties Union (NYCLU) is the preeminent statewide organization dedicated to the protection and enhancement of individual civil liberties and civil rights in New York State. Founded in 1951, the NYCLU’s mission is to defend and uphold the basic rights and liberties articulated in the Bill of Rights and to advocate, litigate and educate for the protection of civil liberties. Through litigation, legal counsel, advocacy and legislative lobbying, the NYCLU has, among many issues, protected political freedom during the McCarthy era, argued against the constitutionality of the Vietnam War, created the first project focused on the rights of mentally disabled, and was the first civil liberties organization to advocate for reforming the foster care placement system. Over the last thirty years, the NYCLU has advocated for issues surrounding voting rights and censorship, fought to end gender discrimination and school segregation in New York State schools, and defended the separation of church and state. The collection consists of legal case files, administrative records and other archival materials. The collection is being processed and is currently closed, unless permission to access is granted in writing from the NYCLU Executive Director.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <corpname encodinganalog="110" source="lcsh">New York Civil Liberties Union</corpname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">700</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage:">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <phystech>
      <p>Web Archives</p>
    </phystech>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information. Certain restrictions may apply.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
      <p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
      <p>The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.<date normal="2013">2013</date></p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>The New York Civil Liberties Union (NYCLU) was founded in November 1951 as the New York affiliate of the American Civil Liberties Union, it is not-for-profit, nonpartisan organization with nearly 50,000 members across New York State. The stated mission of the organization is defend and promote New Yorkers’ unalienable rights, including freedom of speech and religion, and the right to privacy, equality and due process of law. NYCLU performs its work through litigation, advocacy, community organizing, and public education.</p>
      <p>The NYCLU has eight chapters in New York State: Central New York, the Capital Region, Lower Hudson Valley, Suffolk County, Nassau County, New York City, Genesee Valley and the Western Region. The New York City office is the organization’s headquarters and represents all regions that do not have their own local chapter or regional office.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>This collection predominantly consists of the thousands of legal case files the NYCLU partook in. The legal case files series spans from freedom of speech, religion, press, petition, and assembly, to privacy, to equality before and due process of law. The legal cases show the expansive service the NYCLU performs for underrepresented groups and person of New York State.</p>
      <p>The Executive Director files contain the material of past Executive Directors, the NYCLU Board, including board meeting minutes, and chapter news. The legislative Committee series tracks the work of the NYCLU and their impact advocating for New Yorkers through reform. In 1970, a campaign led by the NYCLU's legislative office lead to the repeal of a state law that imposes criminal sanctions for the performance of medical abortions.</p>
      <p>The advocacy series represents the tireless work to promote the issues of New Yorkers including, military and selective service, reproductive rights, LBGT rights, racial justice, immigrants’ rights, rights of people with disabilities, voting rights, youth and student rights, and women and equality. Subject Files show the day to day aspects of the NYCLU and include memorandum of staff attorneys. As well as general subject based materials.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is partially processed. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, The New York Civil Liberties Union Records, 1951-1995. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University  Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the The New York Civil Liberties Union Records).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <subject source="meg" encodinganalog="650">Social Activists and Public Advocates</subject>
      <persname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="600">Glasser, Ira</persname>
      <persname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="600">Neier, Aryeh, 1937-</persname>
      <corpname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="610">American Civil Liberties Union</corpname>
      <corpname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="610">New York Civil Liberties Union</corpname>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Civil rights</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Legal briefs</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">New York (State). Court of Appeals</subject>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Law (discipline)</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Legal Files</genreform>
      <genreform source="meg" encodinganalog="655">Web Archives</genreform>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <head>Container List</head>
      <c01 level="series" id="nam_apap331-1">
        <did>
          <unitid>1</unitid>
          <unittitle label="Series">Web Archives</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1998-12-05/2016-08-30">1998 December 5-2016 August 30</unitdate>
          <physdesc>
            <extent unit="captures">904</extent>
          </physdesc>
        </did>
        <acqinfo>
          <p>Web crawling is managed through the Internet Archive's Archive-It service. This page includes links to both the university's collection and the Internet Archive's public collection.</p>
          <p>The following seeds are crawled monthly: www.nyclu.org, www.facebook.com/NYCLU, www.twitter.com/NYCLU, and en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_York_Civil_Liberties_Union. The domains en.wikipedia.org, twitter.com, and upload.wikimedia.org are subjected to a 1,000 document limit.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <phystech>
          <p>Web Archives</p>
        </phystech>
        <c02 id="nam_apap331-1_1">
          <did>
            <container type="Web-Archive">1</container>
            <unittitle>http://www.nyclu.org/ - University Archives collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2016-05-26/2016-08-30">2016 May 26-2016 August 30</unitdate>
            <dao actuate="onrequest" linktype="simple" show="new" href="http://wayback.archive-it.org/7081/*/http://www.nyclu.org/"/>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="nam_apap331-1_2">
          <did>
            <container type="WARC">1</container>
            <unittitle>WARC file for http://www.nyclu.org/, (please see https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_ARChive for more details)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2016-05-26/2016-08-30">2016 May 26-2016 August 30</unitdate>
          </did>
          <accessrestrict>
            <p>WARC files are very large and difficult to work with. Your request may take time to process, and we may be unable to deliver your request remotely. Please consult an archivist if you are interested in researching with web archives.</p>
          </accessrestrict>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="nam_apap331-1_3">
          <did>
            <container type="Web-Archive">2</container>
            <unittitle>http://www.nyclu.org/ - Internet Archive collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1998-12-05/2016-08-30">1998 December 5-2016 August 30</unitdate>
            <dao actuate="onrequest" linktype="simple" show="new" href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.nyclu.org/"/>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series" id="nam_apap331-2">
        <did>
          <unitid>2</unitid>
          <unittitle label="Series">Legal Case Files</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1951/1995">1951-1995</unitdate>
          <physdesc>
            <extent unit="cubic ft.">500</extent>
          </physdesc>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
          <p>Certain Restrictions May Apply.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>The legal case files series spans from freedom of speech, religion, press, petition, and assembly, to privacy, to equality before and due process of law. The legal cases show the expansive service the NYCLU performs for underrepresented groups and person of New York State.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement>
          <p>Arranged Alphabetically.</p>
        </arrangement>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series" id="nam_apap331-3">
        <did>
          <unitid>3</unitid>
          <unittitle label="Series">Executive Director</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1951/1995">1951-1995</unitdate>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
          <p>Certain Restrictions May Apply.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>The Executive Director files contain the material of past Executive Directors, the NYCLU Board, including board meeting minutes, and chapter news.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement>
          <p>Arranged Chronologically.</p>
        </arrangement>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series" id="nam_apap331-4">
        <did>
          <unitid>4</unitid>
          <unittitle label="Series">Legislative Committee</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1951/1995">1951-1995</unitdate>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
          <p>Certain Restrictions May Apply.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>The legislative Committee series tracks the work of the NYCLU and their impact advocating for New Yorkers through reform. In 1970, a campaign led by the NYCLU's legislative office lead to the repeal of a state law that imposes criminal sanctions for the performance of medical abortions.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement>
          <p>Arranged Chronologically.</p>
        </arrangement>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series" id="nam_apap331-5">
        <did>
          <unitid>5</unitid>
          <unittitle label="Series">Advocacy</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1951/1995">1951-1995</unitdate>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
          <p>Certain Restrictions May Apply.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series" id="nam_apap331-6">
        <did>
          <unitid>6</unitid>
          <unittitle label="Series">Subject Files</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1951/1995">1951-1995</unitdate>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
          <p>Certain Restrictions May Apply.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
