<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead id="nam_apap296">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="apap014" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/apap296.html">nam_apap296</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>SHERWOOD BOEHLERT PAPERS (APAP296)<date normal="1980-2006" type="inclusive">1980-2006</date></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="2015" type="publication">Copyright 2015 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation audience="internal">Jodi Boyle<date normal="2015">2015</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date normal="2014">2014</date>
        <item>EAD file created</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_apap296</unitid>
      <unittitle>Sherwood Boehlert Papers<unitdate normal="1980-2006" type="inclusive">1980-2006</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">This collection contains materials from Sherwood Boehlert's service in the United States Congress from the State of New York.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcsh">Boehlert, Sherwood L. (Sherwood Louis), 1936-</persname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">656</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage: ">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="meg" encodinganalog="650">Politics and Politicians</subject>
    </controlaccess>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Biographical History</head>
      <p>Sherwood Boehlert retired in 2006, after serving in the U.S. Congress (NY-24th District) since first elected in 1982. Among Congressman Boehlert's many achievements was his chairmanship of the House Science Committee; he also served on committees on Transportation and Infrastructure. By appointment of the Speaker of the House, Congressman Boehlert served for eight years as a member of the Select Committee on Intelligence, where he was on the front line of important intelligence decisions faced by Congress. Early in 2003, the Speaker appointed Boehlert to serve on the newly created Select Committee on Homeland Security. In addition to being a leader on science issues, Boehlert's legislative experience and seniority made him one of the most influential Members of Congress. National Journal featured him as one of a dozen "key players" in the House. Time Magazine highlighted Congressman Boehlert as a power center on Capitol Hill. Congressional Quarterly regularly named Boehlert one of the 50 most effective lawmakers in Washington.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>This collection contains materials from Sherwood Boehlert's service in the United States Congress from the State of New York.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement>
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <chronlist>
        <chronitem>
          <date normal="2006">2006</date>
          <event>Sherwood Boehlert donated the majority of his collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives.</event>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date normal="2014">2014</date>
          <event>Sherwood Boehlert donated a much smaller amount of additional files.</event>
        </chronitem>
      </chronlist>
    </acqinfo>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Sherwood Boehlert Papers, 1980-2006. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Boehlert Papers).</p>
    </prefercite>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
