<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" id="apap347">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=apap347.xml">apap347</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Ainsworth, Steven King; Papers <num>apap347</num></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2015</date>
        </p>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-04-14 11:50:55 -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2014</date>
        <item>EAD file created</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date>2015</date>
        <item>Encoded in EAD by Jodi Boyle</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Steven King Ainsworth Papers<unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013</unitdate></unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname source="local">Ainsworth, Steven King</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>apap347</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.1 cubic ft.</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract id="aspace_9af8009f615166b76ea24c7f0fe6d5c6">The Steven King Ainsworth Papers contain "Heads Up" bulletins written by Ainsworth for prison inmates sentenced to life, life without parole, and their advocates.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_b1ceb5c48cb2270bfd458c6f0e758538">English</langmaterial>
      <physloc id="aspace_db904a35b906f82c2e9c4603ca69f388">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <container id="aspace_711ccc9ef40379c034bf11bdcb1129ad" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
    </did>
    <processinfo id="aspace_bee800c9a190d6ce9cf321d9ed03bbcb">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed in 2015 by unprocessed.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_9a28973562b5c54603720e7d8c78c84d">
      <head>Biographical History</head>
      <p>Steven King Ainsworth, currently incarcerated in California, was previously sentenced to death and served two decades on Death Row in San Quentin. In 2001 the United States District Court for the Eastern District of California granted Ainsworth's habeas corpus petition vacating his capital sentence. Ainsworth is a published writer of fiction and non-fiction, and a self-taught artist whose work has been exhibited in the United States and internationally. His many publications include Words from the Row and essays or short stories in Undoing Time: American Prisoners in Their Own Words (2001), Writing for Their Lives: Death Row U.S.A. (2007), and Fourth City: Essays from the Prison in America (2014).</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_7bef3ff52b7a8e627d3012c5fd0229bf">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>The Steven King Ainsworth Papers contain "Heads Up" bulletins written by Ainsworth for prison inmates sentenced to life, life without parole, and their advocates. The bulletins contain advice for and background information about petitioning the Governors Office for clemency in the State of California, as well as news clippings of interest.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_a267c496c55e2aa0b16ada184749120a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_1cfd2ff0d5663c38d1bd98f1d6c57328">
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>Steven King Ainsworth donated his papers to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives.<date normal="2014">2014</date></p>
    </acqinfo>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_839825abafe10893d73a6a3350d727ea">
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_960d0c5f5a66826b0881cb3a574dfb56">
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_a1b6324f32dd7b9d589855e939ced3aa">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Steven King Ainsworth Papers, 2013. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Ainsworth Papers).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="meg">Criminal Justice and Prisons</subject>
      <subject source="meg">Death Penalty</subject>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc/>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
