<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead id="nam_apap092">
  <eadheader audience="external" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="DC">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/apap092.xml" identifier="##">nam_apap092</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>ARCHIBALD C. WEMPLE SCRAPBOOK (APAP092)<date normal="1950/1951" type="inclusive">1950-1951</date></titleproper>
        <author>Amy C. Schindler</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date type="publication" normal="2005">Copyright 2005 by the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Chad Lowther<date normal="2014">2014</date>
      </creation>
      <langusage>
        <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="Language">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>ARCHIBALD C. WEMPLE SCRAPBOOK (APAP092)<date normal="1950/1951" type="inclusive">1950-1951</date></titleproper>
      <publisher> M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
      <date type="publication">2005</date>
      <p>For reference queries contact Grenander Department Reference staff or (518)-437-3934</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_apap092</unitid>
      <unittitle>Archibald C. Wemple Scrapbook<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1950/1951" label="Date:"> 1950-1951</unitdate></unittitle>
      <origination>
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="local">Wemple, Archibald C. </persname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">0.33</extent>
        <physfacet>processed to date</physfacet>
      </physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">Archibald C. Wemple scrapbooked his winning campaign for the office of Mayor of Schenctady, NY.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <physloc label="Storage:">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access</head>
      <p> Access to this record group is unrestricted with the exception of one folder, which is
        marked. </p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright.
        Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will
        provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal
        determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish
        material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and
        Archives. </p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>The Archibald C. Wemple Estate donated all of the materials in this collection to the M.E.
        Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in March 2005. </p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
      <p>Archibald C. Wemple campaigned and won the race for mayor of Schenectady, New York in 1951 as the Republican candidate over the incumbent Owen M. Begley. Wemple served as mayor from 1952 through 1955. Wemple was an attorney and past president of the Schenectady Chamber of Commerce at the time of his election. Wemple was originally entered in the Republican primary race for city court judge, but withdrew from that race to accept the party's endorsement for mayor. At the time Wemple said that withdrawing from the city court campaign meant "sacrificing my person ambitions and dreams of becoming city judge, but I'm willing to throw them out the window for the Republican party." This quote was taken from the article, "Executive Group Approves Archibald C. Wemple As GOP Candidate for Mayor," published in the Schenectady Daily Gazette 12 July 1951. A complete list of officials of the City of Schenectady from 1798 to the present is available from the Schenectady County Historical Society at http://www.schenectadyhistory.org/schenectady/officials.html </p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>The scrapbook was kept by Archibald C. Wemple as the successful Republican candidate for mayor of Schenectady, New York in 1951. In addition to news clippings, the scrapbook includes typescript speeches, notes on platform planks, a campaign letter, and election statistics. The scrapbook was preservation photocopied in 2003 due to the condition of original items in the scrapbook.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection has no series and contains one scrapbook.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <subject source="meg" encodinganalog="650">Schenectady, New York</subject>
      <subject source="meg" encodinganalog="650">Public Servants </subject>
      <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">Archibald C. Wemple Scrapbook</corpname>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
    </controlaccess>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Archibald C. Wemple Scrapbook,  1950-1951. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as [shortened name]).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>Container List</head>
      <c01 id="nam_apap092-1">
        <did>
          <container type="Box">1</container>
          <container type="Folder">1</container>
          <unittitle>Scrapbook, 1950-1951</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1950/1951">1950-1951</unitdate>
        </did>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
