<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead id="nam_apap319">
  <eadheader audience="external" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="##" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/apap319.html">nam_apap319</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>SANDY GALEF (APAP319)<date normal="1991/2009" type="inclusive">1991-2009</date></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="2016" type="publication">Copyright 2016 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Brian Keough<date normal="2016-12-23">2016 December 23</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>Sandy Galef<date normal="1991/2009" type="inclusive">1991-2009</date></titleproper>
      <publisher/>
      <date type="publication">Copyright 2016 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      <p>For reference queries contact Grenander Department Reference staff or (518)-437-3934</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_apap319</unitid>
      <unittitle>Sandy Galef<unitdate label="Date:" normal="1991/2009" type="inclusive">1991-2009</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">This collection contains the papers of Sandy Galef, New York State Assemblywoman.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="local">Galef, Sandy</persname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">36</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage:">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. The constituent case files will be closed for 30 years after leaving office.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
      <p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
      <p>The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archivesin 2010.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>Sandy Galef is assemblywoman for the 90th district in the New York State Assembly. A Democrat, Galef first won election to the Assembly in 1992 and represents portions of Westchester and Putnam counties, including the towns of Kent, Philipstown, Putnam Valley, Ossining, Cortlandt, and the city of Peekskill. Galef has served on many Assembly committees including Real Property Tax (chair), Corporations, Authorities, and Commissions, Election Law, Governmental Operations, and Health. Born in Wisconsin in 1940, Galef moved to Westchester in 1944 and later received her Bachelor of Arts degree from Purdue University and a Masters in Education from the University of Virginia. She taught school in both Virginia and New York and then held several volunteer leadership positions in Westchester while raising her family. Prior to her election to the Assembly, Galef was a Westchester County Legislator for thirteen years. </p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>This collection contains the Assemblywoman Galef's subject files with materials dating from 1991-2009, including correspondence, news releases, clippingss, reports, and background materials.  Per the memorandum of agreement, this collection will be closed for a period of five years after the donor leaves office. </p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Sandy Galef, 1991-2009. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University  Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Sandy Galef).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <subject source="meg" encodinganalog="650">Public Servants </subject>
      <subject source="meg" encodinganalog="650">Politics and Politicians</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Politcian</subject>
    </controlaccess>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
