<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='collection-level.xsl'?> 
<!DOCTYPE ead SYSTEM 'ead.dtd'>
<ead id="nam_apap357">
  <eadheader audience="external" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="##" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/apap357.html">nam_apap357</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>THE LEGISLATIVE CORRESPONDENTS' ASSOCIATION OF THE STATE OF NEW YORK RECORDS (APAP357)<date normal="1915/2012" type="inclusive">1915-2012</date></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="2016" type="publication">Copyright 2016 by the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Jodi Boyle<date normal="2016-10-13">2016 October 13</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>The Legislative Correspondents' Association of the State of New York Records<date normal="1915/2012" type="inclusive">1915-2012</date></titleproper>
      <publisher/>
      <date type="publication">Copyright 2016 by the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      <p>For reference queries contact Grenander Department Reference staff or (518)-437-3934</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_apap357</unitid>
      <unittitle>The Legislative Correspondents' Association of the State of New York Records<unitdate label="Date:" normal="1915/2012" type="inclusive">1915-2012</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">This collection contains materials about The Legislative Correspondents' Association of the State of New York, especially its celebrated annual dinner held since 1900. </abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <corpname encodinganalog="110" source="lcsh">Legislative Correspondents' Association of the State of New York</corpname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">21.25</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage:">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict><head>Access</head><p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p><p>Red asterisks (***) denote restricted items.</p></accessrestrict>
    <userestrict><head>Copyright</head><p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p></userestrict>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>Current and former members of The Legislative Correspondents Association of New York State Susan Arbetter, Kyle Hughes, and Ron Kermani donated the materials in this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives in <date normal="2015/2016">2015-2016</date>.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>The Legislative Correspondents' Association of the State of New York (LCA) is composed of journalists covering the State Capitol in Albany.  Since 1900 the LCA has held an annual dinner in which it pokes fun at New York politics and politicians.  </p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>The collection includes administrative and financial records, correspondence, photographs, slides, and member files from The Legislative Correspondents' Association of the State of New York (LCA).  The majority of the collection, however, consists of materials from the LCA's annual dinner and show, including invitations, tickets, seating charts, programs, scripts, video, audio, film, and songs.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, The Legislative Correspondents' Association of the State of New York Records, 1915-2012. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University  Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the The Legislative Correspondents' Association of the State of New York Records).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <corpname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="610">Legislative Correspondents' Association of the State of New York</corpname>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Legislative reporting--New York (State)</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Journalists--New York (State)</subject>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Photographs</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Souvenir programs</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Admission tickets</genreform>
      <persname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="600">VHS</persname>
    </controlaccess>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
