<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='collection-level.xsl'?> 
<!DOCTYPE ead SYSTEM 'ead.dtd'>
<ead id="nam_apap355">
  <eadheader audience="external" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="##" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/apap355.html">nam_apap355</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>MARGARET VANDIVER PAPERS (APAP355)<date normal="1983/2012" type="inclusive">1983-2012</date></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="2016" type="publication">Copyright 2016 by the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Jodi Boyle<date normal="2016-10-13">2016 October 13</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>Margaret Vandiver Papers<date normal="1983/2012" type="inclusive">1983-2012</date></titleproper>
      <publisher/>
      <date type="publication">Copyright 2016 by the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      <p>For reference queries contact Grenander Department Reference staff or (518)-437-3934</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_apap355</unitid>
      <unittitle>Margaret Vandiver Papers<unitdate label="Date:" normal="1983/2012" type="inclusive">1983-2012</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">The Margaret Vandiver Papers document Dr. Vandiver's research in capital punishment, involvement with abolitionist organizations, and work with individuals sentenced to death.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcsh">Vandiver, Margaret</persname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">15</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage:">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict><head>Access</head><p>Per the memorandum of agreement governing this collection, all correspondence in this collection is closed for no shorter than 75 years from the date a letter was written.  No correspondence may be photocopied, scanned or duplicated in any way.  All case files are closed for no shorter than 50 years from the date of donation. No materials in the case files may be photocopied, scanned or duplicated in any way.  Access to this entire collection is currently restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection, other than the correspondence and case files, may also contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that these other portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist. </p> <p>Red asterisks (***) denote restricted items.</p></accessrestrict>
    <userestrict><head>Copyright</head><p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p></userestrict>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Margaret Vandiver in <date normal="2015">2015</date>.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>Dr. Margaret Vandiver is retired from the Department of Criminology and Criminal Justice at the University of Memphis.  Dr. Vandiver's main area of research interest is state and collective violence, ranging from the use of the death penalty in the United States to contemporary instances of genocide. She is the author of Lethal Punishment: Lynchings and Legal Executions in the South (2006), co-author with Michael Radelet of Capital punishment in America: an annotated bibliography (1988), and co-editor of Tennessee's New Abolitionists (2010), in addition to numerous articles.  In retirement, she continues to speak and research historical homicides and death penalty cases.  </p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>This collection contains subject files, case files, correspondence, and clippings created or collected by Margaret Vandiver about the death penalty.  Many files relate to specific cases or organizations.  </p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Margaret Vandiver Papers, 1983-2012. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University  Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Vandiver Papers).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <persname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="600">Vandiver, Margaret</persname>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Capital punishment -- United States</subject>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Files by subject</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Case files</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Clippings</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Correspondence</genreform>
    </controlaccess>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
