<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='collection-level.xsl'?> 
<!DOCTYPE ead SYSTEM 'ead.dtd'>
<ead id="nam_apap369">
  <eadheader audience="external" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="##" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/369.html">nam_apap369</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>KARLI KEATOR PAPERS (APAP369)<date normal="2001/2006" type="inclusive">2001-2006</date></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="2017" type="publication">Copyright 2017 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Jodi Boyle<date normal="2017-04-04">2017 April 4</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>Karli Keator Papers<date normal="2001/2006" type="inclusive">2001-2006</date></titleproper>
      <publisher/>
      <date type="publication">Copyright 2017 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      <p>For reference queries contact Grenander Department Reference staff or (518)-437-3934</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_apap369</unitid>
      <unittitle>Karli Keator Papers<unitdate label="Date:" normal="2001/2006" type="inclusive">2001-2006</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">Convicted of a 2000 murder in Texas and setenced to death, Deon Tumblin committed suicide in his cell in 2004.  This collection contains research materials about the Tumblin case, compiled by then graduate student Karli Keator.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="local">Keator, Karli</persname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">1.0</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage:">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict>
		<head>Access</head>
		<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>
	</accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
		<head>Copyright</head>
		<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
		<p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
		<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
		<p>The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
	</userestrict>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Karli Keator in<date normal="2017-02">2017 February</date></p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist>
		<head>Historical Note</head>
		<p>Deon Tumblin (1976-2004) was convicted of the February 2000 strangulation and beating death of a 75-year-old Texarkana woman.  He was sentenced to death and was a prisoner on Texas' Death Row since 2001.  In November 2004, Tumblin hanged himself in his cell with a sheet.</p>
		<p>Beginning in 2005, then Sage Graduate School student Karli Keator embarked on a project entitled "Deon Tumblin: A Case Study."  As part of this effort she traveled to Texas to conduct research and collected materials related to Tumblin's life and legal case.</p>
		<p>Keator is now director of the National Center for Mental Health and Juvenile Justice and program area director at Policy Research Associates for children’s behavioral health policy, trauma, and juvenile justice initiatives.</p>
	</bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>This collection is composed of copies of materials about the Deon Tumblin case that Sage Graduate School student Karli Keator collected and analyzed for a project entitled "Deon Tumblin: A Case Study."  It includes clippings, legal materials, and a presentation by Karli Keator.
</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Karli Keator Papers, 2001-2006. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University  Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Karli Keator Papers).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <persname source="local" encodinganalog="600">Keator, Karli</persname>
      <persname source="local" encodinganalog="600">Tumblin, Deon, 1976-2004</persname>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Capital punishment--Texas</subject>
      <persname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="600">Death row--Texas</persname>
    </controlaccess>
  </archdesc>
</ead>