<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" id="ger010">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ger010.xml">ger010</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Padover, Saul K.; Papers <num>ger010</num></titleproper>
        <author>Bonita L. Weddle</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>1999 October</date>
        </p>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-04-12 15:56:59 -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2015 December</date>
        <item>Converted to EAD</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date>2015</date>
        <item>Encoded in EAD by Gregory Wiedeman</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Saul K. Padover Papers<unitdate normal="1947/1972" type="inclusive">1947-1972</unitdate></unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname source="lcsh">Padover, Saul Kussiel, 1905-1981</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>ger010</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.2 cubic ft.</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract id="aspace_4b927db27f5a9713b556c0c4462a08f5">Austrian-American political scientist and scholar of Soviet propaganda and American foreign policy, professor at the New School for Social Research.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_a4bd6be6593d4a8ab9abdeb81fded23c">English</langmaterial>
      <physloc id="aspace_9ffcbe8e59af03e416a96d0da54293c1">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    </did>
    <processinfo id="aspace_5463a10dfed2ea220a5862e76a9c75f3">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed in 1999 October by Bonita L. Weddle.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_d5a61cd77bb32b12050346eec6e16b7a">
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_4ac88dc6f636c35a0775b1b2ff8ca83e">
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites. </p>
      <p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks. </p>
      <p> The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_a8cebac65e798674abe27395a5b1b13f">
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>The documents in this collection were originally housed in a folder inserted into the files of the American Council for migrs in the Professions (ACEP), which the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives photocopied for preservation purposes in 1974. This folder was evidently the creation and personal property of Saul K. Padover and was thus separated from the ACEP collection.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_bb4a90e002dd1eaf979ba9ad182a22a3">
      <head>Biographical History</head>
      <p>Saul Kussiel Padover was born in Vienna, Austria, on April 13, 1905. At the age of fifteen, he came to the United States with his father Keva Padover, an American citizen, and mother Frumet Goldmann Padover. He received an A.B. from Wayne State University in Detroit in 1928. He took graduate courses at Yale University in 1928-1929 and went on to receive an A.M. (1930) and Ph.D. (1932) in history from the University of Chicago. After taking research positions at the University of Chicago (1932) and the University of California (1933-36), he worked at a number of posts in the U.S. Department of the Interior (1938-1944). He then served as a London-based political analyst for the Federal Communications Commission (1944) and as an intelligence officer for the Office of Strategic Services (1944) and the U.S. Army (1944-1946). After working as an editorial writer (1946-48) for PM, a left-leaning and short-lived New York City newspaper, he joined the Graduate Faculty of the New School for Social Research (1949) and taught political science. He remained an active member of the faculty until his death in 1981. </p>
      <p> Padover wrote or edited books about many eminent American and European political figures, among them Alexander Hamilton, Thomas Jefferson, Joseph II of Austria, Louis XVI of France, James Madison, and Karl Marx. He also wrote several books about twentieth-century American and European politics, a memoir of his experiences as an intelligence officer, and several works on foreign policy. A liberal anti-communist, he asserted in the 1950s that the Soviet Union was a serious threat and should be treated as such. </p>
      <p> Toward the end of his life, Padover contemplated writing a book about the American Council for migrs in the Professions (ACEP), an organization established to help refugees fleeing Nazi Germany and Austria. To that end, Padover secured physical possession of the ACEP files and housed them in his New School office. Padover passed away on February 22, 1981, in New York City, before he could complete this project.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_930449c7a02e9fa437b1387f4b731807">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>The materials in this collection were originally housed in a folder labeled "Foreign Affairs" that was inadvertently inserted into the files of the American Council for migrs in the Professions (ACEP), which were sent to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 1974. Saul Kussiel Padover, who kept the ACEP files in his office at the New School for Social Research, apparently created and misfiled this folder. The ACEP files were sent to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, which photocopied them for preservation purposes. The M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, which sent the ACEP files to the Immigration History Research Center at the University of Minnesota after photocopying, retained possession of Padover's "Foreign Affairs" folder. </p>
      <p> Owing to its origins, this collection is limited in scope. Scholars seeking information about Padover's early life, his work as a journalist, or his writings on Alexander Hamilton, Thomas Jefferson, Karl Marx, and other political figures will find little of interest in it. However, those searching for materials that illuminate his attitude toward the Soviet Union and the Cold War and that document his work as a faculty member of the New School for Social Research will find it useful. </p>
      <p> The collection contains seven typescript scholarly articles and two typescript fragments of longer articles. Eight were written in the fifteen years following the end of the Second World War. The ninth may have been written circa 1970; however, it may have been written in the 1950s and revised in 1964, 1970, and 1972. These articles document Padover's staunch anti-communist views and his interest in the relationship between American public opinion and American foreign policy. Several articles also discuss some of his work as an intelligence officer during the Second World War. </p>
      <p> The collection also contains syllabi, student-written presentation outlines, and lecture notes that were generated between 1955 and 1970 and shed light upon Padover's work in the classroom. Materials that Padover prepared while leading the General Seminar, the New School's ongoing interdisciplinary seminar for faculty members, help to document his own activities and the workings of the General Seminar itself. </p>
      <p> Other materials in the collection consist of assorted documents that Padover found relevant to his academic work. Of particular note is a May 3, 1972 circular letter from New School President John R. Everett concerning student protests against the Vietnam War. </p>
      <p> Whenever possible, the original order of the papers was preserved. However, many of the documents were in substantial disarray (e.g., portions of a single typescript were scattered throughout the folder). As a result, much of the material was rearranged to facilitate its use. Several newspaper clippings were photocopied for preservation purposes.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_ed9a94e89e22306255cf7caf6708b75f">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection has three series, arranged chronologically.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite id="aspace_3ee9b824581302f89b383ccfcd41bb8a">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Saul K. Padover Papers, 1946-1972. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Padover Papers).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="meg">Political Science</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Propaganda, Russian.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Political scientists -- United States.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Austrians -- United States.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">United States -- Foreign relations -- 20th century.</subject>
      <persname source="lcsh">Padover, Saul Kussiel, 1905-1981</persname>
      <corpname source="lcsh">New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_cc4a8a245f0a81fe8a24b84c78dc4924" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Scholarly Writings</unittitle>
          <unitid>1</unitid>
          <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.07 cubic ft.</extent>
          </physdesc>
          <unitdate normal="1947/1970" type="inclusive">1947-1970</unitdate>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="aspace_6c6ee1ab4d0ce2ec0d0c7db739b3665e">
          <head>Arrangement</head>
          <p>Arranged chronologically.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_088a7ba984d732766060484705c9d5fa">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series consists of nine typescript essays (two of which are fragments) concerning Soviet propaganda initiatives, American efforts to counter it, the influence of public opinion on American foreign policy, and notes on related topics. One of these essays appeared in published form in Psychological Warfare, a pamphlet published by the Foreign Policy Association in 1951. Other essays in this series may also have been published. Also included in this series are notes that Padover wrote while working on these essays. Almost all of the materials in this series were written in the late 1940s and early 1950s, but the last essay in the series may have been revised in 1964, 1970, and 1972. As a result, it has been dated circa1970.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_278a15b9fd2eed390d94b088a673eea7" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Soviet Propaganda Themes Against the U.S. (unpub. TS), and Notes</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1947/1948" type="inclusive">1947-1948</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_a220c9c450aad27e3861a581eb378d3d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (1-Scholarly Writings)</container>
            <container id="aspace_8c14de87c25cfc00a6b9345155b70331" parent="aspace_a220c9c450aad27e3861a581eb378d3d" type="Folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_d0513248a3ee2ca821fb42ea7e375d8c" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Fragment, "Psychological Warfare" (unpub. TS), and Notes</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1951/1951" type="inclusive">ca. 1951</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_162bd3c748152e6ea6ebd40c5ca945ac" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (1-Scholarly Writings)</container>
            <container id="aspace_a71c17352bd5ef8036056f3546b27d3b" parent="aspace_162bd3c748152e6ea6ebd40c5ca945ac" type="Folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_e93b3c51b9939dc3ab1cf449525ec17d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Psychological Warfare (unpub. TS)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1952/1952" type="inclusive">1952</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_2c4243e8fb9ae6851d164d95c61ca959" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (1-Scholarly Writings)</container>
            <container id="aspace_ef9940293420b6c3b1623b9f9de16b5c" parent="aspace_2c4243e8fb9ae6851d164d95c61ca959" type="Folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_6733cacc6a6480476ac173daf6681a06" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Psychological Warfare (unpub. TS)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1953/1953" type="inclusive">1953</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_b271556ae6f384f3fc4689ea01c2d156" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (1-Scholarly Writings)</container>
            <container id="aspace_4ed06e008c71484782d9734931361bbe" parent="aspace_b271556ae6f384f3fc4689ea01c2d156" type="Folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_50651f5616a3732da36d558144e9181c" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>American Opinion in an Age of World Revolution (unpub. TS)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1953/1953" type="inclusive">1953</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_475bea4e17c24d260ec6b1fee34bfcee" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (1-Scholarly Writings)</container>
            <container id="aspace_205147b891e05b0401fd8badfd9886e4" parent="aspace_475bea4e17c24d260ec6b1fee34bfcee" type="Folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_86f336f6c4b00215bde12c0ffef49b80" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>The Age of Stalin? (unpub. TS)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1953/1953" type="inclusive">1953</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d969bef76ea3f24cdd41df41ec736670" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (1-Scholarly Writings)</container>
            <container id="aspace_33457e62cd3eebc37387c3b2a082fcbd" parent="aspace_d969bef76ea3f24cdd41df41ec736670" type="Folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_a35fc69c6091fccbd845737e3ab4f1ee" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>The Soviet Propaganda Apparatus (unpub. TS)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1953/1953" type="inclusive">ca. 1953</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_fed9086ad903cfca82458a2a5ae1e5e1" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (1-Scholarly Writings)</container>
            <container id="aspace_47044e9f18023c53531a3bcc71c6312b" parent="aspace_fed9086ad903cfca82458a2a5ae1e5e1" type="Folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_14671d6c18680c7073f6760a69d08979" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Fragment on Communist Propaganda in the Philippines (unpub. TS)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1955/1955" type="inclusive">ca. 1955</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_3d6c85953ae51db596f0a46f014c6d4e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (1-Scholarly Writings)</container>
            <container id="aspace_bf1677d3f109da7125b2e8c8da86432f" parent="aspace_3d6c85953ae51db596f0a46f014c6d4e" type="Folder">8</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_0661878140c66f942243ad8441dab9bc" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Notes on New York Times Article</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1956/1956" type="inclusive">1956</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_c995aa09a87f75b9ab46751da677b49c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (1-Scholarly Writings)</container>
            <container id="aspace_01e31a282a7e337ce707c324f50251e4" parent="aspace_c995aa09a87f75b9ab46751da677b49c" type="Folder">9</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_1a7489e578c922013a76f2ca570eaaa3" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Fragment, "Foreign Policy and Public Opinion" (unpub. TS)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1970/1970" type="inclusive">ca. 1970</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_f3416e9eb84b04c401d072a598f4e27f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (1-Scholarly Writings)</container>
            <container id="aspace_b837db9727e34fcdcbc441281207a803" parent="aspace_f3416e9eb84b04c401d072a598f4e27f" type="Folder">10</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_5bf7c1461472408412258a7e694d3543" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Course Materials</unittitle>
          <unitid>2</unitid>
          <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.1 cubic ft.</extent>
          </physdesc>
          <unitdate normal="1955/1970" type="inclusive">1955-1970</unitdate>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="aspace_5cab57b8673fe4886c5da6a81340d630">
          <head>Arrangement</head>
          <p>Arranged chronologically.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_911c6f67617d6ab84b15389b10c27c80">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series contains assorted materials generated in connection with Padover's teaching activities. Included are syllabi for a number of graduate and undergraduate courses, lecture notes, outlines of and notes about student presentations on various aspects of American foreign policy, and materials Padover created when leading the New School's General Seminar for faculty members.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_a034aa09218d3efb2d11096d8218bf16" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Syllabus, "Basic Factors in World Politics"</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1955/1955" type="inclusive">1955</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_85243ccb098659c5ae99f417a437b880" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (2-Course Materials)</container>
            <container id="aspace_4622c07de046785162115bf806ca321c" parent="aspace_85243ccb098659c5ae99f417a437b880" type="Folder">11</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_74df9354bc066980128146de292cb366" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Stock Price List and Notes on Total War and on U.S. Foreign Policy</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1956/1956" type="inclusive">1956</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_2843079ea9bc32f31b99a3c35f438d7a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (2-Course Materials)</container>
            <container id="aspace_a7ae4d9cabf4f90cbe0090a66bf9fe0e" parent="aspace_2843079ea9bc32f31b99a3c35f438d7a" type="Folder">12</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_6cb70206476fe5fa47bedb81f20f22a0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous Notes</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1967/1967" type="inclusive">1967</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d12363b8761de7a02a1fb5c640ad1d41" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (2-Course Materials)</container>
            <container id="aspace_7425df987602a68c6d66f6adbe109906" parent="aspace_d12363b8761de7a02a1fb5c640ad1d41" type="Folder">13</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_c1c36e529ba293eccb6834de5ca99932" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Notes on U.S. Troops Abroad and Clipping on Pakistan</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1967/1967" type="inclusive">1967</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_61ad0702acad801042a960c9a6d6bfcb" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (2-Course Materials)</container>
            <container id="aspace_958275f4f8c35b7a43b96eee7e33821a" parent="aspace_61ad0702acad801042a960c9a6d6bfcb" type="Folder">14</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_143a8cf7eb877277c2173925e39fa561" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Wells, "[Suez Crisis] Chronology" (unpub. TS)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1967/1967" type="inclusive">1967</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_9e027d712ec0c3417a38bbc4072f2846" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (2-Course Materials)</container>
            <container id="aspace_b9a5edd0482a1fb14d80cce6b917ac87" parent="aspace_9e027d712ec0c3417a38bbc4072f2846" type="Folder">15</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_e95b28987dd52bf06765104bd20f7c45" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Syllabus, "The Noble Tradition: Men Who Made American Democracy"</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1969/1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_5f0c40cdd7635c98bfbb7f979d1aa04b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (2-Course Materials)</container>
            <container id="aspace_3cc58c48d26d07735c47d68d55939b24" parent="aspace_5f0c40cdd7635c98bfbb7f979d1aa04b" type="Folder">16</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ea376b70a23c2174a131acce757f7ab1" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>List of [Presentation] Topics, "American Foreign Policy" Course</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1969/1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_df28b5edd1a6807f7869f230ebed1218" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (2-Course Materials)</container>
            <container id="aspace_7fb2cebe69b5606fdc4398a0d49d4780" parent="aspace_df28b5edd1a6807f7869f230ebed1218" type="Folder">17</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_68fd34c7fc337ee7d2132825883bc7dc" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Smith, "American Foreign Policy: The Purchase of the Virgin Islands" (unpub. TS), and Maps</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1969/1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_190e8983dbe45bcabd252186624c029d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (2-Course Materials)</container>
            <container id="aspace_18045550e607a82ec15e2d35a3effe49" parent="aspace_190e8983dbe45bcabd252186624c029d" type="Folder">18</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_48ef7778b536bcd853ff796c6391296c" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Notes on Kramm Presentation, "Lend-Lease," and on Smith Presentation, "V.I. Acquisition"</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1969/1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_59d6afe078e4ba919095f6947b1d0614" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (2-Course Materials)</container>
            <container id="aspace_2d4903f479f227fbb33c9a28cb6b7bc9" parent="aspace_59d6afe078e4ba919095f6947b1d0614" type="Folder">19</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ee97fc7c5ab6e6a910e9d8970b3000ac" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Syllabus, "American Foreign Policy"</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1970/1970" type="inclusive">1970</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_44af02a68a59fdedbf405069e922460c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (2-Course Materials)</container>
            <container id="aspace_c63a8be876fa0fc0f8701dff2a2e9e09" parent="aspace_44af02a68a59fdedbf405069e922460c" type="Folder">20</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_dc5feedf5415f9c998260ab58368a28b" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Notes on U.S. Foreign Policy</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1970/1970" type="inclusive">ca. 1970</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_ff692bc8a69fe3fbc91aa4d7cf305042" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (2-Course Materials)</container>
            <container id="aspace_3695be481d44a8b09c2fe3a9106c0e66" parent="aspace_ff692bc8a69fe3fbc91aa4d7cf305042" type="Folder">21</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_7815a7930a14972f16e0b9b02c82c4a6" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Fast, "U.S.-Philippine Relations 1945-1947" (unpub. TS)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1970/1970" type="inclusive">ca. 1970</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_a89006ceef6127ebb4bec41b6da70279" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (2-Course Materials)</container>
            <container id="aspace_77a673370e2b97c5a47cc2bda8c8ad4b" parent="aspace_a89006ceef6127ebb4bec41b6da70279" type="Folder">22</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_f55028f026e252065ab688d6f97dccb2" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Tortorella, "Dwight D. Eisenhower and His Concept of the Presidency" (unpub. TS)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1970/1970" type="inclusive">ca. 1970</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_244640008a3ddfadb69b6229229b232e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (2-Course Materials)</container>
            <container id="aspace_1aa2b1409ad030e18c804dd1ce0314c5" parent="aspace_244640008a3ddfadb69b6229229b232e" type="Folder">23</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_5decb2e3dd74dce9185cfec3bc0dc1c0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>General Seminar syllabus, "American Foreign Policy: Case Studies"</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1970/1970" type="inclusive">ca. 1970</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_793ff28d0f035ef898a0eacdad10bf44" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (2-Course Materials)</container>
            <container id="aspace_6b23739e9c12abf13c3829e3defbd6b9" parent="aspace_793ff28d0f035ef898a0eacdad10bf44" type="Folder">24</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_f28a0ca39bc82a5ccbecd64cbb38be1c" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Definitions (unpub. TS)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1970/1970" type="inclusive">ca. 1970</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_677d566c55295128bdc51508639f45e5" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (2-Course Materials)</container>
            <container id="aspace_2f951ff2a77d6699184edc3591ac35a4" parent="aspace_677d566c55295128bdc51508639f45e5" type="Folder">25</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_9acf50ae59377f4aad7253dbf644e8e7" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Notes on the Nature of Power and on the Philippines</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1947/1972" type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d1eb80dd4fefc66c1e6af7338728d543" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (2-Course Materials)</container>
            <container id="aspace_c56b066da977f44afd9bafcaa91f8c9d" parent="aspace_d1eb80dd4fefc66c1e6af7338728d543" type="Folder">26</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_37da1fc242f2785fed198afee8dd234d" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Research Materials</unittitle>
          <unitid>3</unitid>
          <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.03 cubic ft.</extent>
          </physdesc>
          <unitdate normal="1947/1972" type="inclusive">1947-1972</unitdate>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="aspace_5d10cd2b2d48da8608e4d9818a5f9fc8">
          <head>Arrangement</head>
          <p>Arranged chronologically.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_edcedfbc2ac95dba0e95eedae24239dc">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series consists of materials that Padover collected for their informational value: a United Nations Information Service flier, newspaper clippings about the Voice of America and foreign policy expert George F. Kennan, an article concerning the U.S. Supreme Court's refusal to hear a case concerning the constitutionality of American involvement in Vietnam, and a letter from the President of the New School concerning protests against the Vietnam War.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_d2047b933b86a91c593d3d710e33dedb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>United Nations Information Service, News Brief</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1947/1947" type="inclusive">1947</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_0c40c1fe6086d0882d2f844344e1e9ee" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (3-Research Materials)</container>
            <container id="aspace_8a102538c2023a84acf58f442d5411a1" parent="aspace_0c40c1fe6086d0882d2f844344e1e9ee" type="Folder">27</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_7306f87945fc24daec77e1fbefad46e2" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings on Voice of America and George F. Kennan</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1956/1956" type="inclusive">1956</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_0c6a16358c9062439d13f2a642679bdc" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (3-Research Materials)</container>
            <container id="aspace_8f3b6d558b5757f33831fc3e7eabc7f0" parent="aspace_0c6a16358c9062439d13f2a642679bdc" type="Folder">28</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_30ae1157eb97f3d9db6884e7a926fda1" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Court Rejects Case Concerning the Legality of the War (pub.)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1967/1967" type="inclusive">1967</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_0b0657469fe6cf83f42051d0e0783722" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (3-Research Materials)</container>
            <container id="aspace_826cb584bdaf3cddcc7887c718f2b85b" parent="aspace_0b0657469fe6cf83f42051d0e0783722" type="Folder">29</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_a2fefc1afba200996357b0a7a16317ac" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Letter from New School President Concerning Vietnam War Protests</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_956e7b538a27291b1aba661140d065eb" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (3-Research Materials)</container>
            <container id="aspace_f0c3e15ce61587ed2473390c459807af" parent="aspace_956e7b538a27291b1aba661140d065eb" type="Folder">30</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
