<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead id="nam_ger128">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="apap014" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/ger128.html">nam_ger128</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>HORST MENDERSHAUSEN PAPERS (GER128)<date normal="1930/1999" type="inclusive">1930-1999</date></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="2016" type="publication">Copyright 2016 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All
          rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation audience="internal">Conversion and encoding by ArchProteus, <date normal="2014">2014</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date normal="2016">2016</date>
        <item>EAD file created</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_ger128</unitid>
      <unittitle>Horst Mendershausen Papers <unitdate normal="1930/1999" type="inclusive">1930-1999</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">The Horst Mendershausen Papers consist of select materials from
        six decades of Mendershausens personal and professional life as an economist and political
        scientist. </abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcsh">Mendershausen, Horst</persname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">1.0</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage: ">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Biographical History</head>
      <p>Born in Koethen, Germany in 1911, Horst Mendershausen obtained his Ph.D. from the
        University of Geneva in 1937 and received a Rockefeller Fellowship for post-graduate study
        in Norway and the United States the following year. During Dr. Mendershausens long career in
        economics and politics, he served as a professor at Bennington College; an economist at the
        Federal Reserve Bank; an economist and assistant chief of price control for the U.S.
        Military Government for Germany in Berlin in the immediate post-World War II years; a
        consultant for the United Nations Division of Economic Stability and Development; a lecturer
        at the University of California, Los Angles; and as a senior social scientist and later a
        consultant for The RAND Corporation. He authored numerous books, articles, and reports, some
        published by The RAND Corporation.</p>
      <p>Dr. Mendershausen died in 2003 and was survived by his wife Elfriede and sons Philip and
        Ralph.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>The Horst Mendershausen Papers contain biographical materials, correspondence, reports,
        subject files related to his publications, article reprints, and clippings. </p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement>
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult
        to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>Horst Mendershausen's son Ralph Mendershausen donated all the materials in this collection
        to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives.<date normal="2016">2016</date></p>
    </acqinfo>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the
        collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable
        information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must
        be managed by an archivist.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright.
        Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will
        provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal
        determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish
        material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and
        Archives.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Horst Mendershausen Papers,
        1930-1999. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University
        Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the
        Mendershausen Papers).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <subject source="meg" encodinganalog="650">Political Science</subject>
      <subject source="meg" encodinganalog="650">Economics</subject>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcsh">Mendershausen, Horst</persname>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Economists--United States</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Political scientists--United States</subject>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Files by subject</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    </controlaccess>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
