<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" id="ger120">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ger120.xml">ger120</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Lederer, Walther; Papers <num>ger120</num></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2016</date>
        </p>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-04-14 12:35:35 -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2017 January 2</date>
        <item>Encoded in EAD by Brian Keough</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Walther Lederer<unitdate normal="1929/2003" type="inclusive">1929-2003</unitdate></unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname source="lcsh">Lederer, Walther, 1908-</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>ger120</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7 cubic ft.</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract id="aspace_99453ab5583f4c8a31d83fb9a41f867b">This collection contains material related to Walther Lederer and his family.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_f405669618c316547c38d4956ad0561e">English</langmaterial>
      <physloc id="aspace_38395c5e8e2c0a551b6265381baf6726">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <container id="aspace_dc6185890cc468c1b9310def618df89e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
    </did>
    <processinfo id="aspace_fc19d64eb59d5147484abd2f7d1e75a3">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed in 2016 by unprocessed.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_f7af1a98266872b160429664f57b3f9b">
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_8e23cb73b105adc5f18f6e9f14b4ac02">
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
      <p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
      <p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_c424a4a2f24917be3e728be288465057">
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_2311fe13ee18a05d3b898d96d4a8bc48">
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>Walther Lederer came to the U.S. in 1933 and, after completing postgraduate work at the University of Iowa, held teaching positions at Hunter College in New York, the University of Delaware in Newark, and Queens College in New York. In 1942, Lederer accepted his first position in Washington, D.C. as an economist for the Board of Economic Welfare. In October 1945, he moved to the U.S. Department of Commerce, Office of Business Economics, Balance of Payments Division, and in May 1954 became Chief of the Division. Lederer continued in that position until 1969.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_a15580d4d899b53bdb93bbce84ae8446">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>This collection contains publications of Walther Lederer and of his uncle, Emil Lederer, correspondence between Walther and his first wife, Ruth Klein Lederer, 1929-1931, and biographical documents.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_be6bf91e839ef022f38ef03012db359d">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite id="aspace_b5b5bcf162f233f8a2c97f43637379e5">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Walther Lederer, 1929-2003. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Walther Lederer).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="meg">Economics</subject>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc/>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
