<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='collection-level.xsl'?> 
<!DOCTYPE ead SYSTEM 'ead.dtd'>
<ead id="nam_mss140">
  <eadheader audience="external" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="##" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/mss140.html">nam_mss140</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>THE GREGORY MAGUIE PAPERS (MSS140)<date normal="1970/2011" type="inclusive">1970-2011</date></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="1970/2011" type="publication">Copyright 1970-2011 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Melissa McMullen<date normal="2016-10-18">2016 October 18</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>The Gregory Maguie Papers<date normal="1970/2011" type="inclusive">1970-2011</date></titleproper>
      <publisher/>
      <date type="publication">Copyright 2016 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      <p>For reference queries contact Grenander Department Reference staff or (518)-437-3934</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_mss140</unitid>
      <unittitle>The Gregory Maguie Papers<unitdate label="Date:" normal="1970/2011" type="inclusive">1970-2011</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">The Gregory Maguire Papers are a collection of materials from the American novelist. He is the author of Wicked: The Life and Times of the Wicked Witch of the West, Confessions of an Ugly Stepsister, and several dozen other novels for adults and children.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcsh">Maguire, Gregory</persname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">12</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage:">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict><head>Access</head><p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p><p>Red asterisks (***) denote restricted items.</p></accessrestrict>
    <userestrict><head>Copyright</head><p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p></userestrict>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.<date normal="2011">2011</date></p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>Gregory Maguire was born June 9, 1945 in Albany, NY. He received his Ph.D. in English and American Literature from Tufts University, and his B.A. from the State University of New York at Albany. He is the New York Times bestselling author of Wicked: The Life and Times of the Wicked Witch of the West, Confessions of an Ugly Stepsister, and several dozen other novels for adults and children. Many of Maguire's novels are based on classic children's stories.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>The materials in the Gregory Maguire collection are unprocessed. The collection includes notebooks, correspondence, and  early drafts of works by Maguire. The collection also holds clippings from Maguire's father and his time as a reporter in Albany, NY. </p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, The Gregory Maguie Papers, 1970-2011. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University  Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the The Gregory Maguie Papers).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <persname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="600">Maguire, Gregory</persname>
      <persname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="600">Maguire, Gregory. Wicked</persname>
      <persname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="600">Maguire, Gregory. Wicked years</persname>
    </controlaccess>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
