<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" id="ua010.013">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>ua010.013</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Task Force for Planning Downtown Campus; Records <num>ua010.013</num></titleproper>
        <author>Erik Stolarski</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2017</date>
        </p>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-12-18 12:13:09 -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Task Force for Planning Downtown Campus<unitdate normal="1970/1972" type="inclusive">1970-1972</unitdate></unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname rules="local" source="local">State University of New York at Albany. Task Force for Planning Downtown Campus</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>ua010.013</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">0.2</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract id="aspace_ae687dd2b86087bfe6d70d2705afbeb4">In the early 1970s SUNY Albany sought to better utilize the space of the downtown campus, and improve the infrastructure overall. This collection is made up of materials created by a Task Force charged with taking on this burden.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_a86c699c08fceeea7a6b90f160666cdc">English</langmaterial>
      <physloc id="aspace_6f39e91a61f1c67c353fc36cf3b0c190">Materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <container id="aspace_3519a03de07faaafaf65f30ba530eaa9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container>
    </did>
    <arrangement id="aspace_1005e42df3c84b5bd0d5e098c421729a">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>Collection is arranged in original order.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <bioghist id="aspace_c1e7821bc2e13785ed894a4d549ebfb9">
      <head>Administrative History</head>
      <p>In the summer of 1971 planning for a reorganizing of the downtown campus began. With the near completion of the Uptown campus, the downtown one was targeted as the campus population grew and accommodations had to be made. It was felt that that the interiors of the buildings needed to be refurbished to suit the modern times. The Task Force also wanted to reform the structure of campus by creating more evening classes for adults. There was also a goal of shortening the time it takes to earn a bachelor’s degree down to three years from four. This was referred to as "Collins College" named after the former president of the University Evan R. Collins.
Not all of the recommendations made by the Task Force were seen through. Based on the ones found in meeting minutes and reports this task force played an important role in the further development of the State University at Albany. The Task Force was only active during the early 1970s as the records span 1970 to 1972. It was also referred to as the Planning Task Force in many documents.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_9a7f3a157248426e30e76ca8b31508e0">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_0cab2a7052a55c9605ba8be14df9d961">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites. Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder. The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks. The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_1adeeda40c12ffaa36b64a3890026ff0">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_1f6afeec02a29ac0c3fae7df36e60a4e">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, The Task Force for Planning Downtown Campus, 1970-1972. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Task force for Planning Downtown Campus).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="aspace_74772c13cec51ab031af35fe14d7fe0c">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Colleection was processed in 2017 by Erik Stolarski.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_bf2322537e8d7528a1ad2780ecddace4">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>This collection contains materials created by the Task Force for Planning Downtown Campus. The items document meetings and proposals made by the Task Force. These include changes to class and degree earning structure, reorganizing and refurbishment of the downtown campus, and expansion of campus buildings to gain more space for key parts of the university. The documents include proposals, meeting minutes, responses to proposals from upper University administration, and correspondence with companies for planning these changes. There is little evidence of the implementation of these changes and most documents cover planning and proposals.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Campus planning -- New York (State).</subject>
      <subject source="local">State University of New York at Albany-Administration</subject>
      <subject source="meg">UAlbany Task Forces &amp; Committees</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Engineering</geogname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_2de93a46e888acb6f1b82c077619f90d" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Task Force for Planning Downtown Campus</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1971/1971" type="inclusive">1971</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_8373b3506a6848d0f15b140e06080f67" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (Task Force for Planning Downtown Campus)</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_c76973b74c4fa69ce6eba94879309f7d" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Program Proposal</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1971/1971" type="inclusive">1971</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_9b85e9b95651672e5adc32621f5ec8ce" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (Task Force for Planning Downtown Campus)</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ce3e2d6d0d5c09d86297cdf175985c2b" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Task Force for Planning Downtown Campus</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1970/1972" type="inclusive">1970-1972</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_056af03584cbc3cf749c26c2a9bec926" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (Task Force for Planning Downtown Campus)</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
