<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" id="ua316">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid/>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Academic Planning and Development, Office of the Vice President for; Records <num>ua316</num></titleproper>
        <author>Erik Stolarski</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2017</date>
        </p>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-01-08 23:00:35 -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Office of the Vice President for Academic Planning and Development, Records<unitdate normal="1963/1998" type="inclusive">1978-1987</unitdate></unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname rules="local" source="local">Vice President for Academic Planning and Development</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>ua316</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">3.0</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract id="aspace_0b0f6195373ec8d0229c8b2367be3329">This collection is made up of materials related to the changes that took place at the University At Albany in the mid-1980s across the uptown and downtown campuses. This included a reorganization of the library and integration of new digital systems.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_0ef91b53da465ffb5cf60e3a7e24d559">English</langmaterial>
      <physloc id="aspace_4b0921a9f1654e802c84a9a24edd8b4a">Materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <container id="aspace_c36e940f511c1b7fa1292615b7b8a439" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container>
      <container id="aspace_c7140df1c960f795f8f3cc61d280eb6c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container>
      <container id="aspace_d97c71be851414684194d9cd5afdd791" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container>
    </did>
    <arrangement id="aspace_60488a82a314c70754d2203921f6fdf5">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>Collection is arranged in the original order it was recieved in.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <bioghist id="aspace_90b89de7afe9862b1cdf7dd5b24998cb">
      <head>Administrative History</head>
      <p>The Vice President for Academic Planning and Development oversaw changes to the overall program offered at the University at Albany in the mid-1980s. John W. Shumaker was the Vice President for Academic Planning and Development. He worked for SUNY Albany from 1977 to 1987, first as the Dean of the Humanities and Fine Arts before being promoted to Vice President. 
    During this time the University sought to become more supportive of research being done on campus. Two separate programs were committed to. One was to expand the library’s holdings and become more of a research library. This also meant expanding the variety of the library’s holdings to support new programs such as Asian or African Studies. Included with these materials are plans from SUNY Binghamton who the University at Albany used as a model to develop their new library.
	The other was to support research programs in the sciences. More resources were put towards supporting work being done for outside institutions. The goal was to connect faculty and students to investors looking to support new research. This was described as being a response to the growth of support in entrepreneurial ventures during the 1980s. This, like the library development, was part of a SUNY wide initiative.
	The last major program represented in this collection is related to the development of the SUNY Albany program for incoming freshman students. This was in response to a changing view on how students experience college and also the reasons for attending college. The Vice President supported the idea of changing the experience of first year students in the wake of a changing world. Like the other proposals there was a committee created to investigate these proposed changes.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_ba93b397e3c6e69afc523f56ce9a45e9">
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_57d08558df3fc7350eb77ab4040c9f6c">
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites. Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder. The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks. The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_7362c2fe17d9c4155256eb2a93af413a">
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_1420b2c38fe6ecc2420d4a8970482443">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, The Office of the Vice President for Academic Planning and Development, 1979-1987. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Office of the Vice President for Academic Planning and Development).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="aspace_e463eb6143e58fdeeb992313653e0eb0">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed in 2017 by Erik Stolarski.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_4b6f4bac8f18d92184095f9d050f1ad5">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>This collection has materials created by the Office of the Vice President for Academic Planning and Development. It consists of correspondence, reports from committees created by the Vice President, reports created by other universities, meeting minutes written by committees, and five year plans crafted for the university. These materials cover various topics such as expansion of the academic and social program on campus, introduction of new technology made available to students, as well as an expansion of research initiatives across the University.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Library catalogs -- Automation</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">School budgets   </geogname>
      <subject source="meg">UAlbany University Development</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Research libraries</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">Educational planning</subject>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc/>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
