<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" id="ua315">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ua315.xml">ua315</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Management and Planning, Vice President for; Records <num>ua315</num></titleproper>
        <author>Erik Stolarski</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2017</date>
        </p>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-11-27 16:58:20 -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2017 February 9</date>
        <item>Encoded in EAD by Benjamin Covell</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Office of the Vice President for Management and Planning Records<unitdate normal="1965/1978" type="inclusive">1965-1978</unitdate></unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname source="local">State University of New York at Albany. Office of the Vice President for Management and Planning</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>ua315</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">4</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract id="aspace_0ab0721c8ec2659d10b10871c920cf82">Contains the records of the Office of the Vice President for Management and Planning, which oversaw budget, personnel, facilities, security, and other campus services from 1966 until 1977 when the position became the Vice President for Finance and Business.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_93996fcfc8cc48f06836ba639b1c36d2">English</langmaterial>
      <physloc id="aspace_a840e34e4beb034aeb7f9c936e9b11ff">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <container id="aspace_e413b506d82ab65f46c881dc314f0a63" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container>
      <container id="aspace_7518d3fd7de415ec0ced85a3136ade8f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container>
      <container id="aspace_25ce57de44ddf2642b144451861068bc" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container>
      <container id="aspace_f2ad51189464767dc80697a0f2c74a04" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container>
      <container id="aspace_248588d862ccea314cb98326436478ce" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">5</container>
    </did>
    <processinfo id="aspace_e66d2d3b9f7f72c98273291cabe080bc">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed in 2017 by Erik Stolarski.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_b0b45b0ebcc37bdc98f8733cf602bedc">
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to the Collection is unrestricted.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_f657004e7625a19238e8e66cc162a9e3">
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
      <p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
      <p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_54a23d05a4b006bbcaf7ed510d49368f">
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_45362c14cb7a3ff7fbf99d3e18eab5ba">
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>The position of Vice President for Management and Planning was created circa 1966 to oversee several University functions that had previously been independent: adminstration, finance and budgeting, and others. The position was replaced by the Vice President for Finance and Business in 1977.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_5283d179b2eb94c685b9254f47e62ba9">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>This collection contains budget planning documents, personnel records, staff meeting minutes, space and construction planning materials, security reports, enrollment summaries, department files, and other administrative documentation.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_f2275483b8a87ff4f88cd6317ad2628f">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite id="aspace_c2c496a250710772381709b86bb4a880">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Office of the Vice President for Management and Planning Records, 1965-1978. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Office of the Vice President for Management and Planning Records).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher--Administration</subject>
      <genreform source="aat">Administrative records</genreform>
      <subject source="meg">UAlbany Finance &amp; Business</subject>
      <corpname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc/>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
