<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead id="nam_ua370">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="apap014" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/ua370.html">nam_ua370</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>OFFICE OF DIVERSITY AND INCLUSION RECORDS (UA370)<date normal="1970/2016" type="inclusive">1970-2016</date></titleproper>
        <author>David Wasserman</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="1992-12-07" type="publication">Copyright 1992 December 7 by the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation audience="internal">Mark Wolfe<date normal="2015">2015</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date normal="2015-12">2015 December</date>
        <item>Converted to EAD</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_ua370</unitid>
      <unittitle>Office Of Diversity and Inclusion Records<unitdate normal="1970/2016" type="inclusive">1970-2016</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">Formerly the Office Of Affirmative Action, the Office Of Diversity and Inclusion Records document the history and development of Affirmative Action office and programs across the campus.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <corpname encodinganalog="110" source="local">Office Of Affirmative Action, 1970-2016</corpname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">10</extent>
        <dimensions/>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage: ">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Biographical History</head>
      <p>The Office dates from the establishment of an Affirmative Action Program in 1971 in the Office of Personnel and was originally administered by the Equal Opportunity Coordinator. Former call the Office of Affirmative Action, it is has been renamed as the Office of Diversity and Inclusion.</p>
      <p>The Affirmative Action Office at the State University of New York at Albany was first described as the Equal Employment Opportunity (EEO)/Affirmative Action Office during the 1974-75 academic year. Delores B. Schmidt served as the first Affirmative Action Officer, initially with the title Equal Employment Opportunity Coordinator.**1 The creation of that office stemed from the U.S. Department of Labor's Order No. 4 which required the "development and implementation of Affirmative Action Programs by Federal Government contractors." SUNYA's plan was introduced to the University community by a "Statement on Affirmative Action at the State University of New York at Albany" from the President on September 28, 1971. The major objective of the Affirmative Action Program was "to change the past recruitment and promotion procedures to insure equal treatment of all candidates".**2</p>
      <p>This initial statement on the subject of affirmative action was later translated by the University's Commission on Affirmative Action into an Affirmative Action Plan consisting of 127 pages and 33 attachments, plus a 10-page supplement analyzing the composition of the Research Foundation work force was presented during Human Rights Week in March of 1974.**3 The Affirmative Action plan was further revised in 1978.**4</p>
      <p>The EEO/Affirmative Action Office initially reported to the Director of Personnel, Leon Calhoun. During the 1975-76 academic year Kay W. Norman served in the post of Affirmative Action Associate.**5 The 1976-77 School Year saw her appointed Affirmative Action Officer.**6</p>
      <p>The 1977-78 Academic Year saw Rosemary Kilkenny Sabai appointed Affirmative Action Officer,**7 a post she retained until 1981 when Gloria DeSole was appointed Acting Director of the Affirmative Action Office. The 1982-83 Academic Year saw DeSole appointed Assistant to the President For Affirmative Action.**8. The change in title signified a new reporting relationship--the Office reported directly the President.</p>
      <p>
        <chronlist>
          <chronitem>
            <date/>
            <event>Delores B. Schmidt, Equal Employment Opportunities Coordinator, 1974; Affirmative Action Officer, 1974/74-1975/76</event>
          </chronitem>
          <chronitem>
            <date/>
            <event>Kay W. Norman, Affirmative Action Associate, 1975/76, Affirmative Action Officer, 1976/77</event>
          </chronitem>
          <chronitem>
            <date/>
            <event>Rosemary Kilkenny Sabai, Affirmative Action Officer, 1977/78-1980/81</event>
          </chronitem>
          <chronitem>
            <date/>
            <event>Gloria DeSole, Acting Affirmative Action Officer, 1981-82; Assistant to the President for Affirmative Action, 1982-</event>
          </chronitem>
        </chronlist>
      </p>
      <p>1. "First Affirmative Action Practicum Here This Week," Tower Tribune, 5/4 (March 11, 1974), 1; State University of New York at Albany, University Directory, 1974-75, 6.
2. Statement on Affirmative Action at State University of New York at Albany, 3/23/72. Affirmative Action 1971-72 file, Office of the President Records (292/14).
3. <emph render="italic">Tower Tribune</emph>, 3/11/1974. 1,2.
4.  <emph render="italic">University News</emph>, 3/1/78, 4.
5. The University of Albany,  <emph render="italic">University Directory</emph>, 1975-76, 6.
6. The University at Albany, <emph render="italic">University Directory</emph>, 1975-76, 6.
7. The University at Albany, <emph render="italic">University Directory</emph>. 1977-78, 6.
8. State University of New York at Albany, <emph render="italic">University Directory</emph>, 1982-83, 6.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>Includes correspondence, memoranda, minutes of meetings, surveys, and printed materials relating to the 504 Program History (handicapped access), and the implementation of the Title IX Program.  Also included in the record group are the minutes and correspondence of the University Council on Affirmative Action.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement>
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection has no series, arranged chronologically.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by the Office of Affirmative Action.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites. </p>
      <p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks. </p>
      <p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future. </p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Office Of Affirmative Action Records, 1970-1984. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University  Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the  Office Of Affirmative Action).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <subject source="meg" encodinganalog="650">Women</subject>
      <corpname encodinganalog="611" source="local">Office Of Affirmative Action</corpname>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">State University of New York at Albany -- Administration.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">State University of New York at Albany. Office of Affirmative Action.</subject>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Memoranda</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
    </controlaccess>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
