<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE ead SYSTEM 'ead.dtd'>
<ead id="nam_ua443">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="apap014" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/ua443.html">nam_ua443</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>HUMANISTIC EDUCATION CENTER (UA443)<date normal="1969/1973" type="inclusive">1969-1973</date></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="2015" type="publication">Copyright 2015 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation audience="internal">Conversion and encoding by ArchProteus, <date normal="2014">2014</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date normal="2014">2014</date>
        <item>EAD file created</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_ua443</unitid>
      <unittitle>Humanistic Education Center<unitdate normal="1969/1973" type="inclusive">1969-1973</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">The collection consists of records from the University at Albany's Humanistic Education Center, 1969-1973.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <corpname encodinganalog="110" source="local">Humanistic Education Center</corpname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">7</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage: ">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Biographical History</head>
      <p>The University at Albany established the Humanistic Education Center in 1969.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>The collections consists of University at Albany's Humanistic Education Center records including:  material on the Vocational Education program, 196973; proposals, 197173; correspondence; reports; publications; memoranda; budgetary documents.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement>
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this manuscript group were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Humanistic Education Center Records. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University  Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local"> Institute for Humanistic Studies</corpname>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">humanism</subject>
    </controlaccess>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
