<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" id="ua520">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ua520.xml">ua520</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>University College; Records <num>ua520</num></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2017</date>
        </p>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-05-04 23:15:59 -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2017 February 23</date>
        <item>Encoded in EAD by Benjamin Covell</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>University College<unitdate normal="1964/1986" type="inclusive">1964-1986</unitdate></unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname source="local">State University of New York at Albany. University College</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>ua520</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10 cubic ft.</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract id="aspace_c116f6ac7f7f2aba6239afe99f218217">This collection contains papers from the office of Robert Morris, who served as Dean of the University College (1966-1970) and subsequently as Dean of Undergraduate Studies (1970-approximately 1976). The collection addresses all aspects of the administration of undergraduate education at the University. It includes undergraduate policy manuals, advisement manuals, grading policy documentation, daily correspondence between Morris and various other administrators at the University, and planning documentation for the Undergraduate Bulletin. The bulk of the material is dated between 1966 and 1978.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_1b1e9703b41a5df69bdb7f0c7a19bf6e">English</langmaterial>
      <physloc id="aspace_dcb62b0fbcaca73769674fcaeb8b530f">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <container id="aspace_bdf63af31beed1b06e55f7ae946dfa43" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
    </did>
    <processinfo id="aspace_1ea88bfedc5f1b406486b0d336b579ad">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed in 2017 by unprocessed.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_1646ab66aed706d1c66efe0179c111cf">
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_7fc9c9cd02dff46a9732408816ffc5d1">
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
      <p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
      <p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_12131e4df0bf7e644ae2120b1266ec79">
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_e043c150a244e8daa4c6201b2afbc84a">
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>This collection consists primarily of records created by Robert Morris during his time at the University at Albany. He started in 1966 as Dean of the University College, which was established in 1963 to oversee aspects academic affairs for freshmen and sophomores, including: academic probation, advisement, attendence, and withdrawal. He then became Dean of Undergraduate Studies, and held that position from 1970 until approximately 1976.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_3d2dbb0319ebf65dc44036b8df5166b6">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>It includes undergraduate policy manuals, advisement manuals, grading policy documentation, daily correspondence between Morris and various other administrators at the University, budget materials, annual reports, enrollment data, and planning documentation for the Undergraduate Bulletin. The bulk of the material is dated between 1966 and 1978.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_9a04d9fe5ea36dbf86be1fbf0e8deba6">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite id="aspace_d1ee73498b81b67fb3c79b2ee9b93434">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, University College, 1964-1986. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the University College).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher--Administration</subject>
      <genreform source="aat">Administrative records</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
      <subject source="meg">UAlbany Academic Administration</subject>
      <corpname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc/>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
