<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='collection-level.xsl'?> 
<!DOCTYPE ead SYSTEM 'ead.dtd'>
<ead id="nam_ua580">
  <eadheader audience="external" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="##" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/ua580.html">nam_ua580</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>UNIVERSITY LIBRARIES, OFFICE OF THE DIRECTOR RECORDS (UA580)<date normal="1916/1993" type="inclusive">1916-1993</date></titleproper>
        <author>Eric Reichert and Geoffrey A. Huth</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="1989" type="publication">Copyright 1989 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Eric Reichert and Geoffrey A. Huth<date normal="1989-07-28">1989 July 28</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>University Libraries, Office of the Director Records<date normal="1916/1993" type="inclusive">1916-1993</date></titleproper>
      <publisher/>
      <date type="publication">Copyright 2017 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      <p>For reference queries contact Grenander Department Reference staff or (518)-437-3934</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_ua580</unitid>
      <unittitle>University Libraries, Office of the Director Records<unitdate label="Date:" normal="1916/1993" type="inclusive">1916-1993</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">This collection consists mainly of the records of the Office of the Director, records of the Library's divisions and departments, and the University Library Faculty.  Includes accession and withdrawal records, 1929-1957; book circulation records, 1929-1960; correspondence, reports and minutes of bibliographers' meetings, 1966-1979; and bound volumes of the University Libraries newsletter, 1972-1976; announcements, schedules of events, memoranda, newspaper clippings, and brochures relating to Community University Day, 1972-1983; memoranda and pamphlets about access policy, 1979-1983; and annual reports, 1979-1987.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <corpname encodinganalog="110" source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany. University Libraries</corpname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">163.7</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage:">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict><head>Access</head><p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is partially unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p></accessrestrict>
    <userestrict><head>Copyright</head><p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p></userestrict>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>
   The University Libraries began as a textbook collection in the New York
State Normal School, which opened in 1844.&amp;nbsp; Within three months of
its opening, the school had acquired its first set of textbooks, and in
1845 a student was appointed as the first librarian.&amp;nbsp; While the important
decisions regarding collection development were made by the faculty, the
library continued to be run by students under the direction of the principal
of the school until 1849 when a faculty member was hired as librarian.
  </p>
  <p>
   Although the library's collection would remain relatively small until
the 1960s (partly because it was felt that the nearby New York State Library
would be adequate for school's needs), by the beginning of the twentieth
century it was clear that the school was becoming increasingly professionalized.&amp;nbsp;
In 1889 the name had been changed to the New York State Normal College,
and in 1905 it began to offer baccalaureate degrees in the arts and in
the sciences.&amp;nbsp; In 1909 the school moved to a spacious new campus built
at the convergence of Washington and Western Avenues (now the Downtown
Campus).&amp;nbsp; The name of the school was changed to the New York State
College for Teachers in 1914, and in 1916 the college hired Mary Cobb,
its first professionally trained librarian.&amp;nbsp; She would preside over
the library for forty of the next forty-five years.&amp;nbsp; In 1933 the college
moved the library from its cramped, University Libraries one-room quarters
on the second floor of Draper Hall to the college's old auditorium, Hawley
Hall, the first building to be solely occupied by the library.&amp;nbsp; The
move didn't solve the perennial space problems that the library would continue
to wrestle with during the ensuing decades, however.
  </p>
  <p>
   The 1960s was a decade of phenomenal growth for the college and the
library, and it was at this time that the college became a true university.&amp;nbsp;
In 1948 it had become a part of the new State University of New York, but
it wasn't until 1962, when it became the State University of New York at
Albany and one of four State University Centers, that it truly began to
be considered a serious research institution. Between 1960 and 1970, as
student enrollment quadrupled, going from 3,300 to 13,200, and the number
of academic departments grew from seventeen to fifty, the library built
a strong collection (swelling from 65,000 items to 620,000) to support
the burgeoning new university.&amp;nbsp; The library's staff grew at a commensurate
pace.&amp;nbsp; In 1960 there were ten librarians; by 1970 there were fifty-eight.
In 1962 the library staffed its new Bibliography Department with subject
specialists.
  </p>
  <p>
   The library's collections and facilities underwent a number of changes
during this time of expansion.&amp;nbsp; In 1964 and 1965 a reclassification
project was planned and implemented which involved converting from Dewey
Decimal to Library of Congress classification, a reorganization of the
card catalog, and the beginning of a machine-readable shelf-list database.&amp;nbsp;
The library was designated a selective repository for U.S. government documents
in 1965.&amp;nbsp; Also at this time, the expanding collection became increasingly
stratified.&amp;nbsp; The library established subject collections in the areas
of the physical sciences, social sciences, humanities, business, and education--all
separately housed within the library.&amp;nbsp; Another separate collection
was the University College Library (known as UNI), which was established
to serve the needs of freshmen and sophomores.&amp;nbsp; The separate collection
approach was quickly abandoned, however.&amp;nbsp; In 1970 the UNI was disbanded,
and in 1972 the subject collections were integrated.&amp;nbsp; Although the
subject collections didn't survive, the branch libraries did.&amp;nbsp; Two
were established in 1966: one for the School of Library and Information
Science and one for the Graduate School of Public Affairs.&amp;nbsp; (After
numerous changes in the branch libraries, there is now one branch--the
Dewey Graduate Library for Public Affairs and Policy, located in Hawley
Hall on the Downtown Campus--which serves the original two schools along
with the School of Criminal Justice, and the School of Social Welfare.)
  </p>
  <p>
   Space continued to be a problem even though the library had acquired
additional buildings in the 1960s to accommodate some of the collection
and staff.&amp;nbsp; It came as a great relief, then, when in the late 1960s
most of the university moved to the new uptown campus.&amp;nbsp; The library
began to make the move to the new campus in 1966, and an official dedication
ceremony was held in 1968.&amp;nbsp; The library's space problem persisted,
however, and a plan to relieve it by adding 165,000 square feet of space
by 1974 was never realized because of fiscal constraints.
  </p>
  <p>
   During the latter half of the 1960s, librarians throughout the State
University system began to lobby for full faculty status on par with the
teaching faculty.&amp;nbsp; Although they never attained true parity with those
professionals, in 1968 SUNY librarians were rewarded for their efforts
when they achieved faculty status with promotion, recognized professional
service, and the ranks of Assistant Librarian, Associate Librarian, and
Librarian.&amp;nbsp; A fourth rank, Senior Assistant Librarian, was created
in 1977.
  </p>
  <p>
   Firmly established as a research institution, the University Libraries
continued to make impressive strides during the 1970s and 1980s, particularly
in the areas of computerization, online information retrieval, and networking.&amp;nbsp;
An automated circulation system built upon the machine-readable shelf-list
(called Library Circulation System and later Library Control System [LCS])
was started in 1972, and in 1984 the libraries implemented an integrated
public access catalog and circulation system designed by the GEAC corporation
called Gemini.&amp;nbsp; In 1974 the University Libraries began to use the
cataloging of the Online Computer Library Center (OCLC).&amp;nbsp; It became
a member of the Center for Research Libraries (CRL) in 1973, the Association
of Research Libraries (ARL) in 1975, and the Research Libraries Group (RLG)
in 1984.
  </p>
  <p>
   The 1990s is proving to be another time of change for the University
Libraries, as it tries to keep pace with&amp;nbsp; rapidly evolving information
technologies.&amp;nbsp; A new GEAC system, Advance, replaced Gemini in 1994,
and the university looks forward to the completion of a new library annex
designed to accommodate digital-based information systems.
  </p>
  <p>
   Prior to the late 1960s the title Librarian was used by the head of
the libraries and the term Library was used to designate the facility.&amp;nbsp;
In the late 1960s the terms Director and Libraries came into use but they
were used along with the older terms until the beginning of the 1970s when
the use of Director and Libraries became firmly established.&amp;nbsp; The
following is a list of Librarians and Directors, whose terms coincided
with the years covered by the records, along with the dates they began
their term:&amp;nbsp; Mary Cobb, 1916; Alice Hastings, 1956; Jonathan Ashton
(Interim), 1970; circa James Schmidt, 1972; John Farley (Acting), 1979; Joseph
Z. Nitecki, 1980; Sharon Bonk (Acting), 1988; Meredith Butler, 1989.
  </p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>The records of the Office of the Director are comprised of a variety of documents, including correspondence, meeting minutes and agendas, reports, surveys, financial records, published articles, newsletters, grant applications, manuals, and vendors' promotional materials.  The records were generated and collected as the director monitored and participated in the activities of the libraries' units, committees, and advisory groups; interacted with agents outside of the libraries; and reported to administrative superiors.  The records begin in 1916, the year the library got its first professionally trained librarian, but the bulk of the collection dates from after 1962, when the school became the State University of New York at Albany and the resources began to be made available to dramatically expand staffing and collections.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is partially unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, University Libraries, Office of the Director Records, 1916-1993. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University  Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the University Libraries, Office of the Director Records).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <corpname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="610">State University of New York at Albany</corpname>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Academic library directors</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Academic libraries</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Library administration</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Education, Higher--Administration</subject>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">administrative recods</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">annual reports</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">minutes (administrative records)</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">newsletters</genreform>
    </controlaccess>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
