<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead id="nam_ua603">
  <eadheader audience="external" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="##" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/ua603.html">nam_ua603</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>DEPARTMENT OF ENGLISH RECORDS (UA603)<date normal="1930/1997" type="inclusive">1930-1997</date></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="2017" type="publication">Copyright 2017 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Benjamin Covell<date normal="2017-02-20">2017 February 20</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>Department of English Records<date normal="1930/1997" type="inclusive">1930-1997</date></titleproper>
      <publisher/>
      <date type="publication">Copyright 2017 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      <p>For reference queries contact Grenander Department Reference staff or (518)-437-3934</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_ua603</unitid>
      <unittitle>Department of English Records<unitdate label="Date:" normal="1930/1997" type="inclusive">1930-1997</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">Contains inactive records of the Department of English, including curricula, annaul reports, program evaluation materials, publications, and administrative records.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <corpname encodinganalog="110" source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany. Department of English</corpname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">12.4</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage:">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
      <p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
      <p>The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>English language and literature instruction at the University dates back to the founding of the New York State Normal School in 1844. The M.A. in English was first offered in 1962, and a Ph.D. was offered the following year.  A Doctor of Arts in English was introduced in 1971, intended for students preparing for a career in teaching, rather than research.  The D.A. program was discontinued in 1995.  Currently, the Department of English offers a B.A., an Honors B.A., a combined B.A./M.A., several minors, and graduate work leading to an M.A. or Ph.D.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>This collection includes: course bulletins (1941-1995); annual reports, State Education Department program evaluation reports and supporting materials; faculty recruitment and personnel documentation; course syllabi; budget files; enrollment statistics; space planning documentation; and subject files containing correspondence with other administrative and academic departments at the University.  Also included are runs of three literary magazines published by 13th Moon Press: <emph>The Quest</emph>, <emph>13th Moon</emph>, and <emph>The Little Magazine</emph>.  The bulk of the collection dates from 1970-1990.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Department of English Records, 1930-1997. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University  Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Department of English Records).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <subject source="meg" encodinganalog="650">Literature</subject>
      <corpname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="610">State University of New York at Albany</corpname>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Education, Higher--Administration</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">English language</subject>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">curricula</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">syllabi</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">annual reports</genreform>
    </controlaccess>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
