<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead id="nam_ua628">
  <eadheader audience="external" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="##" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/ua628.html">nam_ua628</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>DEPARTMENT OF PHYSICS RECORDS (UA628)<date normal="1915/1971" type="inclusive">1915-1971</date></titleproper>
        <author>Orson Kingsley, History 599 Intern</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="2015" type="publication">Copyright 2015 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Gregory Wiedeman<date normal="2015">2015</date>
			</creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date normal="2015-12">2015 December</date>
        <item>Converted to EAD</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>Department of Physics Records<date normal="1915/1971" type="inclusive">1915-1971</date></titleproper>
      <publisher>
			</publisher>
      <date type="publication">Copyright 2015 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      <p>For reference queries contact Grenander Department Reference staff or (518)-437-3934</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_ua628</unitid>
      <unittitle>Department of Physics Records<unitdate label="Date:" normal="1915/1971" type="inclusive">1915-1971</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">Records from the Department of Physics from the State College for Tearchers to the University at Albany, SUNY.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <corpname encodinganalog="110" source="local">State University of New York at Albany. Department of Physics</corpname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">2.0</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage:">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <phystech>
      <p>Web Archives</p>
    </phystech>
    <accessrestrict>
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict>
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites. </p>
      <p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks. </p>
      <p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future. </p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>These records were deposited in the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany. </p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Biographical History</head>
      <p>The Department of Physics at the State University of New York at Albany has a long history, the first courses being taught in Natural Philosophy in 1845. The establishment of the school as a four year liberal arts college in 1905 lead to an expansion of offerings in Physics, now including a General Course in Physics, Heat, Light, and Sound, and Electricity and Magnetism, but still taught by a Professor of Natural Science, Professor Wetmore, and located in the Department of Physical Sciences. The first Professor of Physics, Dr. Clarence Frederick Hale, was appointed in May 1911. In 1913 a separate Department of Physics was formed. A Minor in Physics was made available in 1916.</p>
      <p>Graduate education was introduced in 1913. In 1962 the Masters Program in Physics was opened for the first time to all students. A Ph.D. was first offered in the fall of 1965. David Peak received the first Ph.D. degree in 1970 with his dissertation titled Foundation of Gauge Theory. The honors program for Physics was first listed in the 1981-82 Undergraduate Bulletin. The combined B.S./M.S. program was first listed in the 1983-84 Undergraduate Bulletin. In 1988 the 3-2 program for engineering was introduced, allowing students to spend their first three years at the University at Albany, and spend the next two years at either RPI, Clarkson University, SUNY New Paltz, or Binghamton University. Students who complete this program are awarded B.S. degrees in Physics from Albany and Engineering from the engineering school of their choice.</p>
      <p>Today the Department of Physics offers a variety of programs. Undergraduates can obtain a Bachelor of Science degree in physics or teacher education, while graduate students can receive a Master of Science degree in physics or teacher education. Prospective undergraduate students with plans of continuing their education can take the B.S./M.S. combination program. An honors program and a 3-2 program in which students can split their education between SUNY Albany and one of four other schools known for engineering are also available. A Doctor of Philosophy degree can be obtained as well. Undergraduate students are prepared either to undertake graduate study in physics, to apply physics principles and techniques successfully for advanced work in other disciplines, to enter industry usefully, or to teach in the secondary schools. Along with courses in classical mechanics, electromagnetic theory, atomic and nuclear physics, and thermal physics, students learn modern experimental techniques, principles of quantum mechanics, and applications. UAlbany physics grad students have the opportunity to do creative research in areas ranging from the forefront of particle physics to unexpected applications of condensed matter science.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>The collection includes inventories, 1915-65; publications; and reports.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Department of Physics Records, 1915-1971. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University  Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Department of Physics Records).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">State University of New York at Albany. Department of Physics.</corpname>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Physics -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- New York (State)</subject>
      <genreform source="meg" encodinganalog="655">Web Archives</genreform>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="nam_ua628-1" level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>nam_ua628-1</unitid>
          <unittitle>Web Archives</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1997-06-07/2016-09-18">1997 June 7-2016 September 18</unitdate>
          <physdesc>
            <extent unit="captures">732</extent>
          </physdesc>
        </did>
        <acqinfo>
          <p>Web crawling is managed through the Internet Archive's Archive-It service. This page includes links to both the university's collection and the Internet Archive's public collection.</p>
          <p>Surface-level crawling of www.albany.edu is performed daily which should includes most top-level webpages. Separate targeted crawls of every albany.edu subdomain are performed monthly to attempt to gather all content. This includes: www.albany.edu, www.rna.albany.edu, www.ctg.albany.edu, www.ualbanysports.com, www.albany.edu/rockefeller, www.albany.edu/cela, www.albany.edu/asrc, m.albany.edu,	library.albany.edu,	events.albany.edu,	cstar.cestm.albany.edu, csda.albany.edu, and alumni.albany.edu</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <phystech>
          <p>Web Archives</p>
        </phystech>
        <c02 id="nam_ua628-1_1">
          <did>
            <container type="Web-Archive">1</container>
            <unittitle>http://www.albany.edu/physics/ - University Archives collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2013-05-08/2016-09-18">2013 May 8-2016 September 18</unitdate>
            <dao actuate="onrequest" linktype="simple" show="new" href="http://wayback.archive-it.org/3308/*/http://www.albany.edu/physics/"/>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="nam_ua628-1_2">
          <did>
            <container type="WARC">1</container>
            <unittitle>WARC file for http://www.albany.edu/physics/, (please see https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_ARChive for more details)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2013-05-08/2016-09-18">2013 May 8-2016 September 18</unitdate>
          </did>
          <accessrestrict>
            <p>WARC files are very large and difficult to work with. Your request may take time to process, and we may be unable to deliver your request remotely. Please consult an archivist if you are interested in researching with web archives.</p>
          </accessrestrict>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="nam_ua628-1_3">
          <did>
            <container type="Web-Archive">2</container>
            <unittitle>http://www.albany.edu/physics/ - Internet Archive collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1997-06-07/2016-09-18">1997 June 7-2016 September 18</unitdate>
            <dao actuate="onrequest" linktype="simple" show="new" href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.albany.edu/physics/"/>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
