<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='collection-level.xsl'?> 
<!DOCTYPE ead SYSTEM 'ead.dtd'>
<ead id="nam_ua627">
  <eadheader audience="external" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="##" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/ua627.html">nam_ua627</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>DEPARTMENT OF MATHEMATICS AND STATISTICS (UA627)<date normal="1936/1987" type="inclusive">1936-1987</date></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="2017" type="publication">Copyright 2017 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Benjamin Covell<date normal="2017-02-23">2017 February 23</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>Department of Mathematics and Statistics<date normal="1936/1987" type="inclusive">1936-1987</date></titleproper>
      <publisher/>
      <date type="publication">Copyright 2017 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
      <p>For reference queries contact Grenander Department Reference staff or (518)-437-3934</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unitid>nam_ua627</unitid>
      <unittitle>Department of Mathematics and Statistics<unitdate label="Date:" normal="1936/1987" type="inclusive">1936-1987</unitdate></unittitle>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">Contains inactive records from the Department of Mathematics and Statistics, including faculty research and publications, departmental correspondence, course materials, and planning and policy documentation.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination>
        <corpname encodinganalog="110" source="local">State University of New York at Albany. Department of Mathematics</corpname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc>
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">11</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physloc label="Storage:">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <repository label="Repository:">
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
      </repository>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict><head>Access</head><p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p></accessrestrict>
    <userestrict><head>Copyright</head><p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p></userestrict>
    <acqinfo>
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist>
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>The Department of Mathematics was one of the original departments created at the New York State Normal College.  The first graduate degrees in mathematics were offered in 1962.  As of 1978 it was retitled the Department of Mathematics and Statistics.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <head>Scope and Content Information</head>
      <p>Materials in this collection include: faculty files (research materials, publications, fellowship applications, correspondence); Departmental correspondence; annual reports and departmental activity reports; program descriptions and revisions; course materials (syllabi and exams); space planning documentation; faculty salary and workload analyses; grand proposals and reports; curriculum changes; Ph.D. qualifying exams and Masters comprehensive exams; fliers for colloquia; and graduate theses.  The bulk of the material dates from 1960 to 1980.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite>
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Department of Mathematics and Statistics, 1936-1987. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University  Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Department of Mathematics and Statistics).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <corpname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="610">State University of New York at Albany</corpname>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Education, Higher--Administration</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Mathematics</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Mathematics--Study and teaching</subject>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">syllabi</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">curricula</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">theses</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">faculty papers</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">correspondence</genreform>
    </controlaccess>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
