<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" id="ua902.086">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ua902.086.xml">ua902.086</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Langer, Judith; Papers <num>ua902.086</num></titleproper>
        <author>unprocessed</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2016</date>
        </p>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-05-04 23:34:01 -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2016 November 23</date>
        <item>Encoded in EAD by Gregory Wiedeman</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Judith Langer Papers<unitdate normal="1970/2010" type="inclusive">1970-2010</unitdate></unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname source="lcsh">Langer, Judith A.</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>ua902.086</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 cubic ft.</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract id="aspace_2ef7b822ff44e8a45af07e2ca3e2e869">Office papers of education and literacy scholar Judith Langer who directed the Center on English Learning and Achievement (CELA).</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_d3c947cabe4c7283e36029f84e07531e">English</langmaterial>
      <physloc id="aspace_96028d4a55f01cff3a432228ee68cfd2">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <container id="aspace_e9276eff441bf91bd89264208afd5389" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
    </did>
    <processinfo id="aspace_bffa9e76f4867a788b5403290865c4ac">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed in 2016 by unprocessed.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_d4bf24520c86c54ff980921b798466b8">
      <head>Access</head>
      <p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_0879f15107bec0731d4e5710c1325c98">
      <head>Copyright</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
      <p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
      <p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_df019a37d9835fb3ca9b7f17ba06d06e">
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Judith Langer though the Department of Education.<date normal="2016-11">2016 November</date></p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_bc506793e0584b550689eb598f186fe3">
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>Langer is a Distinguished Professor at the University at Albany, SUNY and founder and director of the Albany Institute for Research in Education and director of the Center on English Learning and Achievement. Her research focused on literacy education and influenced assessment policy both in the United States and abroad.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_d53c660d15bba22d5d2a7f6aefcb00a7">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>This collection includes unique materials from Langer's campus office, including literacy assessment tools, government-funded reports and some correspondence with publishers and other researchers.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_199adc4db4bd49349277fd86f8d06ab2">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite id="aspace_19057b107d4dd220b05e4c947abc113f">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Judith Langer Papers, 1970-2010. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Judith Langer Papers).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="meg">Education</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Education--Literary collections</subject>
      <subject source="meg">UAlbany Faculty &amp; Alumni Papers</subject>
      <corpname source="local">Center on English Learning and Achievement (U.S.)</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc/>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
