<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" id="ua902.089">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>ua902.089</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Robbins, Cornelius; Papers <num>ua902.089</num></titleproper>
        <author>Miles Lawlor</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2018</date>
        </p>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-02-02 23:00:12 -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2018</date>
        <item>Book of student grades and documents related to salary and health insurance removed and shredded by Miles Lawlor.</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Cornelius Robbins Papers<unitdate normal="1979/2006" type="inclusive">1979-2006</unitdate></unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname source="lcsh">Robbins, Cornelius V., 1931-2013</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>ua902.089</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent unit="cubic ft.">1</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract id="aspace_5977a6010bc92dfa6bbaf0ac83e306df">A long-time administrator at two-year and four-year colleges throughout the Northeast, Robbins was employed from 1992 through 2008 as a professor in the Department of Educational Administration at the State University of New York at Albany.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_561063d23ffce145820bfa13a530782b">English</langmaterial>
      <physloc id="aspace_33802046c80c4acbb11e0daf5f53a901">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
      <container id="aspace_129faf838bd4e382d170bc0f241ec612" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container>
    </did>
    <arrangement id="aspace_b05ab00b0273d56efac3202e3e17e04e">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>Collection was maintained in the original order after it was transferred.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <bioghist id="aspace_442699bab93c52f0fd1ba3ae25c611a4">
      <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
      <p>Cornelius "Neal" Robbins was a faculty member in the Department of Educational Administration at the University at Albany, SUNY between 1992 and 2008.  Before coming to Albany Robbins was a long-time administrator at colleges throughout the Northeast, including both two- and four-year institutions. He served as President of several different institutions, including Genessee Community College from 1970 through 1975 and SUNY Cobleskill between 1985 and 1992.  As a professor at UAlbany, his main areas of academic focus were in Educational Administration and Community College Management.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <processinfo id="aspace_37ca3da6d87783b1ace9926fc7800486">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed in 2018 by Miles Lawlor.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_7fe9e38d0f98a4c9ab5b07874677a159">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>Papers focus on Robbins work related to community colleges, including brochures and newsletters from various community college organizations, an oral history of SUNY's community colleges and a student proposal for a Saratoga County Community College delivered for a class he taught in 1993.  Department of Educational Administration documents are included, such as course syllabi, faculty directories and faculty activity reports.  Also contain information on a trip to Taiwan taken before his arrival at UAlbany, including his requests for leave time, his writings on the trip and a slideshow collection.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_19b0779d554a4090259a61255759ae35">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
      <p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_5cca0985334cfdefdf3c174ca1cb1ca4">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_d6beefd4f32d1a7c87187e92df1092fa">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
      <p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
      <p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
      <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
      <p>The M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collection and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_4ee05ecc7b265fa6bdd512729042a38b">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Cornelius Robbins Papers, 1979-2006. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Robbins Papers).</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="local">Higher Education Administration</subject>
      <subject source="meg">UAlbany Faculty &amp; Alumni Papers</subject>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc/>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
