<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='collection-level.xsl'?> 
<!DOCTYPE ead SYSTEM 'ead.dtd'>
<ead id="nam_ua902.065">
	<eadheader audience="external" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
		<eadid countrycode="US" identifier="##" mainagencycode="nalsu" url="http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/findaids/eresources/findingaids/ua902.065.html">nam_ua902.065</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper>DUNCAN BLANCHARD PAPERS (UA902.065)<date normal="1789/2003" type="inclusive">1789-2003</date>
				</titleproper>
				<author>Samantha Brown</author>
			</titlestmt>
			<publicationstmt>
				<publisher>M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives</publisher>
				<address>
					<addressline>1400 Washington Avenue / Albany, New York 12222</addressline>
				</address>
				<date normal="2016" type="publication">Copyright 2016 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
			</publicationstmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Samantha Brown<date normal="2013">2013</date>
			</creation>
			<langusage>
				<language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
			</langusage>
		</profiledesc>
		<revisiondesc>
			<change>
				<date normal="2006-02">2006 February</date>
				<item>Finding aid updated to current standards</item>
			</change>
		</revisiondesc>
	</eadheader>
	<frontmatter>
		<titlepage>
			<titleproper>Duncan Blanchard Papers<date normal="1789/2003" type="inclusive">1789-2003</date>
			</titleproper>
			<publisher/>
			<date type="publication">Copyright 2016 By the University at Albany, SUNY. All rights reserved.</date>
			<p>For reference queries contact Grenander Department Reference staff or (518)-437-3934</p>
		</titlepage>
	</frontmatter>
	<archdesc level="collection">
		<did>
			<head>Descriptive Summary</head>
			<unitid>nam_ua902.065</unitid>
			<unittitle>Duncan Blanchard Papers<unitdate label="Date:" normal="1789/2003" type="inclusive">1789-2003</unitdate>
			</unittitle>
			<abstract label="Abstract:">The Duncan Blanchard papers document Blanchard’s career as a research associate at the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute and as a senior research associate at the State University of New York at Albany.</abstract>
			<langmaterial>
				<language langcode="eng">English</language>
			</langmaterial>
			<origination>
				<persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcsh">Blanchard, Duncan C.</persname>
			</origination>
			<physdesc>
				<extent unit="cubic ft.">35.8</extent>
			</physdesc>
			<physloc label="Storage:">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
			<repository label="Repository:">
				<corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local">M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY</corpname>
			</repository>
		</did>
		<accessrestrict>
			<head>Access</head><p>Access to this collection is unrestricted with the exception of select folders that are  marked on the inventory. Researchers with inquiries about this material should consult and archivist.</p><p>Red asterisks (***) denote restricted items.</p>
		</accessrestrict>
		<userestrict>
			<head>Copyright</head><p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
		</userestrict>
		<acqinfo>
			<head>Acquisition Information</head>
			<p>The Duncan Blanchard papers were donated to M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Duncan Blanchard in 2002 with additional donations made in 2003 and 2004.<date normal="2002/2004">2002-2004</date>
			</p>
		</acqinfo>
		<bioghist>
			<head>Biographical Sketch</head><p>Duncan Cromwell Blanchard was born on October 8, 1924 in Winter Haven, Florida. Soon 
        after his birth, his family moved to the small Berkshire community of New Lenox, 
        Massachusetts where he spent most of his childhood exploring the surrounding area. 
        Despite his curiosity about the world around him, Blanchard never dreamed of becoming a 
        scientist. His teacher at the one-room school house very rarely mentioned scientists or their work 
        and instead dreamed of becoming a commercial artist.</p>
			<p>In 1942 Dr. Blanchard graduated high school and though he dreamed of attending art school 
        or college, these dreams were put on hold due to the war. Instead, Blanchard took a job
        with General Electric in Pittsfield, Massachusetts as an apprentice machinist. After a year, he decided 
        to leave G.E. and took the admittance examine for the Navy’s V-12 Officer Candidate Program. Within the exam, 
        students were instructed to choose three schools from a provided list that they would like to attend for Officer 
        training. Dr. Blanchard’s list consisted of Harvard, Yale, and Princeton and, after passing the exam, was sent to Harvard. 
        After completing his training at Harvard, the Navy then sent him to Tuft’s where they told him to study mechanical 
        engineering and naval science. </p>
			<p>Once his training was complete, in 1945, Blanchard received orders to report to the Anti-Aircraft Training
        center on the island of Guam. Despite enjoying his time in Guam, Dr. Blanchard felt like he was missing something.
        He realized what was missing when he started to read <emph render="italic">Great Men of Science</emph>
        by Grove Wilson. Reading this book allowed him to learn about all the great scientists and showed him what he truly 
        wanted to do with his life. With this new knowledge, Blanchard quickly left the navy and returned to Tufts where he 
        earned a Bachelor in Naval Science in 1945 and a Bachelor in Engineering in 1947.</p>
			<p>After receiving his degrees from Tufts, Blanchard went to work for General Electric Research Laboratory in 
        Schenectady, New York.  His first position was in the Physics Test Program but in 1948 he was reassigned to 
        Project Cirrus where he worked as research assistant. Through his work with Project Cirrus, Blanchard came to
        know Irving Langmuir, Vincent Schaefer, and Bernard Vonnegut.</p>
			<p>While Blanchard enjoyed working at G.E., he left them in 1949 to return to graduate school at Penn. State University. 
          That same year he returned to G.E. to participate in a graduate fellowship. In 1951, Blanchard graduated from Penn. 
          State with a Masters in Physics and joined the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution. While working at the Woods Hole
          Institute, Blanchard served as a Research Associate from 1951-1963, and as an Associate Scientist from 1963-1968. 
          During that time, he held a Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution Associates Fellowship from 1956-1958 and received his PhD
          from MIT in Atmospheric Science. Along with this work, Blanchard also served as a member of the Panel on Air-Sea 
          Interactions for the National Academy of Sciences from 1963 to 1966. At Woods Hole Blanchard’s research interests focused
          on raindrop size, shape, stability and distribution in rain; basic mechanisms of the formation of “warm” rain; freezing 
          phenomena; air-sea interaction with respect to the transfer of particulate matter and electrical charge; dynamics of 
          collapsed bubbles in water; evolution of condensation nuclei from the sea; organic films on the sea and transport to the
          atmosphere; atmospheric and volcanic electricity; and the history of science.</p>
			<p>In 1968 Blanchard rejoined Project Cirrus scientists Vincent Schaefer and Bernard Vonnegut as a senior research associate 
          at the Atmospheric Science Research Center at the State University of New York at Albany. Besides Dr. Blanchard's research
          responsibilities, he also served as a professor in the Department of Atmospheric Sciences at SUNYA and was a member of number of 
          professional organization such as the American Meteorological Society, the Electrostatics Society of America, and the 
          American Association for the Advancement of Science. He continued to maintain close working relations with Leonard Woodcock, 
          a colleague at Woods Hole, who later moved to the University of Hawaii.</p>
			<p>Througout his career, Dr. Blanchard was a prolific author. He published numerous scientific papers, technical reports, 
            and articles. Along with that work, he also created educational films for the general public.He retired from SUNYA in 
            November 1989 but continues to write. After his retirement, he published <emph render="italic">The Snowflake Man: a Biography
            of Wilson A. Bentley</emph> in 1998 and continued to write articles for the Wilson Bentley Newsletter up until March 2012.</p>
		</bioghist>
		<scopecontent>
			<head>Scope and Content Information</head><p>Dr. Blanchard’s papers document his career as a research associate at the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute and the
        State University of New York at Albany. The collection contains materials ranging from 1789 to 2003 with the bulk being
        from 1958 to 1989. The earliest materials in the collection are reprints of articles that he referenced for his research.</p>
			<p>While some correspondence contains information about his personal life, the collection is focused on his professional 
        career and research. Included in the collection are handwritten and typed notes, notebooks, journal articles, newspaper 
        and magazine clippings, brochures, pamphlets,  bulletins, memos, reports, correspondence, invitations, event programs, 
        postcards, photographs, negatives, projection slides, drawings, graphs, figures, research data, drafts, rosters, applications,
        proposals, resumes, class outlines, grant outlines, and grant abstracts.</p>
			<p>The documents are arranged in 4 series. Series 1 is arranged numerically while the remaining 3 series are arranged 
        alphabetically. The series were arranged in this way to preserve Dr. Blanchard’s own arrangement scheme. Along with 
        maintaining his arrangement scheme, his folder titles were also preserved. Folder titles were only changed if clarification 
        was needed and some folders include dates that are in brackets. These bracketed dates reflect the dates that Dr. Blanchard 
        assigned to the folders based on the date the material was published or presented at a meeting or conference. </p> 
			<p>For related materials, please see the following collections held by the ME Grenander Department of Special Collection and 
        Archives: Atmospheric Sciences Research Center Records (UA450), which includes many publications and articles issued by the ASRC, Bernard Vonnegut (UA902.068), Raymond Falconer Papers (U-902.014) and Vincent J. Schaefer (UA902.010).</p>
		</scopecontent>
		<separatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 0">
			<p>Archivists transfered the monographs <title>
					<emph render="italic">Summary of Weather Modification 
      Activities Reported in 1979</emph>
				</title>, <title>
					<emph render="italic">Weather Modification: Eighth
      Annual Report, 1966 </emph>
				</title>, <title>
					<emph render="italic">Weather Modification: Tenth Annual
      Report, 1968 </emph>
				</title>, <title>
					<emph render="italic"> Weather Modifiction: Some Facts About
      Seeding Clouds</emph>
				</title>, <title>
					<emph render="italic">Weather Modificayopm in the Soviet Union,
      1946-1966; A Selected Bibliography</emph>
				</title>, <title>
					<emph render="italic">Weather Modification:
      Law, Controls, Operations: A Survey of Responses to Questionaires of the Special Commission on Weather
      Modification of the National Sceince Foundation by States, Research and Experimental Organizations, 
      Commercial Operators, and Federal Agencies</emph>
				</title> and <title>
					<emph render="italic">Weather
      and Climate Modification: Report of the Special Commission on Weather Modification</emph>
				</title>
      to the book division of Special Collections. The catalog records for these monographs is included 
      in Minerva, the University Library Catalog.</p>
		</separatedmaterial>
		<arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
			<head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
			<p>The collection is arranged in to four topical series.</p>
		</arrangement>
		<prefercite>
			<head>Preferred Citation</head>
			<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
			<p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Duncan Blanchard Papers, 1789-2003. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University  Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Duncan Blanchard Papers).</p>
		</prefercite>
		<controlaccess>
			<head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
			<persname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="600">Blanchard, Duncan C.</persname>
			<persname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="600">Hughes, Jim</persname>
			<persname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="600">Moore, A. D.</persname>
			<persname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="600">Moore, Charles B., 1920-2010</persname>
			<persname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="600">Schaefer, Vincent J.</persname>
			<persname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="600">Vonnegut, Bernard</persname>
			<persname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="600">Woodcock, Alfred H.</persname>
			<corpname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="610">General Electric Company</corpname>
			<corpname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="610">State University of New York. Atmospheric Sciences Research Center</corpname>
			<corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution</corpname>
			<corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">National Science Foundation (U.S.)</corpname>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Aerosols</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Air--Microbiology</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Atmospheric electricity</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Atmospheric physics</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Bubbles</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Cloud physics</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Drops</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Electrostatics</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">History of science and technology</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lightning</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Ocean-atmosphere interaction</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Rain and rainfall. </subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Surface chemistry</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Thunderstorm electricity</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Volcanoes--Costa Rica</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Volcanoes--Iceland</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Volcanoes--Hawaii</subject>
			<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="tgn">Albany (N.Y.)</geogname>
			<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="tgn">Surtsey (island)</geogname>
			<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Hilo (Hawaii)</geogname>
			<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Irazú Volcano (Costa Rica)</geogname>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Administrative reports</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Brochures</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Charts</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Drafts (documents)</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Field Notes</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Laboratory Notes</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Lecture Notes</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Manuscripts (document genre)</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Negatives (photographic)</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Newsletters</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Newspaper clippings</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Notebooks</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Pamphlets</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Postcards</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Research notes</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Résumés (personnel records)</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Rosters</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Slides (photographs)</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Technical reports</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Transparencies</genreform>
			<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Video recordings</genreform>
		</controlaccess>
		<dsc>
			<head>Container List</head>
			<c01 level="series" id="nam_ua902.065-1">
				<did>
					<unitid>1</unitid>
					<unittitle label="Series">Manuscripts</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1789/2003">1789-2003</unitdate>
					<physdesc>
						<extent unit="cubic ft.">9.8</extent>
					</physdesc>
				</did>
				<accessrestrict>
					<p>Any folders that contain personally identifying information are restricted.</p>
				</accessrestrict>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Series 1 contains materials Dr. Blanchard published while at Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute
            and the State University of New York at Albany as well as after his retirement. The topics covered
            by these publications include the history of science, water-to-air transfer, aerobiology, sea salt
            aerosols, volcanic electricity, and surface charge. There are also materials covering his studies of
            bubbles, water droplets, and rain. Along with his scientific publications, Dr. Blanchard also wrote 
            letters to editors, comments and replies to articles, book reviews, obituaries, and autobiographical 
            articles. Dr. Blanchard published materials from the early 1950s to the early 2000s but the majority 
            of materials in are from 1960s, 1970s, and 1980s.</p>
					<p>Included in the series are notes (handwritten and typed), notebooks, journal articles, newspaper and
            magazine clippings, brochures, bulletins, reports, correspondence, photographs, negatives, figures, 
            data (handwritten), drawings, graphs, drafts, rosters, completed application and record forms, and resumes.  
            Folders are arranged according to Dr. Blanchard’s own filing system with the exception that materials are 
            arranged by the date of the materials included in the folder instead of the date the articles were published.  
            Dr. Blanchard’s folder titles were also maintained unless further clarification was needed.</p>
				</scopecontent>
				<arrangement>
					<p>Arranged numerically.</p>
				</arrangement>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="series" id="nam_ua902.065-2">
				<did>
					<unitid>2</unitid>
					<unittitle label="Series">Research Materials</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1943/2002">1943-2002</unitdate>
					<physdesc>
						<extent unit="cubic ft.">14.4</extent>
					</physdesc>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Series 2 documents the research Dr. Blanchard conducted while he was working at the Woods Hole Oceanographic 
            Institute and the State University of New York at Albany.  The work that he did while at General Electric is 
            mentioned but not specifically covered. The main focus of Dr. Blanchard’s research was on the nature of bubbles and 
            water drops but he also conduct studies on volcanic electricity and its effects. To conduct this research, he travelled
            throughout the Northeast and Hawaii. Along with the research he did in the United States, Dr. Blanchard also traveled 
            internationally to collected data. A large part of his international research was done around Surtsey Volcano in Iceland.</p>
					<p>The documents included in this series are photographs, projection slides, negatives, newspaper and magazine clippings, 
            journal articles, correspondence, journals, notes (both handwritten and typed), graphs, figures, drawings, and data 
            (both printouts and handwritten). Folders are arranged and titled to reflect Dr. Blanchard’s own arrangement scheme. To 
            help maintain his arrangement, the series is sub-divided into titled sections. Since all the sections are related to one
            topic, they have not been divided into sub-series. Along with this, many of the folders have the same titles that 
            Dr. Blanchard used in his own filing. The titles were only changed if they were redundant and did not provide the researcher
            with a clearer understanding of what the folder contained.</p>
				</scopecontent>
				<arrangement>
					<p>Arranged alphabetically.</p>
				</arrangement>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="series" id="nam_ua902.065-3">
				<did>
					<unitid>3</unitid>
					<unittitle label="Series">Correspondence</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1900/2003">1900-2003</unitdate>
					<physdesc>
						<extent unit="cubic ft.">7.8</extent>
					</physdesc>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Series 3 focus on Dr. Blanchard’s personal and professional correspondence while he was working professionally as well
            as when he retired. The majority of correspondence was exchanged between Dr. Blanchard and his colleagues and discusses
            manuscripts or research. The series contains handwritten and typed letters, postcards, manuscripts, newspaper clippings,
            journal articles, brochures, memos, handwritten notes, figures, photographs, and reports. Please note that not all of the
            files contain correspondence directly between Dr. Blanchard and the person the folder is named after. Some folders contain
            letters sent to Dr. Blanchard from the person’s family members or letters sent to that person from another source.</p>
				</scopecontent>
				<arrangement>
					<p>Arranged alphabetically.</p>
				</arrangement>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="series" id="nam_ua902.065-4">
				<did>
					<unitid>4</unitid>
					<unittitle label="Series">Subject Files</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1926/2003">1926-2003</unitdate>
					<physdesc>
						<extent unit="cubic ft.">3.8</extent>
					</physdesc>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Series 4 documents Dr. Blanchard’s professional activities from his time at the University of New York at Albany.  
            While materials from the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute are also included, they make up a smaller part of the series.
            The focus of the materials is on grant applications, meetings and conferences, and classes Dr. Blanchard taught.</p>
					<p>The materials included in the series are photographs, negatives, correspondence, postcards, invitations, event programs,
            pamphlets, brochures, newspaper and magazine clippings, journal articles, notes (handwritten and typed), drafts, figures, 
            class outlines, grant applications and proposals, proposal evaluations, memos, grant outlines, grant account abstracts, 
            and reports.</p> 
					<p>Folder names reflect Dr. Blanchard’s own naming system but arrangement has been changed to allow for easier use.</p>
				</scopecontent>
				<arrangement>
					<p>Arranged alphabetically.</p>
				</arrangement>
			</c01>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>
