<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ger009</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Tischler, Hans; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>Tischler, Hans; Papers <num>ger009</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.
Processed by unprocessed. </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-09-29 00:18:23 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Hans Tischler Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>ger009</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.5 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1935/1982" type="inclusive">1935-1982</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_bcb4559716205fa1b99dca0a76a9ea92">Hans Tischler was an Austrian born musicologist who held doctorates in Musicology (Vienna University, 1937) and Yale University (1942). This collection contains publication and essays, musical scores, correspondence, and research notes.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_0755bd8326cd99767919caad7ece1606">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="ger" scriptcode="Latn">German</language>
,       <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_27157a94512176a1a18cdd20036f05f6" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_3fc68d0517edc7048118f0381ebfecfe">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_c5ffe1bf99cb0c8c129922bcdbf7ceeb">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>
Hans Tischler, musicologist, was born in Vienna, Austria, on January 18, 1915 to Joachim and Grete Spitz Tischler. In 1938 he married the pianist and musicologist Louise Hochdorf who died in 1957. One year later he married the organist and music librarian Alice Bock. In 1933, having studied with Eduard Steuermann, Bertha Jahn-Beer, and Paul Wittgenstein, he received a Piano Pedagogy Diploma from the Vienna State Academy of Music, and then Master's degrees in Conducting under Oswald Kabasta and Composition under Franz Schmidt, respectively in 1935 and 1936. He earned his first Ph.D. in Musicology from the University of Vienna in 1937, under Robert Haas, Robert Lach, Leopold Novak, Alfred Orel and Egon Wellesz, with a dissertation entitled Die Harmonik in den Werken Gustav Mahlers (Harmony in the Works of Gustav Mahler). A second Ph.D., from Yale University, under Paul Hindemith and Leo Schrade, followed in 1942, with a dissertation, The Motet in 13th-Century France.</p><p>Hans Tischler began his professional career in 1938, doing conducting research at the British Museum for Gustave Reese's book, Music in the Middle Ages. After several years as piano teacher and pianist in Bridgeport, Connecticut, and service in the U.S. Army (1943-1945), he became Professor of Piano and Music History and Head of the Music Department at West Virginia Wesleyan College (1945-1947). From 1947-1965 he was Associate Professor of Music History at Roosevelt University in Chicago, where he founded a chapter of the International Society for Contempory Music. During his time in Chicago, he also guest-taught at the University of Chicago and at several universities abroad, and he began a long career of publishing books and articles. In 1965 he accepted the position of Professor of Musicology at Indiana University, Bloomington.</p><p>As Professor Emeritus since 1985, Dr. Tischler continued his research and publication, concentrating primarily on the music of the late 12th and 13th centuries. Since about 1950 he  published some fifteen books and multi-volume editions as well as about 80 shorter studies. They ranged from a volume of analyses of Mozart's Piano Concertos (1966) to a 15-volume edition of the songs of the 12th–13th century trouvères (1997). Other titles were: The Montpellier Codex (3 vols., 1979), The Earliest Motets (3 vols., 1982), The Parisian Two-Part Organa (2 vols., 1988), and The Parisian 2-Part Conductus (2 vols., 2005). His articles appeared in The Musical Quarterly, Journal of the Musicological Society, Music and Letters, Acta Musicologica, Die Musikforschung, Orbis Musicae, Revue Belge de Musicologie, etc. These studies range from medieval music to Mendelssohn, Bruckner, Mahler, Hindemith, and Samuel Barber.</p><p>Hans Tischler received several honors for his work, including grants from the American Philosophical Society in 1955, 1962, and 1965, a Guggenheim Fellowship for 1964-1965; grants by the Chapelbrook Foundation (1965, 1969), an editorial grant and a fellowship from the National Endowment for the Humanities (1971, 1975-6). He belonged to the American and International Musicological Societies, was an honorary member of the Austrian Musicological Society, was the President of the Midwest Chapter of the American Musicological Society, and was a member of the Mediaeval Academy of America and the Medieval Association of the Midwest (past president). He is listed in many reference works, such as Grove's Dictionary of Music and Musicians, Who's Who in America, Who's Who in American Education, Who's Who in Music, Who's Who in Austria, International Who's Who in Music, and Dictionary of International Biography. </p><p>Tischler died on November 18, 2010 in Bloomington, Indiana.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_0d84731a1ce055e86326da99b9e51ebc">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains publication and essays, musical scores, correspondence, and research notes. Tischler's musical compositions are represented in the collection, as is his correspondence with colleagues at other college and university music departments throughout the United States, Europe, and Israel. Notable correspondents are linguist Samuel Rosenberg; musicologists Jurg Stenz and Israel Katz, and Bach scholar Gerhard Herz. This collection also contains a series of letters between Tischler and Gwynn McPeek of the University of Michigan at Ann Arbor, written throughout 1973, detailing a debate regarding the distinction between modes and scales in medieval music.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_04c9d323c839a52b9003709880d8e1ed">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_7a61b8a1854b4df1ddc7bff1c2827fd7">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>The majority of the records were received from Hans Tischler in May 1977. Additional materials were donated by him in 1981 and 1983.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_f895d06f0a55bf8519336278b998a1c4">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_67e7409682da1d39526e2b2811daa06f">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_17e51fe04e840f8d8d64c654e97cedca">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Hans Tischler Papers, 1935-1982. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Tischler Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Tischler, Hans, 1915-2010</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">sheet music</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Research Notes</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
