<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ger035</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Fritz, Kurt von; Papers <num>ger035</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.
Processed by unprocessed. </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-04-20 23:00:06 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Fritz, Kurt von Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="lcsh">Fritz, Kurt von, 1900-1985	</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ger035</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.1 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1935/1980" type="inclusive">1935-1980</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_cb92d14a62e9b59b0a01e53515b615f4">Von Fritz was a professor of classics at the University of Munich and at Columbia University. This collection contains German autobiographical notes and materials, "Die Grund, die zu meiner Emigration", corrected copies of letters, and photograph, 1970-1980s. </abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_9a062f87351d25ad0a809e95ad456850">English and German. </langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_1b5b263e27e556d62d7abca13df41724">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_2b9d501caeba643f1c419e185d83fca3" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_00b668ae9f2a48a5ce53c079e41d4dad">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_11bda3a3a3f26790260d49f8feb1eed1">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Karl Albert Kurt von Fritz was born on August 25, 1900 in Metz, France. Fritz was educated at Freiburg im Bresigau and graduated high school in 1918. Fritz earned his doctorate from Sinope in 1923 and moved to Munich, Germany to study Democritus, a Greek philosopher and in 1933, he was appointed professorship at the University of Rostock. Fritz refused to take the oath of service to Adolf Hitler in 1934 and was forced to retire. </p><p>In 1936, Fritz went to Oxford and lectured at the Corpus Christi College and later that year he moved to the United States where he taught at Reed College, in Portland Oregon. Fritz then taught at Columbia University until he went back to Germany where he taught at the University of Munich from 1958-1968. While teaching, Fritz wrote publications on Greek philosophy, science, and literature. </p><p>Fritz was a member of the Bavarian Academy of the Sciences and the Austrian Academy of the Sciences. Fritz also received the Sigmund Freud Prize from the German Academy for Language and Poetry in 1981. Fritz was married to Luise Elckemeyer and died on July 16, 1985 in Feldafing, Germany. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_d9f581edb1a9e2fe9bd4ca18f2d3e630">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains German autobiographical notes and materials, "Die Grund, die zu meiner Emigration", corrected copies of letters, and photograph, 1970-1980s. Von Fritz was a professor of classics at the University of Munich and at Columbia University.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_f7d00c0925b84f65ba07b2ea355174d5">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_b4bb5db6c40fe26a387816fe0049eb48">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>This collection was donated.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_ffa92a76becb037a0888c309009d6b9f">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_86c8e9cde52a0bfb70da469a328d8c41">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_a3a75d6668c8034e28107e8abf831320">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Kurt Von Fritz, 1935-1980. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Fritz Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Fritz, Kurt von, 1900-1985	</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Autobiographies</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Exiles -- Germany.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Exiles' writings, German.</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
