<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ger099</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Wolff, Victoria; Manuscript <num>ger099</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.
Processed by unprocessed.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-04-21 13:35:54 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Wolff, Victoria Manuscript</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="lcsh">Wolff, Victoria, 1903-1992</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ger099</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Vol.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">1973</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_f665125f7d71d46a089b6e1b306b96be">Wolff was born in Heilbronn, Germany in 1908. After moving to the United States, she was a screen writer and wrote film scripts for both 20th Century Fox and MGM, was a foreign correspondent for Madame and served as a contributor to Swiss and German magazines. This collection contains the manuscript "Hass Liebe Hollywood: Meine dreissig Jahre als Underhund."</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_3414e243b6205fd0052e45204b88bf0a">English.</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_e5a2d67c86b95888bb1491360e7e04d8">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_edb5aa368c30e45a424397aa9b2bf1ff" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_c045db4a1f581ec4472699acf6f0c7d4">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_028cded2a02b50ee9c780ed9f97b4cec">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Victoria Wolff was born in Heilbronn, Germany in 1908. After receiving her bachelor's dregree at the University of Munich (1929) and her master's degree at the University of Lausanne (1931), she moved to Switzerland and worked as a freelance writer. After moving to the United States, she was a screen writer and wrote film scripts for both 20th Century Fox and MGM, was a foreign correspondent for Madame and served as a contributor to Swiss and German magazines. Wolff died in 1992.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_68aad761086b01350d2c378e54c44ecb">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains the manuscript "Hass Liebe Hollywood: Meine dreissig Jahre als Underhund."</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_171cc6f306db2212b3fefbee89744bef">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_8ceb3d493f8d61ed687d76458534abaf">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>This collection was donated.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_aaaaf9cfe00af4386c369c8fda34245d">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_04b5cdd7808110622cdacdff719a5f52">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_dc8ad1a5ca2bd43a17a83c9d689a1082">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Victoria Wolff Papers, 1973. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Wolff Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Wolff, Victoria, 1903-1992</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Manuscript</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
