<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ger025.xml">ger025</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Manschinger, Kurt and Grete Hartwig; Papers <num>ger025</num></titleproper><author>unprocessed</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>1983 June</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-03-09 01:05:11 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2015 December</date><item>Converted to EAD</item></change><change><date>2015</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Jodi Boyle</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Greta Hartwig Manschinger and Kurt Manschinger (Ashley Vernon) Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="lcsh">Hartwig, Greta, 1899-1971</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ger025</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">20 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1912/1970" type="inclusive">1912-1970</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_883a6d949ead21d8e1643f03ae14fada">This collection includes artistic works and personal papers from Greta Hartwig and Kurt Manschinger as well as Mela Spira, Ms. Manschinger's sister.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_89997c7fa1fe0cba55e67ad5a6ff2291"><language langcode="eng">English</language> <language langcode="ger">German</language></langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_6b5b6f0c067590a518c7a0eff71fb33b">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_34807860ac05125da936ac6e14b37fa8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_59833050195a422bf6017f3a6f9c48be">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 1983 June by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_dadbb5354f35acca4b3b95aab14c4a5c">
    <head>Biographical History</head>
<p>Greta Hartwig Manschinger (18991971), writer and librettist for works composed by her husband Kurt Manschinger (also known as Ashley Vernon). Born in Austria, Manschinger lived in New York City.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_82619911dd4662f22afcbd9f9afbf510">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection includes correspondence, 1945-1968; manuscript of Greta's unfinished autobiographical novel "Brno-New York" and hand-corrected typescripts and manuscripts of novel sketches, opera librettos (English translations from German), songs, short stories, children's literature, advertising and media sketches, and critical reviews, 1935-1970; personal family papers of Kurt and Greta Manschinger; scores and sheet music by Kurt and Greta; audio tapes of performances; index card files of Manschinger music contacts; Manschinger Music Trust files. There also is artwork and personal papers from Greta Manschinger's sister Mela Spira (Melanie Hartwig) and her husband Robert.</p><p> Please contact the archivists for a more detailed inventory.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_a2f4ee2696c26130aba210f31ced54ec">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_b63242ab4a8e6723b4abc424a35429ca">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p><chronlist> <chronitem> <date normal="1983-03-13">1983 March 13</date> <event>The majority of items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by Wilbur Broms, Executor for the estates of Greta Hartwig Manschinger and Kurt Manschinger. </event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date normal="2006-03">2006 March</date> <event>Additional materials were added to the collection by Wilbur Broms.</event> </chronitem> </chronlist></p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_9cc5e905655310f9514365b291ac5630">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_4552ae76296c64d5466212455fb3812f">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites. </p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks. </p><p> The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_b0e341008bc6293600a750c885b6cd11">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Greta Hartwig Manschinger and Kurt Manschinger (Ashley Vernon) Papers, 1912-1970. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Manschinger Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">Music</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Literature</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- Refugees</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women authors</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Scores</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Poems</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Novels</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Short stories</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Essays</genreform>
    <persname source="lcsh">Hartwig, Greta, 1899-1971</persname>
    <persname source="lcsh">Vernon, Ashley</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
