<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ger048</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Kahler, Erich von; Papers <num>ger048</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.
Processed by unprocessed. </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-09-24 23:02:30 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Erich von Kahler Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>ger048</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">13 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1905/1970" type="inclusive">1905-1970</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_0565aeccbb5dc8732b37a7d3be541bb4">This collection contains diaries, 1906-1913; correspondence; corrected manuscripts of literary works by Hermann Broch, Golo Mann, and others, 1945-1970; lecture notes on philosophy of history; contemporary politics for lectures given in Germany and the United States; and 16 audio recordings of lectures, readings, and other presentations.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_cef3eb569760edfd2d46a74c64b4af00">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="ger" scriptcode="Latn">German</language>
,       <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_b1ae1d81f06d5601c8a00a0746be4a0a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_0fe926a7f76e4bff6d72c79a407de62b">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The Kahler Papers are not processed but a detailed ealier inventory is available for researchers who contact the department.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_75290526e4b3ad7f0365773ef948d857">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Erich Von Kahler was born on October 14, 1885 in Prague. Kahler studied at the University of Munich, the University of Berlin, the University of Heidelberg, and the University of Freiburg. Kahler received his doctorate from the University of Vienna in 1911. He was stripped of his German citizenship in 1933 because he was Jewish. Kahler eventually emigrated to the United States in 1938. He became a U.S. citizen in 1944.</p><p>Kahler taught at a variety of Universities in the United States including The New School, Black Mountain College, Cornell University, and Princeton University. Kahler was a member of the Institute for Advanced Study and wrote many books on politics, technology, and science. Kahler was married to Josephine Sobotka, and later to Alice (Lili) Loewy. Kahler died on June 28, 1970, in Princeton, New Jersey and was survived by his wife and stepdaughter. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_2f0ebcbf785576be693f34bdac449f4e">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Erich von Kahler was a German-American literary scholar and teacher. Kahler taught at the New School for Social Research, at Cornell University and Princeton University. This collection contains diaries, 1906-1913, correspondence in German and English with Hans Bethe, Richard BeerHofmann, Jacob Bronowski, Albert Einstein, Elizabeth Mann Borgese, Erich Fromm, Herbert Marcuse, J. Robert Oppenheimer, Kurt Wolff, and others, 1923-1970. This collection also includes corrected manuscripts of literary works by Hermann Broch, Golo Mann, and others, 1945-1970, lecture notes on philosophy of history, Jewish history, German literature, and contemporary politics for lectures given in Germany and the United States and for courses at Black Mountain College and Ohio State University, 1915-1968, and 16 audio recordings of lectures, readings, and other presentations.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_44f235d36886570b1889b4f0418f7dac">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Archivists previously arranged the collection into nine general series.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_7508d4c123c0acc4c195ca7e22cfd947">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>This majority of the collection was donated by Alice Loewy Kahler in the late 1970s with a small amount of material donated by Janit Roberts in 1991.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_578c31ab0a212ad2b48504ffd83c2a26">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is not fully processed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_5003151cb6672b9c08b02bf6b853fff0">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_9338fc4ae3ecdb5d02c9bcb998593035">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Erich Von Kahler Papers, 1905-1970. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Kahler Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Kahler, Erich, 1885-1970</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Diaries.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Manuscripts.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Lecture notes</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Jews -- Germany -- Berlin..</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Exiles -- Germany.</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
