<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ger037</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Furth, Otto; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>Furth, Otto; Papers <num>ger037</num></titleproper><author>Sandra Hunt Hawrylchak (June 2007)</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-10-17 23:00:05 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change><change><date>2022</date><item>David Abril Torres and Jodi Boyle converted to EAD</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Otto Furth Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>ger037</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1912/1986" type="inclusive">1912-1986</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_8f0f38a34d700dd292bb060f73518a93">This collection predominantly contains German and English manuscripts, plays, poetry, lectures, and articles in newspapers and magazines, 1933-1969. There is also correspondence with friends, writers and with Twentieth Century Fox pertaining to copyright infringement, 1940-1948. Otto Furth also wrote under the pseudonym Owen Elford.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_693ba1a0eba23f9553def59f4d9f17e3">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_c4e585cd8a88bc0d489e97ba26483bc7" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_de90429d935d94c26a0a502a7ebb5371">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Sandra Hunt Hawrylchak in 2007.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_edfe64dedab9a50370fb7d9ec70044df">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Otto Fürth was born in Strakonitz, Bohemia, Germany, on November 7, 1894 where he spent the first four years of his childhood. In 1899 his father, Hugo Fürth, relocated the family to Vienna, Austria where he opened a fez factory, the Aktiengesellschaft der Oesterreichischen Fezfabriken.</p>  

<p>Otto Fürth spent the next fifteen years of his life in Vienna, where he attended school and then university to study law, philosophy and literature. His university studies were interrupted by the onset of World War I and Fürth's enlistment in the army early in 1915. He was soon shipped to the Russian front, where he was eventually promoted to lieutenant of the artillery division. On July 4, 1916 he was captured and sent to Siberia, where he spent the next three and a half years. Fürth finally managed to escape with a friend and spent the next six years teaching French and German at a German school in Tientsin, China, until he was able to secure passage on a Danish ship headed for Copenhagen.</p>

<p>In 1920 Fürth finally returned to Vienna, where he finished his university degree during the next two years and took a position in the family factory. Fürth spent the next years in Vienna, married Gertrude Harteck in 1924, had daughter Irmgard (1926) and son Harald (1930), and continued to advance in his career. At the same time, he continued to write, a career he always considered secondary. Nonetheless, early in 1931 saw the first performance of his play "Der Mann ohne Privatleben" in the Deutsches Volkstheater, Vienna. Although this play achieved moderate success, traveled to a number of European theaters, and had the film rights purchased by Paramount, the most successful of Fürth's plays was the comedy "Zehn Gesichter gegen eins."</p>

<p>With the takeover of Austria by Hitler in 1938, Fürth immediately applied for visas to the United States for himself and his family. Not wishing to wait any longer in Vienna, in August 1939, Fürth took his family to Switzerland, where they stayed for the next year and a half. Finally on August 28, 1941, Fürth and his family arrived in New York harbor.</p>

<p>Fürth, with the aid of a relative, soon secured a position as an accountant for the Wall Street firm of Lazard Frères, a position which he held until his retirement in 1964. Fürth continued to write after his arrival in the United States. His one successful full-length novel, Men in Black (published in 1942 under the pseudonym Owen Elford), was first written in German and translated by Richard Winston into English.</p>

<p>Although Otto Fürth considered himself first and foremost a businessman, and a writer only as a pastime, his literary production consisted of numerous plays (mostly comedies), countless poems, newspaper articles, movie script ideas and one full-length published novel. Fürth died in New York on December 15, 1979.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_9dff2a3f8e558ae6b38dcb88da2ef716">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Although this collection contains some biographical materials, documents and correspondence, the bulk consists of Fürth's writings, both in published and in manuscript form. There are examples of Fürth's writings from all genres, including poetry, drama, television and film, prose and essayistic writings, and his literary output spans over six decades.</p><p>Although there is very little correspondence in the collection, Fürth's legal battles against RKO studios over his claim to the screenplay rights for the film Tom, Dick and Harry (1941), are well documented. </p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_45da9f222a4d3fb342fee1085b954f0f">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged in six series.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_7373d9f8545fd80e4ced63203924eedd">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>In 1981, Harold P. Furth, son of Otto Furth donated this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_fd5a74c001bc975be851be7909fe35a4">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_a4dcd926b46ac761aeaaad19838878c6">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_cb4e9f2514b73f93f6962ccacec2941a">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Otto Furth Papers, 1912-1986. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Furth Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Fürth, Otto, 1894-1979</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Manuscripts for publication</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Screenplays</genreform>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Correspondence</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_3dec539e984c91facbff54a9322d5425" level="series"><did><unittitle>Biographical Materials</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8 folders</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1939/1978" type="inclusive">1939-1978</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_d285eee5473902f3626b369fc1d3b387"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_0032265bb3244a3a0fd7f3720b019615"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series includes several short biographical statements prepared by Fürth, clippings about him, as well as some documents relating to Fürth, his wife, and several family members.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0ba95263cb565d22b2035757176e7c6b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">23 folders</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1919/1986" type="inclusive">1919-1986</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_67b00074f9f64c8e1ac8baf783c9b8aa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains isolated letters over the years, including some with relatives. One folder of special interest contains letters received by Fürth relating to his time in Tientsin, China, 1919-1921.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_621170ccbcbbf35d7318c3ca24a85016"><head>Arrangement</head><p>The majority of this series is arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement></c><c id="aspace_f3c2730349f3b1c45d70cc3752797f17" level="series"><did><unittitle>Fürth vs. RKO</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">11 folders</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1940/1948" type="inclusive">1940-1948</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ceb11a8b597e899562dca5d04bd60ba2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series is related to the plagerism case surrounding Fürth's play, <emph render="italic">Dorothea mit Variationen</emph>. It contains correspondence, legal documents, as well as both Fürth's version and Paul Jarrico's version of the screen plays, which were the basis of the film <emph render="italic">Tom, Dick and Harry</emph>, starring Ginger Rogers.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_6bc6c2dbed4b0bef6723a70feb2a9b43"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement></c><c id="aspace_643498e52850f260f7a3825e082bd5d9" level="series"><did><unittitle>Writings of Otto Fürth</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">166 folders</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1912/1979" type="inclusive">1912-1979</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2e1899080a56a5856c16f698e2d88f36"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series represents the bulk of the collection and contains typescripts and handwritten manuscripts written by Fürth over a sixty year period. The series contains poetry (8 file folders), plays (37 file folders), film and TV sketches (17 file folders), prose writings (22 file folders), essayistic writings (82 file folders) and published reviews of Fürth's writings (4 file folders). Included in the prose writings are several versions of the unpublished autobiographical <emph  render="italic">Flucht aus dem Schicksal</emph>, as well as the original translation by Richard Winston of Fürth's novel <emph  render="italic">Men in Black</emph> (published under the pseudonym Owen Elford).</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_455b10e32792e76c74918d182130e1bb"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged by format, then alphabetically.</p></arrangement></c><c id="aspace_f5094b9b24216cd2741c30dff9224b0d" level="series"><did><unittitle>Publications of Otto Fürth (newspaper clippings)</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">82 folders</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1949/1974" type="inclusive">1949-1974</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b4ce38dd12bfe77e8d533aec513c5872"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains a fairly comprehensive collection of clippings of Fürth's essayistic writings from Swiss, German and Austrian newspapers.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_845af848375a29ba345e4144c53e7b47"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged chronlogically.</p></arrangement></c><c id="aspace_fd276cf9447ebcc0a4529c8f63f403ca" level="series"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous Materials</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6 folders</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1933/1974" type="inclusive">1933-1974</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_89bf0fd72ce16a89a606839309dfb874"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Inclues manuscripts by other authors.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
