<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ger025.xml">ger025</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Manschinger, Kurt and Grete Hartwig; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>Manschinger, Kurt and Grete Hartwig; Papers <num>ger025</num></titleproper><author>Johann Poehlmann</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2022 August</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-08-18 23:00:14 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2015 December</date><item>Converted to EAD</item></change><change><date>2015</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Jodi Boyle</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Greta Hartwig Manschinger and Kurt Manschinger (Ashley Vernon) Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>ger025</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1905/1995" type="inclusive">1912-1995</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_883a6d949ead21d8e1643f03ae14fada">This collection contains correspondence, manuscripts, opera librettos, songs, short stories, children's literature, advertising and media, sketches, and critical reviews. It also has personal family papers of Kurt and Greta Hartwig Manschinger, paintings and writings by and other records from Greta's sister Mela Hartwig, audio recordings, scores, and sheets, as well as audio recordings of performances.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_6b5b6f0c067590a518c7a0eff71fb33b">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
,       <language langcode="ger" scriptcode="Latn">German</language>
,       <language langcode="ger" scriptcode="Latf">German</language>
,       <language langcode="cze" scriptcode="Latn">Czech</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_70184d2afe7fb40da626a1369750dbfe" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_59833050195a422bf6017f3a6f9c48be">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Collection arranged and described by Johann Poehlmann, 2022 August.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_dadbb5354f35acca4b3b95aab14c4a5c">
    <head>Biographical History</head>
<p>Greta Hartwig was born on April 19, 1899 in Vienna, at the time the capital of the Austro-Hungarian Empire. She was the daughter of Theodor Hartwig (born Theodor Herzl, later changed to differentiate himself from the famous Zionist), a noted German philosopher and advocate for free-thinking, and younger sister to Mela Hartwig, a well-known artist and author. Raised in a musical family, Greta was attracted to all forms of performing arts, her wide range of talents leading her to create the "One Woman Shows" that she became known for.   </p><p>Dr. Kurt Manschinger, also known by the nom de plume Ashley Vernon, was born in 1902 in a Viennese suburb. A precocious youth with a talent for music, Kurt was schooled by the famous Austrian composer Anton von Webern during his teenage years. Eventually, Kurt would receive his doctorate in musicology from the University of Vienna in 1926. After establishing himself as a figure in the Austrian theater scene, Kurt would meet Greta as the starring actress in one of his plays.  </p><p>Fiercely critical of fascism, Greta and Kurt were forced to flee their home country of Austria after its annexation by Nazi Germany in March 1938. First, the two fled to nearby Prague, where an inability to perform led to Greta's first foray into a writing career. Later, when the Hitler regime completed its annexation of Czechoslovakia, Greta and Kurt were forced to relocate to London in May 1939 where they helped found the anti-fascist literary cabaret "The Lantern", which hosted many of their fellow emigres who were fled the ever-rising violence of the Third Reich. The next year, the two would relocate for the final time, this time to New York City, and began to re-establish themselves as mainstays in their respective artistic endeavors.  </p><p>It was in America that the two found the most critical and commercial acclaim, with Greta successfully tutoring several students into prominent roles in film, stage, and television, while Kurt began to write operas. The most famous of these, "The Barber of New York", quickly became a critical and commercial success, being nominated for the Pulitzer Prize in 1954. In appreciation of their newfound home, both Greta and Kurt would become naturalized American citizens in April 1946.  </p><p>Kurt died at home in 1968 while performing at his piano for a group of friends. Greta, never fully recovered from the loss of her husband, passed away in April 1971. Mela Hartwig Spira died in London in 1967, her husband Robert following just days later.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_82619911dd4662f22afcbd9f9afbf510">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Series 1 contains original works created by Kurt and Greta Hartwig Manschinger, as well as Greta's sister Mela Hartwig Spira and their father Theodore Hartwig. Among the works are short stories, novels, playlets, librettos, operas, choral arrangements, scholarly articles, and drawings. Included with the works themselves are programs and reviews for various performances that the Manschingers were associated with. Materials related to Greta's teaching are also present, including correspondence, programs, and reviews from former students and institutions that she taught at.    </p><p>Series 2 contains correspondence by Kurt and/or Greta to various friends, family members, and working associates. Much of the material concerns their attempts to develop their business endeavors in the United States, with several personal letters to family members still in Europe included as well.  </p><p>Series 3 contains biographical information regarding the Manschingers, including important legal documents surrounding the Manschinger's flight from Austria, brief autobiographical profiles of Kurt and Greta, plus many photographs of the Manschinger and Hartwig families.  </p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_a2f4ee2696c26130aba210f31ced54ec">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>All 3 series are arranged alphabetically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_b63242ab4a8e6723b4abc424a35429ca">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The majority of items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by Wilbur S. Broms, executor for the estates of Greta Hartwig Manschinger and Kurt Manschinger on <date normal="1983-03-13">1983 March 13</date>. Additional materials were added to the collection by Wilbur Broms in the 1980s and by Martin Broms, son of Wilbur Broms on <date normal="2006-04-06">2006 April 6</date>.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_9cc5e905655310f9514365b291ac5630">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_4552ae76296c64d5466212455fb3812f">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The rights to the published works of Greta Hartwig Manschinger, Kurt Manschinger (Ashley Vernon), or Mela Hartwig are held according to applicable copyright laws.  </p><p>The rights to any unpublished or other works of Greta Hartwig Manschinger or Mela Hartwig are held by the University Libraries of University at Albany. Permission to perform any of Greta Hartwig Manschinger's musical works must be obtained from the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives.</p><p>The rights to any unpublished works of Kurt Manschinger (Ashley Vernon) are held by the Austrian National Library. This library must be contacted for permission to publish materials of Kurt Manschinger (Ashley Veronon) at Josefsplatz 1/Postfach 25/1015 Vienna/Tel: +43 1 534 10/Email: onb@onb.ac.at/https://www.onb.ac.at/en/</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_b0e341008bc6293600a750c885b6cd11">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Greta Hartwig Manschinger and Kurt Manschinger (Ashley Vernon) Papers, 1912-1995. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Manschinger Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">Music</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Literature</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- Refugees</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women authors</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Scores</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Vernon, Ashley</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Hartwig, Mela</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Hartwig, Greta, 1899-1971</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Composition (Music)</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Painting</genreform>
    <persname source="lcsh">Hartwig, Greta, 1899-1971</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
