<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ger026</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Eberhard, Wolfram; Papers <num>ger026</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.
Processed by unprocessed. </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-07-20 23:00:47 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Wolfram Eberhard Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="lcsh">Eberhard, Wolfram, 1909-1989</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ger026</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1935/1957" type="inclusive">1935-1957</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_9807f765936da3f128bb0ff0934c24ed">Born in Potsdam, Eberhard taught in China and Turkey in the 1930s and at the University of California at Berkeley. This collection contains corrected manuscripts of "China-Aufenhalt: Arbeiten ber Astronomie und Volkskunde"(1935), "Chinesische Volksmrchen in bersetzungen"(1935), "Materialen von der China-Reise zur Volkskunde und Astronomie Chinas"(1936), "Kaiser der Idee" (1937), and "Biographisches Wrterbuch, Beamtetitel Hsiung-nu-Texte" (1943); and offprints of articles on Chinese history, culture, and folklore, 1935-1957. </abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_27849e19d56ab113b3fd6605383f3ab1">English and German. </langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_d0faa304ecf2f411eb41fa572264700e">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_66ef15fc0810df1cce6dbe8e4403721a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_615e16c973080651cdbfb4185842beb4">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processing by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e5d1f9236474b0161ae842a257702740">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Wolfram Eberhard was born in Potsdam Germany on March 17, 1909 to Gustav B. and Gertrud Mueller Eberhard. Eberhard went to Berlin University to study Chinese and social anthropology. Wanting more education on China, Eberhard secretly enrolled at the Seminar for Oriental Languages because his professors at Berlin did not believe in teaching colloquial languages. After school, Eberhard worked at the Berlin Anthropological Museum and traveled to China in 1934. </p><p>While on his trip to China, Eberhard taught at Peking National University, Peiping Municipal University, and the Medical School at Baoding. Eberhard wrote and published books about China and language throughout this trip. After returning to Germany in 1936, Eberhard became the director of Asian studies at the Grassi Museum in Leipzig. At the height of the War, Eberhard was able to get a Moses Mendelssohn Fellowship and left for Hong-Kong, China where he then went to Turkey and began teaching history at Ankara University. While working at this University, he continued to publish works. </p><p>Eberhard received a one-year Rockefeller grant at the University of California, Berkeley in 1948 and ended up being offered a full-time faculty position in the Department of Sociology where he taught until 1976. </p><p>Throughout his career, Eberhard published extenisvely.  He published some 35 books, 185 articles, 300 book reviews, and numerous shorter notes in Chinese, German, Turkish, and English.  </p><p>Eberhard died on August 15, 1989 and was survived by his wife and two children. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_559d5d3b3924bb2724697fa151001359">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains corrected manuscripts of "China-Aufenhalt: Arbeiten ber Astronomie und Volkskunde"(1935), "Chinesische Volksmrchen in bersetzungen"(1935), "Materialen von der China-Reise zur Volkskunde und Astronomie Chinas"(1936), "Kaiser der Idee" (1937), and "Biographisches Wrterbuch, Beamtetitel Hsiung-nu-Texte" (1943); and offprints of articles on Chinese history, culture, and folklore, 1935-1957.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_6f5b99cc57bd2e248f97fa9457b480cd">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_d11ab52114625aeda71ae3badbd9fb7f">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Wolfram Eberhard donated all materials in this collection in May 1981.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_d411d134d8b8f44139255cf5316825a1">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_a967356f00894325f0cda4c6d082c104">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_1bc4c25ce676751f95beb04683cb532b">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Wolfram Ebehard Papers, 1935-1957. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Eberhard Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Eberhard, Wolfram, 1909-1989</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
