<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="unprocessed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ger113</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Manschinger, Kurt and Grete Hartwig; Papers <num>ger113</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.
Processed by unprocessed. </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-10-28 18:36:50 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Kurt and Greta Hartwig Manschinger Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>ger113</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1935/1995" type="inclusive">1935-1995</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_b0e65c13ab5c8c5668ed33cc54d5f976">This collection contains correspondence, manuscripts, opera librettos, songs, short stories, children's literature, advertising and media, sketches, and critical reviews. It also has personal family papers of Kurt and Greta Hartwig Manschinger, paintings and writings by and other records from Greta's sister Mela Hartwig, audio recordings, scores, and sheets, as well as audio recordings of performances.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_da76656018120fd66934076967a20703">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="ger" scriptcode="Latn">German</language>
,       <language langcode="ger" scriptcode="Latn">German</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_d7a3a5110622710da9d3b19af3e2bc05" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_89f3b8108169bd610dabd6d60a3197cf">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_75dea516e957ea2f129778cdf438180d">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Greta Hartwig Manschinger (1899-1971) was a novelist, poet, and librettist for works composed by her husband Kurt Manschinger (1902-1968), who wrote under the name Ashley Vernon. Born in Austria, the two emigrated first to England and then to the United States. Greta Hartwig Manschinger was the daughter of the philosopher Theodor Hartwig and the sister of the painter and writer Mela Hartwig (1893-1967).</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_a60bc6965ed0380f17d07ca3affbf783">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains correspondence, 1945-1968; a manuscript of Greta's unfinished autobiographical novel and corrected manuscripts of novel sketches; opera librettos (English translations from German); songs; short stories; children's literature; advertising and media sketches; and critical reviews, 1935-1970; personal family papers of Kurt and Greta Manschinger; paintings and writings by and other records from Greta's sister Mela Hartwig; scores and sheet music by Kurt and Greta; audio recordings of performances; index card files of Manschinger music contacts; and the Manschinger Music Trust files.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_c70acaa3bb13d9545753a5a7493f1033">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_4175ecc0d062947d3ac10ff819fd9bc7">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>This collection was donated in April 2006 by Martin Broms per a 1983 agreement between the University at Albany Libraries and the late Wilbur S. Broms.  Martin Broms was the son of Wilbur S. Broms, trustee and executor of the Manschinger Estates.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_3aa8d845b3aa8186af72e637ce054078">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_fe947c4d1a9331be1a75bab32f866ae2">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The rights to the published works of Greta Hartwig Manschinger, Kurt Manschinger (Ashley Veronon), or Mela Hartwig are held according to applicable copyright laws.  </p><p>The rights to any unpublished or other works of Greta Hartwig Manschinger or Mela Hartwig are held by the University Libraries of University at Albany. Permission to perform any of Greta Hartwig Manschinger's musical works must be obtained from the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives.</p><p>The rights to any unpublished works of Kurt Manschinger (Ashley Veronon) are held by the Austrain National Library. This library must be contacted for permission to publish materials of Kurt Manschinger (Ashley Veronon) at Josefsplatz 1/Postfach 25/1015 Vienna/Tel: +43 1 534 10/Email: onb@onb.ac.at/https://www.onb.ac.at/en/</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_b3410c4ab548693bfbd7216378cce045">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Kurt and Greta Hartwig Manschinger Papers, 1935-1955. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Manschinger Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Vernon, Ashley</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Hartwig, Greta, 1899-1971</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Manuscript</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Germany--Emigration and immigration</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Composition (Music)</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Hartwig, Mela</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
