<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>mss001</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Ancient and Honourable Company of Fellmongers; Records <num>mss001</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.
Processed by unprocessed. </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-05-19 23:00:03 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Ancient and Honourable Company of Fellmongers Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="local">Ancient and Honourable Company of Fellmongers</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>mss001</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Vol.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1820/1859" type="inclusive">1820-1859</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_b9a8ac8b2cafd3cd0692ae36f323cc54">The Ancient and Honourable Company of Fellmangers was a trade guild located in Richmond, Yorkshire, England. This collection includes the Company’s minutes of annual meetings, membership lists, and financial accounts.
</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_2e13a8e59fc6994098142f9fb395475f">English.</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_a73a3799ddef9427bc2bb167a67d7885">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_e50031d6f6880badc6b13336b9008ea0" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_2f11668cb914db97889f6fc5cc0587c6">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_1e08112c8f0ff6b2e078145d4fcaa03e">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The Ancient and Honourable Company of Fellmongers was a trade guild located in Richmond, Yorkshire, England. Fellomongers remove wool from hides in preparation for leather making. The date of the foundation of the Company is unknown, but it said to have begun in the Middle Ages as a religious fraternity. The Company held power in Richmond, Yorkshire, England and elected the Mayor of the town until 1835. After its powers were taken away by the Municipal Reform Act of 1835, the Company fell apart. </p><p>In 1980, a minute book of the Company was sold, and it prompted a group of people to refound the Company. Today the company includes men and women who were widows of deceased members. The Company seeks to promote fellowship and friendship and provides an opportunity for members to meet people in varying walks of life, not just those in the trade industry. The Company is active in charity reform and gives out prizes for those who do charity work. The Company’s website mentions that the University at Albany has a meeting minute book from the original Company. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_bcaa8afd18f11a8de396b68ffd899804">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection includes the Ancient and Honourable Company of Fellmongers’s minutes of annual meetings, membership lists, and financial accounts.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_46f6482a68d0154ffd2da58e034f5650">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_c2d8a605d46f924de575df86b262456c">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b7c8a26d821f9daddbcfad63c0c03027">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_8ff74056f9663107b96d4d39a17895f0">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Ancient and Honoruable Company of Fellongers Records, 1820-1859. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Ancient and Honoruable Company of Fellongers Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_2008e9edcdac716171bee434b0403b3a">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The provenance of this collection is unknown.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="local">Ancient and Honourable Company of Fellmongers</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Richmond (North Yorkshire, England)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Wool</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Leather</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
