<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="unprocessed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>mss093</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>New York Canals; Collection <num>mss093</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-08-13 23:00:03 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>New York Canals Collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="lcsh">New York (State). Canal Department</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>mss093</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.17 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1828/1883" type="inclusive">1828-1883</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_2d78a2f5052662f96fb1dc2443fccc9f">Collection contains a variety of 19th century materials related to several New York State canals.  </abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_c7a582172b114fe50cef537c6f934356">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_f86e28eab0902d7c521c5f26dc777336">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_c4dfe8a846b59e02de12489e018c1442" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_ba4061af2151794a587f704728059b21">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>This artifical collection consists of a variety of 19th century materials relating to canals in New York State such as the Erie Canal, Chenango Canal, and Delaware and Hudson Canal.  Materials include documents related to the New York State Canal Department, stock certificates, toll receipts, vouchers for rfepairs, certificates of deposit, correspondence (including with the Canal Contracting Board, Canal Commissioners' Office, and Canal Appraisers' Office), affidavits, and other receipts.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_9c88a575ce556fc31be51d9bdc4b5774">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Erie Canal (1821), Chenango Canal (1836), and Delaware and Hudson Canal (1828) all opened in the early 19th century as part of a canal building boom in New York State.</p>  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_2bc4434fc579c54e320bd7b2bf3e1b8e">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The collection is currently unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_ae2ddffb21c1747cd8c97d1b83fafa65">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_99a5103761960d24fc3dc85b1d61d95f">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>The provenance of this collection is  unknown.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_baaa7331edf7af43c0b5b4337764df3c">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_2f94731278dfbf82c9767f65ffc171fe">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_20b47a66570755ecb7a08ff07abff2a5">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, New York State Canals Collection, 1828-1883. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the New York State Canals Collection).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State). Canal Department</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Erie Canal (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Chenango Canal (N.Y.) </geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Delaware and Hudson Canal (N.Y. and Pa.) </geogname>
    <subject source="meg">Business and Industry</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
