<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>mss031</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Webb, Sidney; Letters <num>mss031</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.
Processed by unprocessed. </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-06-11 23:00:16 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Sidney Webb Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="lcsh">Webb, Sidney, 1859-1947</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>mss031</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1890/1929" type="inclusive">1890-1929</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_bdc6541466202e6f0244046809562e8d">Sidney Webb, 1st Baron Passfield, was a leading British economist. This collection includes 16 letters from Webb about the publication of his work, economic measures being considered for enactment in Parliament, and the Fabian Society's support of political candidates. </abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_bf8e9625460e8e965c0328c616ecee64">English.</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_990b8b581c9a4fb33174ce9afc31ccc9">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_00f01210770a9a88ae05f9510e16b014" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_f2ce4b96642e78076af0abb3a83fa161">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_d0a72959e2150beda58e7adb87f4a5ff">
    <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
<p>Sidney Webb, 1st Baron Passfield, was a leading British economist. Webb was born on July 13, 1859 in London. Webb was educated at the Birkbeck Literary and Scientific Institution and Kings College. Webb joined the bar in 1885 and in 1895 helped establish the London School of Economics. Webb became a professor of public administration at the school in 1912. Webb was also a member of the Fabian Society. </p><p>Webb married Beatrice Potter and they founded the New Statesman magazine in 1913. Webb was a member of Parliament for Seaham in 1922 and in 1929 he became the Baron Passfield of Passfield Corner in the County of Southampton. Webb went on to serve as the Secretary of State for the Colonies and the Secretary of State for Dominion Affairs in 1929. Webb also supported communism and the Soviet Union. Webb, as well as his wife, wrote books on economics, nationalism, and education Webb died in 1947. Potter and Webb are buried in the nave of Westminster Abbey. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_d83df0a5264c1f1a4c55a3b5895bb042">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection includes 16 letters from Webb about the publication of his work, economic measures being considered for enactment in Parliament, and the Fabian Society's support of political candidates. This collection also contains one letter from his wife, Beatrice Webb, dated January 12, 1913.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_6b78287fe8d6a9119f27f3379fb97570">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_28a030e70380bd6d79332e327c117c9b">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_f8e5e192a4db8654620e84e3589b6f86">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_3c98e65eccd304f1dab80b78e426ce20">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Sidney Webb Papers, 1890-1929. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Webb Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_694bdc97ad29e9d9e8cdf57b8ad047b1">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>The provenance of this collection is unknown.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Webb, Sidney, 1859-1947</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Correspondence</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Economics</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
