<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>mss007</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Cooper, Anthony Ashley; Papers <num>mss007</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.
Processed by unprocessed. </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-05-21 23:00:07 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Anthony Ashley Cooper Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="lcsh">Shaftesbury, Anthony Ashley Cooper, Earl of, 1801-1885</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>mss007</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1877/1884" type="inclusive">1877-1884</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_6ac3708150f772e34b0588f4f9c29d4b">This collection contains a large series of letter between Anthony Ashley Cooper, seventh earl of Shaftesbury, and a Miss Marsh. </abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_0e8b69b0947cfd1adf9c208d5d72d965">English.</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_5998dea3d8c3541af6507b52f4a089da">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_e4d3e6339adcd74ca62d9614d0601352" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_567353a99a6ca900cca1fff716d5ff9c">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_bb10fcd41a2f2c40ae533d8abbae38b0">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Anthony Ashley Cooper, seventh earl of Shaftesbury, was a British social reformer and philanthropist. Cooper was born on April 28, 1801 and educated at the Manor House school in Chiswick, the Harrow School, and Christ Church Oxford. Cooper received his MA in 1832, and was appointed DCL in 1841. </p><p>Cooper was elected as the Tory Member of Parliament for Woodstock in June 1826 and in June of 1827, he was appointed to the Select Committee on Pauper Lunatics in the County of Middlesex and on Lunatic Asylums. During his time on the committee, Cooper visited many “madhouses,” and he sponsored two Lunacy Acts for better care and treatment of lunatics in England and Wales. Cooper also sponsored the Ten Hours Act 1833 bill which introduced laws against child labor, as well as the Mines and Collieries Act of 1842, which protected women and children from being allowed to go underground in coal mines. </p><p>Cooper was a pre-millennial evangelical Anglican and in 1851, he became the President of the British and Foreign Bible Society.  Cooper also studied under Edward Bickersteth, a Christian Zionist. Cooper also served as the first president of the Society of Suppression of the Opium Trade. </p><p>Cooper died on October 1, 1885, and was buried at St. Giles. Cooper was survived by his wife Lady Emily Caroline Catherine Frances Cowper and many of their ten children. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_479bab19820a1e0f68f02d4446fc4a1e">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains a series of 125 letters written to a Miss Marsh between January 3, 1877, and December 16, 1884.  Miss Marsh may have been Catherine M. Marsh, a contemporary British writer on religious and social-welfare themes. The letters discuss Cooper’s religious and social-reform interests, as well as his health and travels.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_d1a562e4612036e578de0a6f675917ef">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_99b4bb35f99bb698c20d04ddcd475d4d">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_fdcedb85eaaf87b58a498aadf3f8825a">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_46abee0b78d73580c14ec60b89bfc5f1">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Anthony Ashley Cooper Papers, 1877-1884. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Cooper Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_b51871c89cd09035aff8c903b81b29c2">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The collection was aquired in 1970 from a London dealer, Francis Edwards.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Shaftesbury, Anthony Ashley Cooper, Earl of, 1801-1885</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondences</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
