<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>mss096</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">New York, Newfoundland, and London Telegraph Company; Records</titleproper><titleproper>New York, Newfoundland, and London Telegraph Company; Records <num>mss096</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.
Processed by unprocessed.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-09-29 00:25:50 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>New York, Newfoundland, and London Telegraph Company Records</unittitle>
    <unitid>mss096</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Vol.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1854/1867" type="inclusive">1854-1867</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_75b822e7df72945bba48af6909cd0e2b">Founded in 1852 in New York City, the New York, Newfoundland, and London Telegraph Company was a company that preluded the first trans-Atlantic cable. This collection contains the minutes of meetings of this company's "corporators," including Peter Cooper, Cyrus W. Field, Frederick N. Gisborne, Moses Taylor, and others.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_8a9e84625a680197ac76296a37330100">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_20ca7802185608ec2686bc9cf8c82d3e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_8589cc55cb2883d34c7e466165cebc41">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_2b852b5ac55682b76c71fa3b82cb01be">
    <head>Historical Sketch</head>
<p>Founded in 1852 in New York City, the New York, Newfoundland, and London Telegraph Company was a company that preluded the first trans-Atlantic cable. Charles Bright, Cyrus W. Field, and John Watkins Bret became representatives of the company. The founders wanted the telegraph line to run from Nova Scotia through Newfoundland.  In 1853, the company was taken over by the Anglo-American Telegraph Company (AAT).</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_c7af80f3a6153e0175c552fb0e41442e">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains the minutes of meetings of this New York City company's "corporators," including Peter Cooper, Cyrus W. Field, Frederick N. Gisborne, Moses Taylor, and others.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_5421d9ee003239a2fb8eddb94c264e11">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_1f4b8ce2a449ea7d58a2f366be53523c">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_2c3217909a5a774a8cecbdec4c2fdc41">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_90b0474c03eedc319cb03b975bbbcad4">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, New York, Newfoundland, and London Telegraph Company Records, 1854-1867. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the New York, Newfoundland, and London Telegraph Company Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_95c14f0f02f9dd245d5fe6fbbb7ae886">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The provenance of this collection is unknown.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="local">New York, Newfoundland, and London Telegram Company</geogname>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Minutes (administrative records)</genreform>
    <subject source="meg">Business and Industry</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Field, Cyrus W. (Cyrus West), 1819-1892</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">	Cooper, Peter, 1791-1883	</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Gisborne, F. N. (Frederick Newton), 1824-1892</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Taylor, Moses, 1806-1882</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
