<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>mss055</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Colfax, James; Papers <num>mss055</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-09-03 13:17:19 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>James Colfax Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>mss055</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Vol.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1808/1813" type="inclusive">1808-1813</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_7988a25732e6af8960ab58db4a1792d7">This collection includes shipping and related records from a dock operator in New York City in the early 19th century.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_e38afb12bd6177c5f89b86153f67e592">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_9562ff82d745a0db62d6240cc7d708d3" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_8d1513502c7f881ff74a83a6d9e964dd">
    <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
<p>James Colfax operated a dock in New York City.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_455f7e14bdabf031790c2a6ae9af49dc">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection includes daily records of vessels in New York City. The records include tonnage, place of origin, and wharf fees as well as arrears for sloops, schooners, and other merchant vessels shipping between New York City and other places in New York, New Jersey, and Pennsylvania.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_39f63a4998e301d55f5f0630403d39e5">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_d404c973d86b6c880ba5e375e1720452">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_41a6bd598e959c550af28990fe35c704">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_3fd55980ff7c96f23fcd3466adc71de3">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, James Colfax Papers, 1808-1813. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Colfax Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_88154b1fa68888ce4e18e1c3380a6df7">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The collection was purchased from dealer Argosy Book Stores in 1967.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="local">Colfax, James</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
