<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>mss009</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>De Grey, Thomas; Papers <num>mss009</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.
Processed by unprocessed. </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-06-04 23:00:33 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Thomas De Grey Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="lcsh">De Grey, Thomas</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>mss009</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Vol.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1809/1813" type="inclusive">1809-1813</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_239e92ee5d4bf4d0ca2940eaf7de3c28">Thomas de Grey, Baron Waslingham was the Archdeacon of Winchester. This collection contains a record book of day laborers’ compensation and services on the Merton estate in Norfolk, England in the early 19th century.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_b0a7a0275568f2bc4bc46059bb63c32e">English.</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_b3cda40b6671483020465f10048da128">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_9e91d1fe220a861a7361d120f5e2c052" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_81936dda626f1a64239db36fc17f511d">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_9432d7acc224a8164503e89eb660a72f">
    <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
<p>Thomas de Grey, Baron Waslingham, was the Archdeacon of Winchester. Based on the dates of the record book, it might have belonged to Thomas de Grey, 4th Baron Wasingham. All of the Greys served at Merton Hall in Norfolk, England.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_17455c001d83414bc15ebcd498a576fc">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains a record book entitled, “Expenses of Workmen Employed on the Merton Estate,” a weekly record of day laborers’ compensation and services (chiefly, carpentry, gardening, bricklaying, and blacksmithing) on the Merton estate in Norfolk, England that dates from July 9, 1809 to June 27, 1813.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_1b4510c7f6600984e0b72878e40b313e">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_222e443f41564f11eb062503f90ac8f5">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_a793724694bfd44e68c81f3eea1b25bb">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_dd331498f668ffbd541916424bc9cddc">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Thomas De Grey Papers, 1809-1813. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the De Grey Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_d401903cf3ea9d848bbd1e889133dba1">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The collection was purchased from a dealer in 1968.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">De Grey, Thomas</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Financial Records</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
