<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>mss028</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Smith, Thomas; Papers <num>mss028</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.
Processed by unprocessed. </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-09-03 13:16:36 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Thomas Smith Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>mss028</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Vol.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1600/2000" type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_5afe2f70f76289ab305a5c0cf92618a6">Sir Thomas Smith served in official positions during the reigns of Edward VI, Mary I, and Elizabeth I. This collection contains the manuscript entitled, "A Discourse for the Common Welthe of England," which was one of five known early manuscripts of a political treatise completed in 1549 in response to socio-economic problems in Tudor England at the time and first published in 1581.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_95229de91db6b907576e43ad629760a1">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_0280c5963cc5b5a7d6c29586239af554" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_59459a246a7f2391ecf106cf2ad44d84">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_c8572debed00d5a9fab1e1ef90059ab1">
    <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
<p>Sir Thomas Smith served in official positions during the reigns of Edward VI, Mary I, and Elizabeth I. Smith was born on December 23, 1513 in Saffron Walden in Essex. Smith was educated at Queens College and became a fellow in 1530. Smith then obtained a law degree at the University of Padua. Smith was educated in Greek and taught many lectures about the language. </p><p>In 1543, Smith was appointed the first Regius Professor of Civil Law, and in 1547 he became the Provost of Eton College and Dean of Carlisle Cathedral. A Protestant, he was the Secretary of State under Edward Seymour, 1st Duke of Somerset and was knighted in 1548. Smith served as a member of Parliament for Livrpool in 1559 and was the ambassador for France in 1562.  Smith was also known to write about England's government. Smith died on August 12, 1577, and  was survived by his second wife and one of his children. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_4deaa59f494504689c68e9fd327d0a90">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains the manuscript entitled, "A Discourse for the Common Welthe of England," which was one of five known early manuscripts of a political treatise completed in 1549 in response to socio-economic problems in Tudor England at the time and first published in 1581. On the first page is a note written ca. 1607: "I think it not fit that this Treatize be printed, except it be authorized by some of the Lordes of the Consayle. Tho: London." For an analysis of this manuscript see <emph render="italic">A Discourse of the Common Weal of This Realm of England, attributed to Sir Thomas Smith,</emph> ed. Mary Dewar (Charlottesville: University Press of Virginia, 1969), pages 157-162.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_2e0b5b03cb20df4c582d22569c1dee6d">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_134e62453b7b70868ed663e68c31c068">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_f37a25768b8d9f46bd6dc5aa5059f818">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_2b43ae2f27545b1eb1fd7ca525485340">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Thomas Smith Papers, Undated. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Smith Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_9c8b2be73a79b751b392566a8e487a4f">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The provenance of this collection is unknown.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Smith, Thomas, 1513-1577</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Manuscripts for publication</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
