<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>mss036</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Albany General Store; Records
 <num>mss036</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.
Processed by unprocessed. </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-10-28 18:39:42 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Albany General Store Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="local">Albany (N.Y.) General Store</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>mss036</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Vol.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1784/1786" type="inclusive">1784-1786</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_e3f4689564a82a877ffb61978eedd27b">The Albany General Store Records contain business records kept by an unidentified proprietor of a general store which sold dry goods, rum, and other merchandise.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_26bc74f878e2e62c2b1227f4b186ca8e">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_76380fd1b21599bba379296376da49d6" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_5eb506b44a06079eaf6ccf176383be9f">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_650f00037ce69ed0acfad7bf5aefe229">
    <head>Historical Sketch</head>
<p>The Albany General Store was run by an unidentified proprietor of a general store, probably located in Albany, which sold dry goods, rum, and other merchandise to customers from Albany to Schaghitcoke, (north of Troy, New York), and westward to Stone Arabia, and other Mohawk Valley settlements.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_3ed97003429671eec226722dc1d88dc6">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains the business records of the general store including the names of early Albany Dutch settlers. The volume also features day book entries from Oneida, New York, 1877-78, and notes on English grammar and physical geography taken by a student at the Oswego Normal School, 1878.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_0219d630e035fc890143ca21a13f80e6">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_da50ac33b5d61fc13d79904cb21383a5">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_2d6847420d6578f5e5b7857c646b801d">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_521b9e1a422d710842eb2d0e75ba0c71">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Albany General Store Records, 1784-1786. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Albany General Store Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_6f87c0430b8851e2395d8f82b414f30f">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The collection was purchased from dealer Knoblauch's in 1970.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Financial Records</genreform>
    <geogname source="meg">Albany, New York</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
