<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>mss097</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Newburgh, Dutchess, and Connecticut Railroad; Records <num>mss097</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.
Processed by unprocessed.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-06-08 23:00:05 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Newburgh, Dutchess, and Connecticut Railroad Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="lcsh">Newburgh, Dutchess &amp; Connecticut Railroad</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>mss097</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">32 Vol.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1887/1890" type="inclusive">1887-1890</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_4afa71603c06cd06905621d0d48a67f6">The Newburgh, Dutchess, and Connecticut Railroad was chartered on September 4, 1866 under the original name of the Dutchess and Columbia Railroad. This collection contains monthly statements of passengers and tons of freight carried over the railroad by the New York and New England Railroad. Kept by W. H. Moore, the railroad's general passenger agent, in Matteawan, New York.
</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_509b6e18c39ecdfc0ec87daaee31472e">English.</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_3e4afb006638f09d4382900dd695f0ec">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_adb2af367fd5c88b6b512d46593bc1c2" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_c032cc61eb0e74e3a3561c906fae5e6e">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e31979c7c7ad88153c8e78a2aee3229a">
    <head>Historical Sketch</head>
<p>The Newburgh, Dutchess, and Connecticut Railroad was chartered on September 4, 1866 originally as the Dutchess and Columbia. The railroad company began using the Connecticut Western Railroad and the Poughkeepsie and Eastern Railroad lines in 1871. The company also combined railroads under George H. Brown, including the Harlem Extension Railroad, the Pine Plains and Albany, and the Hartford and Providence Railroad. </p><p>On August 5, 1876, the D&amp;C was sold and on January 25, 1877 it was renamed the Newburgh, Dutchess, and Connecticut Railroad. The railroad operated through the Dutchess Junction and included a locomotive repair ship, a paint shop, and a train yard. The company also had a steamboat that transferred passengers across the river to and from Newburgh. In 1907, the railroad merged into the Central New England Railway, and smaller tracks began to be abandoned. In 1969, the railroad was merged into Penn Central and became the Beacon Secondary Track. The remaining part of the original railroad is now part of the Metro-North Railroad. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_bb9fe81ceafd7654219c112df08a0971">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains monthly statements of passengers and tons of freight carried over the railroad by the New York and New England Railroad. Kept by W. H. Moore, the railroad's general passenger agent, in Matteawan, New York.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_455f8057d890bdbc9ee26bd06add1769">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_2e6e7f85aa3e25635f89d63b142e06f1">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_9c2f42172f0c45bf53c6d200fa947786">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_0754b6f1ef97e0f3ed2be6e9a346d96a">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Newburgh, Dutchess, and Connecticut Railroad Records, 1887-1890. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Newburgh, Dutchess, and Connecticut Railroad Records)</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_6411f9464d8f3a6be0a47a85190e1d04">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The collection was purchased from a dealer in 1971.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Newburgh, Dutchess &amp; Connecticut Railroad</geogname>
    <subject source="meg">Business and Industry</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Financial Records</genreform>
    <geogname source="local">Moore, W.H.</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
