<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=mss148.xml">mss148</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Delmar Progress Club; Records</titleproper><titleproper>Delmar Progress Club; Records <num>mss148</num></titleproper><author>Jodi Boyle, Michael Munsey</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2021</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-07-16 23:00:23 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Delmar Progress Club Records</unittitle>
    <unitid>mss148</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">15.61 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1902/2021" type="inclusive">1902-2021</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_a4f378ff4b11f8258380d00fd642c5bb">The Delmar Progress Club Records document the day-to-day operations and communitiy activities of this Bethlehem-N.Y. based organization founded in 1901.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_71a92a7a1ff6c69991562f4aa69e44b5">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_59285fc5b09365ed6eac91c38e7a5b3a">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>This collection contains administrative records including minutes, annual reports, by-laws, and a certificate of incorporation; membership lists, application materials, and club yearbooks (including calendar of events); club history and anniversary files; photo albums, photographs, and scrapbooks; multimedia items, i.e. an audio casette, CDs, DVDs, and VHS tapes; events and program files; financial records; publications; ephemera; and subject files.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_61cdecc29cbef79bb6f9c7365fff628e">
    <head>Organizational Sketch</head>
<p>Established in 1901 in Delmar, N.Y., a hamlet in the town of Bethlehem, the Delmar Progress Club is a women's organization located in the Capital Region of New York State. The organization joined the New York State Federation of Women's Clubs in 1904, the General Federation of Women's Clubs in 1916, and was incorporated in 1929. The first president was Mrs. Sherman B. Rouse who served from 1901-1906.</p><p>The Delmar Progress Club was responsible for many community developments as the town of Bethlehem grew in the 20th century. In 1912, the Club raised money for books to establish the first free library in town and in 1913 organized the Delmar Free Library Association. The library was staffed and administered by Club volunteers for nearly two decades.</p><p>In addition, the Club named streets and numbered homes making the town eligible for mail delivery to residences. The Club's Civic Betterment committee petitioned the town to provide garbage collection, and it also is credited with leading the effort to establish the Town Planning Board.</p><p>Today the Delmar Progress Club remains active and engaged with the community and offers social and educational activities for its members.</p>  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_0979c062d1002cd4686eb218b9d53e1a">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection is unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_1722ed2cf52b1044e9a10a589cc40167">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is arranged into four series: administrative, events, publications, and subject files. The first three series are arranged chronologically, while the subject files series is arranged alphabetically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_a470a00ebed4ba5c9e6f803d5b2f249a">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>The Delmar Progress Club donated all materials in this collection in November 2021.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_f1a75ba571d40b1dfa7d1f26b3fcffbf">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_339a4082bf9ac0aaae0dbc3d068a96f4">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_db76045f6bc7eac4a16a52c7c906a937">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Delmar Progress Club Records, 1903-2020. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Delmar Progress Club Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <title source="local">Delmar Progress Club</title>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women--New York (State)--Societies and clubs</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Minutes (administrative records)</genreform>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Newsletters</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Financial Records</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Programs (documents)</genreform>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Photographs</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Membership lists</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Neighborhood and Community Associations</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Photograph albums</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">DVDs</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">VHS</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Audio cassettes</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Newspaper clippings</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <corpname source="lcsh">New York State Federation of Women's Clubs</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_1596ead0cb25e7908de3113e0eecc1fe" level="series"><did><unittitle>Administrative</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5.34 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1902/2020" type="inclusive">1902-2020</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>.</langmaterial></did><arrangement id="aspace_de76b8ec9b4452b5da5a763292bf36cd"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged chronologically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_ac30f975c11e38466aaffeba39619615"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains the administrative records of the Delmar Progress Club, including meeting minutes, correspondence, financial documents, membership records, and committee reports. Meeting records comprise Bethlehem town board and school district meetings, Delmar Progress Club meetings, i.e. board of directors meetings, business meetings, executive board meetings, general meetings, past president's meetings, and special meetings, and General Federation of Women's Clubs (GFWC) meetings, i.e. bi-county meetings, mid-Hudson district meetings, third district meetings, and tri-county meetings. In the first few decades of the Club's existence, meeting roll calls were included with the meeting minutes. More recent Club meeting minutes are interfiled with agendas, ballots, by-laws and standing rules, citations, Club calendars, Club communications, correspondence, event invitations, financial documents, GFWC materials, member guidelines, lists of officer candidates and conference delegates, memoranda, motions, newspaper clippings, notes, policy documents, presentations, reports, resolutions, speech transcripts, webpages, and yearbooks. Meeting minutes are typically arranged by the fiscal year (October to May) rather than by calendar year. Correspondence is divided into general correspondence, which includes intra-Club and extra-Club communications, membership correspondence, and the papers of the Club's corresponding secretaries. Financial records include accounts, audit reports, bank books, checks, Club budgets and proposed budgets, GFWC finances, profit and loss standards, reports of the Club's treasurer, summaries, tax documents, and town budgets and tax reports. The early financial documents of the Club include lists of members, officers, and resignations. Membership records include address changes, applications for membership, dues paid, lists of members, lists of new members, lists of resignations, notices of the deaths of members, and reminders to contact members. Reports include the annual reports of the recording secretary, the corresponding secretary's reports, committee and group reports, conference reports, event reports, membership reports, New York Legislative Forum reports, the Club president's reports, school district meeting reports, task force reports, town board meeting reports, town planning reports, and the Club vice president's reports. This series also includes the Club's certificate of registry with the Home Education Department of the University of the State of New York, the Club constitution, the incorporation documents of the Club (the original 1929 document is stored in a flat file), various iterations of the Club's by-laws, scripts for the installation ceremony for new Club officers, rules for conducting meetings, parliamentary procedure guidelines, New York Legislative Forum by-laws and program schedules for 1974 and 1976, the notes of Club president Muriel H. Welch, and the personal notebook of Club President Wilma DeLucco. Finally, the series includes index cards, which include the member's name, her address, the date she joined, her Club identification number, the names of her sponsors, and the date she left the Club, for former Club members who have died or resigned.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c0ff61bfbddeb9e35fda6c413d1909c9" level="series"><did><unittitle>Events</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.85 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1913/2021" type="inclusive">1913-2021</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>.</langmaterial></did><arrangement id="aspace_e0bc02e8176b8b08167a5df36ae87d82"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged chronologically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_70a1cb0d5f65b9190e388c8d40856adf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains records concerning events that the Delmar Progress Club organized and participated in, such as stage productions, Club annual or spring banquets, Club fall banquets, Club anniversary celebrations, Bethlehem Public Library anniversary celebrations, and charitable fundraisers. This series does not contain events organized by the General Federation of Women's Clubs or the New York State Federation of Women's Club; any materials relating to such events can be found in the subject files series. The materials in this series include event flyers, event booklets and programs, event calendars, song lyrics, newspaper clippings, dues statements, photographs, scripts for stage performances, request forms for event spaces, cast lists, correspondence concerning donations, sheet music, e-mails, Bethlehem Public Library newsletters, presentation scripts, history of the Delmar Progress Club, letters from the Club president, submissions to Progress in Print (the Club's newsletter) about upcoming Club events, photo albums for the Club's Festival of the Arts (they are stored in ordinary folders and oversized boxes), and DVDs and VHS tapes (they are stored in a smaller box). In addition, this series includes folders containing both photographs and other materials and those only containing photographs. This series also contains records concerning the foundation, history, and upkeep of the Bethlehem Public Library, including history of the Bethlehem Public Library, meeting minutes from the Bethlehem Public Library Centennial Committee, the constitution of the Delmar Free Library Association, an annual report for the Delmar Free Library from 1914, and indentures from the will of George C. Adams to support the Delmar Free Library Association, and a resolution by the board of directors of the Delmar Progress Club to fund equipment and/or materials for the Bethlehem Library. Finally, the series contains the records of the Club's garden study group and the performing arts study group.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_26340bf2b560216ad083eeba79067957" level="series"><did><unittitle>Publications</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.0 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1904/2019" type="inclusive">1904-2019</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>.</langmaterial></did><arrangement id="aspace_6cf1b92f89dee7f0a528339a73bd9f46"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged chronologically</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_7372364606d332fe26d7d7d1f8619532"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series only includes publications of the Delmar Progress Club and contains an incomplete run of the Delmar Progress Club's newsletter and a complete set of the Club yearbook, i.e. 1904 to 2019. Although the newsletter did not initially have a title, by August 1988, it was named Progress in Print. Starting in 2006, receipts for the printing of Progress in Print are included with the newsletters. An issue of the Club yearbook typically contains a message from the Club president, announcements, lists of Club and General Federation of Women's Clubs officers, lists of committees and committee members, a Club calendar, a general Club program, a list of past Club presidents, member phone directory, and standing rules of the Club. Copies of the yearbook may also contain loose documents, i.e. Club by-laws, by-laws revisions, correspondence to the members, dues statements, event invitations, and membership lists.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_12dc0ffa9cb1f71676e073e8d71fcd80" level="series"><did><unittitle>Subject Files</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7.42 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1913/2021" type="inclusive">1913-2021</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>.</langmaterial></did><arrangement id="aspace_271a11d482396d8b7ecb2816f29090a7"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically</p></arrangement></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
