<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="unprocessed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=mss150.xml">mss150</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Hettger, Henry T.; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>Hettger, Henry T.; Papers <num>mss150</num></titleproper><author>Jodi Boyle</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2023</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2023-03-14 23:00:23 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Henry T. Hettger Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>mss150</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.75 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1990/2008" type="inclusive">1990-2008</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_2fd55a4e7eb279c931ec791fcbf7789d">The Henry T. Hettger Papers document Hettger's interest in numismaticsacs and his writings about coins and coin collecting.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_1856d4a9e51edee30acdaae6f87e6c68">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_de9c80d5b482592c2dfafbe5a04057ba">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_cf2f0c9a1d0195b208c1d96efa2d081f">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Henry T. Hettger donated all materials in this collection in March 2023.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_96428d5e02d667583069b95ee4cc1594">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_4cba3470eaddde52f646b1fc7cc57026">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_6fcb68c2c4b718670deffd82b560f9d3">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Henry T. Hettger Papers, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Hettger Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <arrangement id="aspace_791dad6ffd727f8eddd3ad7acc4db62c">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_b8bd4e5684456815bdb2a55892c339c9">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Henry T. Hettger received an MPA from the University at Albany in 1968. After graduating, he worked for President Carter's Affirmative Action Project before becoming a researcher for the National Archives and Records Administration. An avid coin collector, he has authored over 100 articles for Numismatic News, collector newsletters, and Open Archeology, a peer-reviewed journal.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <function source="lcsh">Hettger, Henry T.</function>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Faculty &amp; Alumni Papers</subject>
    <function source="lcsh">Coins--Collectors and collecting</function>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
