<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>mss134</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Carrara, Dolores I.; Papers <num>mss134</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-12-04 23:00:26 -0500</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Carrara, Dolores I. Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="local">Carrara, Dolores I.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>mss134</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.2 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1946/1947" type="inclusive">1946</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_dfe2c775fbd560b86ab6132ac2adf8cf">Dolores Carrara was a radio actress and dnacer. This co;;ections include scripts from programs broadcasted on the radio station WGY and television station WRGB based in Schenectady, NY.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_25aeb9ca938e22a79c0930bb0e2a66ba">English.</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_f411938fb85e1d0c40ce7ac8625bfef9">The materials are located onsite in the department. </physloc>
    <container id="aspace_a3e310a57c1c08da17d6b1d8387ab0fc" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_ea3cf767e00bb122876d46cae81038e2">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Born on Janaury 29, 1929, Dolores I. Carrara started dancing acting, and singing for radio stations at just three years old. Some of her first radio apperances at the WGY station in Schenectady, N.Y. included dancing for the shows "Children's Jamboree" and "Tell Me A Story." Carrara also did a Christmas Eve special for the WGY radio station in which she sang two songs that were broadcasted in South America. As she got older, Carrara also modeled for General Electics and was a regular actress on the "FBI in Action" WGY radio show.</p><p>Dolores I. Carrara also took dance lessons from Florence Sanford and eventually moved to Miami with her husband where she worked on shows for the WTVJ commerical radio. Eventually Carrara moved back to Schenectady, N.Y. and became a secretary at a local library.</p>  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_1a1f328e93019a939166641e52e26d20">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Sheri Sarnoff in 2019.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_6fd978bddddc099960819197232c3c7c">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains scripts that Dolores I. Carrara used when starring in radio shows. Programs in the collection include episodes of Dear Chollie and The Ted Malone Show and an adaptation of Jane Eyre. The majority of radio scripts are episodes of The FBI in Action.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_9691f150b15af6a5d71043f84b31ec75">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This series is arranged alphabetically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_c490722bdabd08337b605dd748265530">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Dolores I. Carrara donated all items in 2004.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_ae4377814902b2048159f5a72ee4ed57">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>This collection is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_51409d88cf9f5c743d063d7f8e8b136e">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal refernce use, reffered to, or linked to from other websites. Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder. The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.)and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additonally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks. The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_9eb9e598462fcf588d9c9bcb4d9f7031">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Dolores I. Carrara Papers, 1946-1947. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Taylor Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">Radio and Television Broadcasting</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Radio scripts</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Voice actors and actresses</subject>
    <geogname source="meg">Carrara, Dolores I.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Schenectady (N.Y.)</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
