<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=mss143.xml">mss143</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Frank, Joachim; Papers <num>mss143</num></titleproper><author>Jodi Boyle</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2019</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-08-03 23:00:03 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Joachim Frank Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="lcsh">Frank, J. (Joachim), 1940-</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>mss143</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1953/2016" type="inclusive">1953-2016</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_db9a5ca00e68e0e9f986a1b7688c897c">The Joachim Frank Papers document Frank's artistic pursuits and accomplishments. </abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_eefec68ef1ea923b5e92aa4fcbb7482f">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_d489b590b6979fdc360c5327f0fe0966">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_8196ce88663087596a322ad97715c194">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>This collection consists of mail art, including works created by Joachim Frank and other individuals; documents related to and documenting WORKSPACE, an Albany arts group of which Joachim Frank was a member; copies of <emph render="italic">PROP</emph>, an arts magazine published by WORKSPACE and edited by Joachim Frank, as well as documents relating to the magazine; a scattered run of publication <emph render="italic">Granta</emph>; and other publications, correspondence, catalogs.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_2561b960997e1c02bf554d2ca30702fb">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Portions of the collection were privately processed many years ago.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_cffc341722ff2b3099ea728dd837c7b9">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The materials are not currently arranged.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_18a345e76e086a2974a4a37b5f752bf3">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Dr. Joachim Frank is a German-born scientist who has been writing for more than 40 years since he lived in Albany, New York and took writing classes with William Kennedy. He currently lives in New York City. Frank has published several short stories and prose poems in print publication and other poems, short stories, and flash fiction online. While in Albany, Frank served as editor of <emph render="italic">PROP</emph>, the arts magazine of WORKSPACE, an Albany arts group of which he was a member.</p><p>Frank is a professor of Biochemistry and Molecular Biophysics and of Biological Sciences at Columbia University, and Distinguished Professor at the University at Albany. In 2017, he received the Nobel Prize in Chemistry.  </p>  </bioghist>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_7cb37a125cc9719b2309a36d36a6b0db">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Joachim Frank donated all materials in this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in October <date normal="2019">2019</date>.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_90a069bb647199f40e0c3005ad11c429">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_4813b27293328d13b9abaff3d9c761e6">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_ad3faa47d453065e819f8790c4a51a85">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Joachim Frank Papers, 1953-2016. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Frank Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Frank, J. (Joachim), 1940-</geogname>
    <subject source="meg">Art</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
