<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ua030.xml">ua030</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Institutional Research, Office of; Records <num>ua030</num></titleproper><author>Miles Lawlor and Benjamin Covell</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2018</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-08-28 10:45:06 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2017 February 7</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Benjamin Covell</item></change><change><date>2018</date><item>Series level description created by Miles Lawlor.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Office of Institutional Research, Planning and Effectiveness Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="local">State University of New York at Albany. Office of Institutional Research</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ua030</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5.5 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1929/2017" type="inclusive">1929-2017</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_1be145eadfa9904898b17fd1d0515f05">Contains studies and reports on the State University of New York at Albany based on research conducted by the Office of Institutional Research.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_70fc4c83960341114e11c10fcbd99cc8">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_105171cfcf93213e003f02e7cf6d7906">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_aa3b7eaa9396e3622ca04004be1415c9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_4f4bafc8c43bb65115c11aa3b35061af">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2018 by Miles Lawlor.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_fead1d6e02b0ec98b29821702ac38e4d">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_65422483de568eda4c5a7bdb047a9a6a">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_1b1a3752d291750301e44e17b6bc41a1">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_a7c5a99762eab3a100852eb78dadb365">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Office of Institutional Research, Planning and Effectiveness is a major source of official data and statistics about the University. The Office  has been a key developer of campus enrollment and revenue projections, especially concentrating on undergraduate admissions and financial aid databases. The Office also conducts special studies and databased analyses which measure organizational effectiveness and which support campus management.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_d787db27a6639d0d4709674eeee36d46">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Reports and Presentations series of this collection documents the day-to-day work done by the Office.  It includes studies and reports completed by the Office on topics including faculty workload and salary; enrollment figures, goals and projections; tuition and student charges; degrees awarded; five year planning background documentation and outcome assessments.  This series also includes both internal office correspondence and correspondence with a number of other offices and departments within the university.
This collection also contains a series of outcome assessments and correspondence documenting the work done by the Office of Assessment, a subsidiary within the Office of Institutional Research.
Finally, this collection includes a series of web crawls of the Office’s website.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_765802238aa9f17ef41af79a8b145f1b">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>Collection was maintained in the original order after it was transferred.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_cfffe63e04e1d387f30a68b31dd19a03">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Office of Institutional Research Records, Planning and Effectiveness, 1929-1994. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Office of Institutional Research Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Educational evaluation</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">School enrollment</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Workload</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Administrative records</genreform>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Academic Administration</subject>
    <corpname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_f7303cb042c00935ae8a43ddf01cdea6" level="series"><did><unittitle>Reports and Presentations</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1929/2004" type="inclusive">1929-2004</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_b922d66b8642b0f4c4a54bd4824b2954"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Series was maintained in the original order after it was transferred.</p></arrangement><processinfo id="aspace_e991d238a817c18fbc706ce0c6950654"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Loose papers in each box were foldered in the order that they were found.   Work orders, telephone service request forms, allocation transfers and similar routine paperwork no longer in retention removed in 2018 by Miles Lawlor.</p></processinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_205bf870aa1f666cc379b65f698e9892"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains a number of files documenting the activities of the Office of Institutional Research.  This includes university profiles, and prepared presentations and reports on a number of different topics including staff salaries, staff workload analyses, enrollment projections, degree awarding trends, five year plans, student outcome assessments and the Student Information Retrieval System (SIRS) implemented in the 1980s.  This series also includes departmental correspondence interspersed throughout.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_19d3ff04da5a60497a8e499988afb3d2" level="series"><did><unittitle>Wendell Lorang Space Management Committee Records</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.33 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1980/1996" type="inclusive">1980-1986</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_48b3fc4bd2a8a33b44bfe189f9ac30d1"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Collection was maintained in the original order after it was transferred.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_06a0503e401686e35901bbc2c2338070"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series is made up of documents collected and created by Wendell Lorang, Associate Director of Institutional Research and Chair of the Space Management Committee.  The documents in this series include correspondence, memoranda regarding space allocations, renovation and alteration requests, classroom move requests, and committee meeting minutes.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_84b7bf7dfb0ed0e43e987766ccbbb53b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Office of Assessment Files</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.17 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1993/1999" type="inclusive">1993-1999</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_72ec5cac8d5a249fd7f70e1ad6b37d0e"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Series was maintained in its original order after it was transferred.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_ebed5be44092883ba66c87224538054b"><head>Contents</head><p>This series contains outcome assessment reports, example surveys to be furnished to students, and departmental self-studies on how best to measure student success in a given major.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c51264a3784da2324fd30c897ee3372b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Website of the Office of Institutional Research</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">435 captures</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="2013-05-08/2018-08-21" type="inclusive">2013 May 8-2018 August 2018</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/3308/*/http://www.albany.edu/ir/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.albany.edu/ir/"><daodesc><p>http://www.albany.edu/ir/</p></daodesc></dao></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
