<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ua355.xml">ua355</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Student Accounts, Office of; Records <num>ua355</num></titleproper><author>Miles Lawlor</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2018</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-10-28 17:50:37 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2017 February 2</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Benjamin Covell</item></change><change><date>2018</date><item>Shredded document containing student's personal information by Miles Lawlor</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Office of Student Accounts Records</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua355</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.17 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1975/1986" type="inclusive">1975-1986</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_f5ea2bc747012d7df8ae9f4226665e50">The collection contains inactive records from the Office of Student Accounts, which oversees student tuition and billing.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_d0dac7ef5d2ecdc78fe853aacdc16b22">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_7d3c4ef7f5790cd2056dc5255bc44131" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_25d1be64285754567cd08be2267b8c12">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2018 by Miles Lawlor.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_c142aa605bc32f1ac35bd96395e66441">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_76b624dc42177bf957f7060f8f2698dd">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
<p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
<p>The M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collection and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_d6f1840e8ba4edaaaf0ca63f33dbe60d">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_32c0d9c9a567c55b83efde28399b9c32">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Office of Student Accounts is responsible for the student billing process. The Office was formerly overseen by the Division of Finance and Business but is currently organized under the Office of Academic Affairs.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_6a3621ad54541aac82d941ad11a7f9d9">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains budget information for the Office of Student Accounts, sample tuition billing forms, reports, audits of the Office of Student Accounts, and administrative correspondence with other offices.  Collection also includes a productivity report conducted UAlbany MBA students.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_90a8c2f03c30749929e0ec4f42b5a1c2">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>Collection was maintained in the original order after it was transferred.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_f17a965f07e7eb48612117ab1a2b7f34">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Office of Student Accounts Records, 1976-1986. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Office of Student Accounts Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher--Administration.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Administrative records</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Budgets</genreform>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Finance &amp; Business</subject>
    <corpname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
