<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ua370.xml">ua370</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Diversity and Inclusion, Office of; Records <num>ua370</num></titleproper><author>Erik Stolarski</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2018</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-03-09 01:45:24 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2017 February 7</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Benjamin Covell</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Office of Diversity and Inclusion Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="local">State University of New York at Albany. Office of Diversity and Inclusion</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ua370</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">19.5 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1970/2017" type="inclusive">1970-2017</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_f93576a090908dc7765d6b9be8b575d7">Records of the Office of Diversity and Inclusion and its predecessors. Materials include administrative correspondence, committee and task force meeting materials, planning documentation, and assorted reports, all relating to issues of diversity, inclusion, equal employment, and discrimination.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_92dcd859bf4374b08a1417cb1628386b">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_e1ef0ef0e66f3c4668ee0da0dd5aae1f">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_1f845722d4e4378effb709a213f08bdc" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_5568ff39f941f09997f715310c2c9705">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2018 by Erik Stolarski</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_4946604e0d491efcb58fcfe63e3e189d">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b93a643c705d7b4c1922f526d7cbde1d">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_5e072d47bdb7c565701da5c6447397ef">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_a45de6273ed03032638e3f01b8245a27">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Office was formed in 1971 due to the establishment of an Affirmative Action Program on campus. It was initially part of the Office of Personnel and led by Leon J. Calhoun. As the responsibilities of this office expanded it became its own entity and was known as the Office of Equal Employment Opportunity. The office expanded through Title IX and Section 504 legislation that had recently been signed into law. These included the creation of sports teams for female students and addressed the treatment of students with disabilities on campus. It later became known as the Affirmative Action Office and overseen by Gloria DeSole who also worked in the Task Force for Women's Safety at the same time. It evenutally became known as the Office of Diversity and Affirmative Action before becoming the Office of Diversity and Inclusion in 2010. 
     The role of this is to provide diversity-related training and resources, address discrimination and harassment complaints, enforcement and support of legislation such as Section 504. One of their greatest current responsibilites is oversight on the recruiting an dhiring processes in all aspects of the University. This includes approval of advertisements for positions and potential candidates for interviews.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_aa716fa560fc5a9488f2cc5acdc91566">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection includes affirmative action and recruitment plans; student surveys; workforce analysis documents; conference materials; daily correspondence (1974-1986); Federal compliance reports (1971); task force and committee materials including: the Women's Concerns Committee (1978-2000), the Task Force on Women's Safety, the Black Action Coalition, and others. Topics covered include: Section 504 (which addresses disability discrimination), Title IX, and equal employment.</p><p>     There is a single series dedicated to Women's Studies 399: Classism, Racism, and Sexism, a class taught by staff of the Affirmative Action Office in 1977. </p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_a5471b1970be674e641107cd8ad968bc">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>Collection is arranged into nine distinct series based on subject. Original order is maintained within each series.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_a0a7033193616cb93f569757263e5171">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Office of Diversity and Inclusion Records, 1970-2017. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Office of Diversity and Inclusion Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">Women</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Affirmative action programs</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Affirmative action programs in education</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Discrimination in employment</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Administrative records</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Administrative reports</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Minutes (administrative records)</genreform>
    <corpname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
