<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ua390.xml">ua391</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Communication and Marketing, Office of; Records</titleproper><titleproper>Communication and Marketing, Office of; Records <num>ua391</num></titleproper><author>Benjamin Covell</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2017</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-09-28 23:48:32 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2012</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Angela Perez</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Office of Communications and Marketing Records</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua391</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1995/2000" type="inclusive">1995-2000</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_dcb20eec53a1b78ab7fe57f01ac0dbe4">The Office of Communications and Marketing Records contain video footage of winter and spring commencement ceremonies at the University at Albany between 1981-2005.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_9439905a419690c0e5cc16b195cba6fa">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_9a3d57518ba82b12bd6f8e8e69032a63">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_1b2e3c8aa20b7e824b7b81969df86c7d">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to the oontent in this collection is unrestricted, but some film or video formats are challenging and/or costly to access and some materials must be digitized first to avoid damage to the originals. Thus, its possible that some items may be restricted on this basis.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_77103467282a2de55269884a1a01625d">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_8b7eed717ab2eef2ec3d0e9a40753657">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives received these materials from the Office of Marketing.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_89d67b609a6ef3a5652dad8d21a4129e">
    <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
<p>Founded in 1844 as the New York State Normal School, the University at Albany held its first commencement ceremony in 1845. The first graduating class of the Normal School consisted of 34 graduates; 29 men and 5 women. Currently the University at Albany holds two commencements during the year, one in May and the other in the December, with more than 3,000 students receiving degrees annually.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_788d0c985509cfc534997a6e5356f84b">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains desktop publishing materials created by the Office of Marketing for the publication of UAlbany Magazine.  Materials include proofs, article drafts, CDs and floppy disks with photographs and other publishing materials, and invoices from printing presses.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_800fdb9fbf646d7ab78bd2f54131181d">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_dfba2a849a9bb6562f9541897323f7d5">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Office of Communications and Marketing Records, 1995-2000. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher--New York (State)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Periodicals--Publishing</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Floppy Disks</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">compact discs</genreform>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Communications &amp; Marketing</subject>
    <corpname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany</corpname>
    <corpname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany--Office of Communications and Marketing</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
