<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ua400.xml">ua400</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Research and Dean of Graduate Studies, Office of the Vice President for; Records <num>ua400</num></titleproper><author>Benjamin Covell and Miles Lawlor</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2017</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-05-21 23:00:14 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2017 March 27</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Benjamin Covell</item></change><change><date>2018</date><item>Series-level processing completed by Miles Lawlor.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Division for Research Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="local">State University of New York at Albany. Office of the Vice President for Research and Dean of Graduate Studies</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ua400</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">42.88 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1974/2013" type="inclusive">1974-2013</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_520f0dc0b48e914158aea1b829fb482b">This collection contains records from the Office of the Vice President for Research and Dean of Graduate Studies, which oversaw research and graduate education at the University between 1971 and 1998.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_aaf3532c16a4ee038ccdcbbc03d1ac0f">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_d150de1b96fe1b773e68d95dc914490f">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_738e681c06f53e9c7734f5353d87388e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_c9ec25d0317f84a4cda608521c55ff61">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed, with grievance documents out of retention and documents containing social securty and other personal information removed and shredded in 2018 by Miles Lawlor.</p><p>A number of partially filled boxes in this collection have been consolidated, with original file order maintained throughout.  Information regarding original box numbers has been included in series level description.  Upon processing it was discovered that boxes 35, 36, 44 and 51 were missing.  It is unclear whether these boxes were merged into other collections or whether this was due to the numbering errors upon transfer.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_e21f8bba583436cec4a5aad7dc99f67d">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_86d2773d2e5c2df190004cdc5925a6d6">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_c672cb6a393724b7cdcb7a7494635df8">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_dffef10e764878d8299cbccebbf1c523">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>The Office of the Vice President for Research and Dean of Graduate Studies was created in 1971 as a result of the combination of the Offices of Research and Graduate Studies.  The Office’s duties were two-fold:  Firstly, the Dean of Graduate Studies was responsible for overseeing graduate education at the University, including program development, graduate student recruitment and retention, student travel grants and guidelines, academic grievances and the development of graduate programs with international universities.  The Vice President of Research’s portion of the Office was primarily dedicated to the promotion and facilitation of faculty research, with a focus on reviewing grant requests and overseeing the dispersal of institutional grants and other funding to faculty.  Generally, a single person filled both roles.  The Office also played a part in the development and financing of research centers and the dispersal of Faculty Research Awards.  For a number of years, the role of Vice President of Research and Dean of Graduate Studies was filled by Jeanne Gullahorn, whose tenure of office makes up a large portion of this collection.
In 1998, the Division for Research was created and the Vice President for Research was folded into that office, while the Division of Academic Affairs assumed responsibility for graduate education and international graduate programs.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_a57fdf51cd6dbbb335ef53d43c7d7974">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The records in this collection were created by various individuals in the Office of the Vice President for Research and Dean of Graduate Studies. Materials include: Vice President search committee records; administrative files relating to other university departments; records of research centers and institutes, including: the Center for Women in Government, the Center for Computing and Disability, the Center for Legislative Development, the Center for Technology and Government, and others; records from various international programs; council and committee files, including: the Council on Research, Committee on Centers and Institutes, Graduate Academic Council, and others; faculty salary information and performance reviews; budget files and account expenditure summaries; files relating to the Research Foundation; files relating to the Office of Laboratory Animal Services; and various other records relating to the administration of graduate education and research.</p><p>A small portion of the collection dates from 1999-2002, after the Office of the Vice President for Research and Dean of Graduate Studies was dissolved. These materials are largely intermixed with the earlier records and represent the transition to the current Office for Research
 
Includes subject administrative files relating to other university departments, records of research centers and institutes, council and committee files, faculty files, UUP records, correspondence, and Office for Research records.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_304dab0fc70c1c7ec1977ded6c856db3">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>This collection has been broken up into 10 series.  Most series have been arranged in the order in which they were transferred to the archives.  As collections were not transferred chronologically, items within the collection are not in chronological order.  The Articulation Agreements and International Programs series, the Search Committee series, and the Publications series have been created artificially from material found in several other series.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_9dfc17fa25ad12fec140318ab89878d4">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Office of the Vice President for Research and Dean of Graduate Studies, 1974-2002. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Office of the Vice President for Research and Dean of Graduate Studies).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher--Administration</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Universities and colleges--Graduate work</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Research</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Administrative records</genreform>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Academic Administration</subject>
    <corpname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_a8f4dd230f9a8267466b6a3775cf447a" level="series"><did><unittitle>Administrative Records, 1992 July 17 addition</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9.57 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1974/1992" type="inclusive">1974-1992</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c55adbe3850080e28dc86dec916a44c6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains correspondence sent to and from the Office of the Vice President for Research and Dean of Graduate Studies.  This series contains documentation on both proposed and approved Research Centers and Institutes affiliated with the Univeristy.  Contains polices regarding research misconduct, funding requests, office travel vouchers and nominations for the Faculty Research Awards Program.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_5b9b2bc03a32829e844afc901c6d6ac8"><head>Processing Information</head><p>According to information on original boxes, this series was accessioned to the University Archives 1992 July 17.  The decision to maintain these materials as their own series was based upon these labels.  Boxes in this series were originally labeled as Boxes 1 through 10.  Box 3 of this series also contains a 5" floppy disk.</p><p>Payroll documents containing Social security numbers removed and shredded in 2018.</p></processinfo><arrangement id="aspace_5f4d858da4b23e2f39ab271b40d85f94"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Folders in this series were maintained in their original order upon processing.</p></arrangement></c><c id="aspace_710b9e2a0054c560357a7cf88fb0a2e1" level="series"><did><unittitle>Administrative Records, 1993 January 5 addition</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4.4 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1983/1992" type="inclusive">1983-1992</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_1111da37828d16d8a8cee8af5d0c34e1"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Folders in this series were maintained in their original order upon processing.  As collection was not transferred chronologically, items within the collection are not in chronological order.</p></arrangement><processinfo id="aspace_0731c2e4949ce281c3ee7ec5fd89c434"><head>Processing Information</head><p>According to information written on the original boxes, this series was accessioned on January 1, 1993.  The decision to maintain these materials as their own series was based upon these labels.  Boxes in this series were originally labeled as Boxes 11-15.</p></processinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_8d24c93975737ec47d684435f8dfe743"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains information on internal audits of the Office's budget, animal research policies, correspondence with research centers and institutes, reports from committees on which the Office played a part and correspondence with academic departments regarding their graduate programs.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_79424143a73040f820d070d15f358ad0" level="series"><did><unittitle>Administrative Records, 1994 August 11 addition</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1986/1992" type="inclusive">1986-1992</unitdate></did><processinfo id="aspace_654276793d7e766584819bb11ef1e67b"><head>Processing Information</head><p>According to information on original boxes, this series was accessioned to the University Archives 1994 August 11.  The decision to maintain these materials as their own series was based upon these labels.  Boxes were originally labeled as Boxes 16 through 19.</p><p>Documents containing Social Security information on department employees removed and shredded in 2018 by Miles Lawlor.</p></processinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_79a598a35a3f9b3574b648960f89bac3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series consists of correspondence relating to the creation of a variety of research centers and institutes, memorandum regarding graduate student recruitment and travel guidelines, departmental employee salary information as well as meeting minutes for a number of committees with which the office was associated.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_e71d80f57fec38ff19a6e13eacf43b53"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Folders in this series were maintained in their original order.</p></arrangement></c><c id="aspace_9804541d491fa9cd8484f44c4191d311" level="series"><did><unittitle>Administrative Records, 1995 January 23 addition</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1983/1992" type="inclusive">1983-1992</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d149128dfe24521c580af14a19a9d37f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series is primarily focused on graduate research policies, office correspondence, graduate fellowship guidelines and  Research Initiative memorandums.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_4e55218893b8cf76f65592901a82df63"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Files in this series were maintained in their original order upon transfer.</p></arrangement><processinfo id="aspace_6c63507bb4febb36cbdbeaa744c8b3f6"><head>Processing Information</head><p>According to information on original boxes, this series was accessioned to the University Archives 1995 January 23.  The decision to maintain these materials as their own series was based upon these labels.  Boxes in this series were originally labeled as boxes 20 and 21.</p></processinfo></c><c id="aspace_7247209a2a6d8f461fa51ad2e71ded04" level="series"><did><unittitle>Administrative Records, 1997 May 15 addition</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1982/1996" type="inclusive">1982-1995</unitdate></did><processinfo id="aspace_95643e3d75c65e7f0da8118f99c1fa42"><head>Processing Information</head><p>According to text written on original boxes, these files were received by the University Archives 1997 May 15, 1997.  The decision to maintain these materials as their own series was based upon these labels.  Boxes in this series were originally labeled as Boxes 22 through 30.</p><p>Files on discretionary pay increases containing personal information removed and shredded in 2018.</p></processinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_052481616345aba961fe6cb7bf03e6dc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains documentation of research and faculty awards including FRAP, correspondence with academic departmnets and several university collectives, as well as minutes, memoranda and correspondence related to graduate program development and various committees and university consortiums with which the Office of Research and Graduate Studies was affiliated with.  This series also contains correspodence between the Office of Research and similar offices at different colleges in the SUNY system.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_5b1f35c6c6cd275f0fc8bace96542ba4"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Folders in this series were maintained in their original order upon processing.</p></arrangement></c><c id="aspace_b77477987d6a9de41cbc1b5976dd3975" level="series"><did><unittitle>Administrative Records, 1999 April 20 addition</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1993/1998" type="inclusive">1993-1997</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3eb41c0568023a7ce11fb2c8e389e9a7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains university employee disclosure statements and related memoranda.  This series also contains a number of files documenting the process of handing out research grants and awards, including FRAP and the Albany Benevolent Association Grant Awards.  The series also contains several folders of correspondence sent both to and from the Office of Research and Graduate Studies.  Finally, this series includes correspondence with a number of international universities regarding both proposed and implemented cooperative degree programs.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_108df55d40fa9bf9434f4524fe3ebf19"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Folders in this series were maintained in their original order upon processing.</p></arrangement><processinfo id="aspace_7f61033e2df681203f5c3b94687f3011"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Materials in this series were originally labelled as boxes 31 thorugh 34.  According to information written on the original orignal containers, Boxes 31-33 were originally received by the Archives on 1999 April 20.  While Box 34 does not contain such information, based upon the design of the folders and the time period of the material it entailed it was surmised to be from the same accession and included in this series.</p></processinfo></c><c id="aspace_2db6f40f599f089c65bd5a41a468383c" level="series"><did><unittitle>Administrative Records, 2001 addition</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9.4 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1980/2001" type="inclusive">1980-2001</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_1cf2325e070693e1853948ef4a173b24"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Files in this series have been maintained in their original order upon transfer.  A number of partially full boxes within this series were consolidated with original file order maintained.</p></arrangement><processinfo id="aspace_f99ed32c4b3c9f09b7b76467cb62e616"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Boxes in this series were originally labeled as boxes 37-52 .  Upon processing it was discovered that boxes 35, 36, 44 and 51 were missing.  It is unclear whether these boxes were merged into other collections or whether this was due to the numbering errors upon transfer.</p><p>While previous series in this collection were designated based upon information written on their original boxes, none of the boxes in this series contained such information.  It was therefore decided to maintain these remaining boxes as a single series.</p><p>Resumes, vita and student grievances no longer in retention removed and shredded by Miles Lawlor in 2018.</p></processinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_63575d75e0ff0aad15865888d6b9bed4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials in this collection include documents regarding research policies, including documentation on conflicts of interest as well as both human and animal testing.  This series also contains correspondence and documentation on University-affiliated research centers and institutes.  This series also includes the Research Foundation's documentation on Y2K compliance as well as the University's implementation of Oracle software through the OASIS program.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7504343cb7308075b4b04b21a0b8c0da" level="series"><did><unittitle>Articulation Agreements and International Programs </unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.17 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1984/1990" type="inclusive">1984-1990</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ee74bad38aca650dd28f828368e2860b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This artificial series contains articulation agreements between the University at Albany and international universities.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_ae2c47f075b1157080c3770276e2edcb"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Folders are arranged alphabetically by institution.</p></arrangement><processinfo id="aspace_60213e2383bcfd1b10344b4b6067a312"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Files in this series were origianlly taken from the 1993 January 5 series as well as the 1999 April 20 series.</p></processinfo></c><c id="aspace_abe291ece6dd7ba4e0a8729780ceaed1" level="series"><did><unittitle>V.P. of Research and Dean of Graduate Studies Search Committee Records</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.17 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1978/1980" type="inclusive">1978-1980</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_817f0b661ed01f1413aac4012e0c1ae3"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Folders in this series were maintained in their original order upon processing.</p></arrangement><processinfo id="aspace_8d867a4b75c091a59b2c108187ee6f3a"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Documents no longer in retention and relating to individuals who were not hired by the university were removed and shredded in keeping with standard retention schedule.</p><p>Series contains IBM Magnetic cards designed to be used with an IBM Selectric typewriter.</p></processinfo><bioghist id="aspace_4fec4155ffa0da38796a32d3da32a0db"><head>Administrative History</head><p>After Louis R. Salkever announced that he would retire at the end of the 1978-1979 academic year, a committee chaired by Sociology Professor Dr. Richard H. Hall was appointed to oversee the search for his replacement in early 1978.  The Search committee was unsuccessful that year in selecting a long-term replacement and Hall was appointed Acting Vice President for Research and Dean of Graduate Studies, while Dr. Marguerite Q. Warren took over as chair of the Search committee for the next academic year.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_a2348ecd102988b19ebb49afd4b64c45"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains meeting schedules and minutes of Search Committee meetings, documentation of how the position was advertised, affirmative action data, correspondence between committee members, pamphlets on how to organize a search committee, solicitations of candidate recommendations from other universities and form letters sent to applicants for the position.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f939ccfd97be35df5a67ac0a8192d813" level="series"><did><unittitle>Publications</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.17 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1994/2013" type="inclusive">1994-2013</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_dd39f70c78393fce8f531124d8dbab1c"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Files in this series have been arranged chronologically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_9c17dc3d6c5a15081c974063afb1d69b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This artificial series is made up of publications released by the Office of Research highlighting both faculty and student research, as well as a publication commemorating the University's sesquicentennial in 1994.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_922619335199ef932d15322b8a671f4c"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Materials in this series were originally found on a shelf in the archives with a Post-It labeled "Office of Research."  The materials were then processed and foldered in 2018 by Miles Lawlor.</p></processinfo></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
