<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ua435</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>System Dynamic Society; Records <num>ua435</num></titleproper><author>Miles Lawlor</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2018</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-01-02 23:00:40 -0500</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>System Dynamic Society Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="lcsh"> 	System Dynamics Society </corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ua435</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5.33 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1978/2016" type="inclusive">1978-2016</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_bc126abc78667b84022137786d5a3741">Adminsrative records of the System Dynamic Society, a professional organization of academics devoted to furthering research into system dynamics and systems thinking. The Society holds an annual international conference, and the administration of the group was based at UAlbany until 2018.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_eeb8d7be6414c568f92cf50bba533f32">English</langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_5f32d878315df73a8d563d9cd34f8786" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_6e5c716c4901fef65c41e8bd6ec63e29">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>Contains administrative records for running the professional organization and annual conference for System Dynamics. Includes conference promotional materials, meeting records, proceedings and photographs from conferences, membership directories, budget documentation, annual reports, correspondence with publishers, newsletters, and games designed by the Society to teach System Dynamics. Also includes A/V materials, mostly from 2000s-2010s and born digital records on external media which is likely copies of material in the web archives and that will be transferred over network shares.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_85c68724d150dbe1091dcd859548778e">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The System Dynamics Society is an international, nonprofit organization devoted to encouraging the development and use of System Dynamics and systems thinking around the world. The Society provides a forum in which researchers, educators, students, consultants and practitioners in the academic, corporate and public sectors interact to keep abreast of current developments, build on each other’s work and introduce newcomers to the field. The Society manages the annual International Conference of the System Dynamics Society and publishes the System Dynamics Review. Originally founded at MIT, the Society was later administered at UAlbany until 2018 where they recieved some state funded assistance for their administration, as well as funding from members and sponsoring organizations. After 2018 the Society was supported by an outside vendor in Albany.</p>  </bioghist>
  <userestrict id="aspace_f23258ce03ee5709f9b46a67469f9da0">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</p>  </userestrict>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_29d4135af15334234ec6c433a4029b40">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted unless otherwide denoted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <arrangement id="aspace_52817b9aabdee0f541f84060a44c8128">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collections was arranged by Society staff members during their office closing.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_8257acea08432ecd01c943a1bdd23b41">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by the System Dynamics Society in October 2018.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Dynamics</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_053063e90098b5755d11bc739f49bb67" level="series"><did><unittitle>Society Administration and Correspondence</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.33 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1978/2018" type="inclusive">1978-2018</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_689c9c46ba4114841fae08378f1fe277"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Files in this series have been maintained in their original order.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_4aca5cb423646b3308d9b167140d0e76"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series is made up of files related to the founding, organization and management of the Society.  It includes the society's bylaws, meeting minutes, programs for conferences organized by the Society, various contracts with the University at Albany, SUNY, budget documentation, the Society's song, and documentation on various conferences and proposed conferences organized by the Society.  There are also several files containing correspondence between members of the society and outside individuals.  Additionally, this series contains instructions, promotional material and a board for the society's "Beer Game," a board game designed to introduce people to general concepts in system dynamics.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3f44dabeb446e10a1c25ae7052b96b6a" level="series"><did><unittitle>Membership Lists</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1984/2002" type="bulk">1984-2002</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7b46112ae0f43651435f433119756672"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series is made up of the membership lists maintained by the System Dynamic Society.  It contains membership lists for every year between 1984 and 2002, excluding 1994.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_edc3deaa424b21ff4f6afd5c239e92b7"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Files in this series are arranged chronologically.</p></arrangement></c><c id="aspace_72334d2755cabe2cec7e43ded718a0a5" level="series"><did><unittitle>Marketing Materials</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.33 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1983/2017" type="inclusive">1983-2017</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_41c7221ce4388f4e939430c0a7ef7692"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Files in this series have been maintained in their original order.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_385300c1972507c6ba358a0c253e6915"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series is made up of marketing materials created for and distributed by the society.  This includes promotional mailers, conference brochures and schedules, and commemorative pens.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a4931a3be8c921a6673690078933aba4" level="series"><did><unittitle>President's Newsletters</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.17 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1988/2016" type="inclusive">1988-2016</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_ac8cf97be4876163aef83a8e47db7e4c"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Files in this series have been arranged chronologically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_fade51b66b4d6bcdfcfcb1a76dd721a9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series is made up of copies of the Society's newsletter, called the President's Newsletter.  Over its history, the newsletter was generally published either annually or biannually depending on society activities.  It covers past and upcoming conferences, publications by members and society sponsorship information.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ce02d3a7975bd1deccf11b4b709c93af" level="series"><did><unittitle>Audio/Visual and Photographs</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1986/2014" type="inclusive">1986-2014</unitdate></did><phystech id="aspace_3635ebaf57b6db355f8c98d28f21a65f"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>This collection contains a large number of CDR's, CD-ROM's and DVD's and VHS tapes that require a media viewer.  Contains one Betacam cassette that needs its own proper media viewer.  This series also contains one (1) Tweety Bird-shaped Flash Drive, which appears to include materials already present elsewhere in the series.</p></phystech><scopecontent id="aspace_5d118b4a506f07aa1aae6651f1590e5c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains both audio-visual and born-digital materials documenting various conferences that the Society has organized throughout the world.  Materials include recordings of speeches, backups of conference websites, conference proceedings, photographs and conference brochures.</p><p>This series also contains VHS recordings of a lecture series narrated by former Society President Jay W. Forrester on system dynamics,</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
