<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ua532</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Normal College, New York State; Grade Books <num>ua532</num></titleproper><author>Erik Stolarski</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2018</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-03-02 00:58:56 -0500</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>New York State Normal College Grade Books</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua532</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.77 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="circa" era="ce" normal="1868/1899" type="inclusive">1868-1899</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_95b07c982deddeb2caac98dc181d2780">This collection documents the grades by subject of all students who atteneded the Normal School from 1868 to 1899.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_1938bed0adc7a938f812a7bd1794de4d">Materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_718284fa1f44b24b244e9c803f155746">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is arranged in chronological order.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_f4c335e4a1abcc1a607c9fde63cd5692">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The Normal School as founded in 1844 as an institution devoted to training teachers in New York State. There was  a wide curriculum covering varuious subjects and students had to follow this strict order of classes. Records of all the grades for each student were kept and divided by semester. The book was maintained by the president of the School, and explains why the books start in 1868, a year after the Joseph Alden, the first president of the school, took over.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_ee991b76998023927e56ec606a550bf6">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>This collection contains student records which are governed by the New York Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). We are not legally able to provide access to the restricted records in this collection. Please consult an archivist for more details.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b278c4eeba0a884a5f9cf6d5f7829570">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p> <p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p> <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p> <p>The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>   </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_f3ca04c5865cd3a805180c7e2c25b9a7">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo id="aspace_52ad4aef89a3f3c2ddb9516ece3aee5e">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Collection was processed in 2018 by Erik Stolarski.</p>  </processinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_bd363a088a9d5d9fc56c2efe66c20a01">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, The New York State Normal School Grade Books, 1868-1899. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the New York State Normal School Grade Books.).</p>  </prefercite>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_e2a21fbdc10a60efbd4b573a01ddbc84">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection consists of books containing the grades, classes taken, name of every student that went through the Normal School in a thirty year period. It gives great insight into the curriculum of each student, and what subjects were taught to future teachers in this period. The books are organized by the term that the student would have been in at the time, breaking down the student's schedule by each term.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Student records</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Report cards</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">College Students</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Universities and colleges -- examinations</geogname>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Academic Administration</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_41fae9a2566887ce965b0177028206da" level="item"><did><unittitle>New York State Normal School Grade Book</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="circa" era="ce" normal="1868-02-19/1886-02-10" type="inclusive">1968 February 19-1886 February 10</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial><container id="aspace_20748f650ea09c69a2b40fde6e4a4f86" label="Mixed Materials" type="Item">1 (New York State Normal School Grade Books)</container></did></c><c id="aspace_5689935b2942549a3e170093456189cd" level="item"><did><unittitle>New York State Normal School Grade Book</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="circa" era="ce" normal="1886-09-08/1891-09-09" type="inclusive">1886 September 8-1891 September 9</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial><container id="aspace_2760bd25c7528abdd306869ad8a8e3bc" label="Mixed Materials" type="Item">2 (New York State Normal School Grade Books)</container></did></c><c id="aspace_7b71dfb16d8f2851d6eec9ad63341a12" level="item"><did><unittitle>New York State Normal School Grade Book</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="circa" era="ce" normal="1891/1900" type="inclusive">1891-1900</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial><container id="aspace_88c07b246efafe506da1bf4c2cd6a48e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Item">3 (New York State Normal School Grade Books)</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
