<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ua561.xml">ua561</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Educational Opportunity Center; Records</titleproper><titleproper>Educational Opportunity Center; Records <num>ua561</num></titleproper><author>Dulcie Beauregard</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2023</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2023-11-01 23:00:50 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Educational Opportunity Center</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua561</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.8 ft. cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1959/1978" type="inclusive">1959-1978</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_6888cb2c1f687508801bceda1b42ff2e">This collection is comprised of the inactive records from the Educational Opportunity Center at the State University of New York at Albany.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_3e27d36e635eed28c450c09a12b652cd">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_3e421bbaaa03432d066fa19d534b754c">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>The collection documents the procedures of the  Educational Opportunity Center (EOC) from 1973 to 1978 and contains reports, budgets, correspondence, data, surveys, audits, memos, plans, projects, reports, program materials, and more. Earlier records of the EOC from the late 1960s to early 1970s were destroyed by a water leakage. Files titled as "Important Documents" may include enrollment information, program proposals and reports, memos, surveys, evaluations, budgets and fiscal reports, student data, correspondence, and more.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_e5c74c35c2fe0ff8939a8a3a952ea1e7">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2023 by Dulcie Beauregard.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_8a3079f61404531653ef737c2b7bbf47">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_62314b44670a45c73e7cd3f13ef1b2d3">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>The records of the Educational Opportunity Center were transferred to the archives in May of 1978.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_fa4e245fb60521772d1fefd4b57998a6">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Educational Opportunity Center Records, 1959-1978. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Educational Opportunity Center Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <userestrict id="aspace_a40b689e127df0af53080dafb39f5cd2">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p>The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <arrangement id="aspace_b378c6a8a9b110d60680505b5447204a">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is arranged chronologically. There are no series.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_34ba1960ba835c34164730aadad9d36c">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Educational Opportunity Center (EOC) at the State University of New York at Albany provided free programs for economically or educationally disadvantaged adults in the Albany area in order to further their careers and/or educational goals from the late 1960s to late 1970s. Vocational programs included bookkeeping/accounting, clerk typing, keypunch operation, office assistant jobs, and secretarial work. Free academic programs included English-as-a-Second-Language courses, vocational preparation, high school equivalency, and health science programs. After completion of a program, the EOC worked to place graduates in jobs or college.</p>

<p>These records pertain to the program as it was offered by the State University of New York at Albany before it was consolidated in 1978 with the Troy Educational Opportunity Center. Operations were combined under the management of Hudson Valley Community College and still operate today, under the name Capital District Opportunity Center. In May of 1978, the records of the Educational Opportunity Center were transferred to the archives as a result of the consolidation of EOCs and the end of State University of New York at Albany's administrative responsibility in August of 1978.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <function source="local">Educational Opportunity Center (State University of New York)</function>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Centers &amp; Institutes</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Education</subject>
    <geogname source="meg">Albany, New York</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Career development</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Administrative records</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
