<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="under_revision" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ua600.xml">ua600</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Arts and Sciences, College of; Records <num>ua600</num></titleproper><author>Miles Lawlor</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2019</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-10-28 17:54:10 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2014</date><item>EAD file created</item></change><change><date>2014</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Conversion and encoding by ArchProteus</item></change><change><date>2019</date><item>Series level processing completed by Miles Lawlor.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>College of Arts and Sciences Records</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua600</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">48.9 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1955/2011" type="inclusive">1955-1977</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_488b0cffe79d94e6f59e4081e244f72b">The collection consists of inactive records from the University at Albany's College of Arts and Sciences.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_243394d64eaceb2d04155b4a52fb3d09">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_3a3a676a8f85ef5891c01a59471d9e45" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_ab559e8f06250231ef88b40e161f6601">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Materials in this collection include accessions acquired in 1994 and 1995 from the College of Humanities and Fine Arts, the College of Social and Behavioral Sciences, and the College of Science and Mathematics. Materials from these three colleges were inititally intermixed but were arranged into separate series for each college.</p>  </processinfo>
  <phystech id="aspace_e44098170b1eb7ce179c206ed220559e">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Web Archives</p>  </phystech>
  <bioghist id="aspace_6597692d7d18b8b11bdbf5d24f5bf4e0">
    <head>Biographical History</head>
<p>The University at Albany's created the School of Arts and Sciences in 1963 to bring together all the programs in the arts and sciences, in 1964 its name was changed to the College of Arts and Sciences. The College of Arts and Sciences was dissolved in 1978-79 into the new Colleges of Humanities and Fine Arts, Science and Mathematics, and Social and Behavioral Sciences. The College of Arts and Sciences was officially recreated in October of 1993 after the recommendations made by a Task Force on Campus Organization were accepted by then President H. Patrick Swygert. The Colleges of Social and Behavioral Sciences, Science and Mathematics, and Humanities and Fine Arts, were officially brought together to form the College of Arts and Sciences.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_31d7bbc7d563892d00c7f96c5fcd965f">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of inactive records of University at Albany's College of Arts and Sciences and documents the administration of the College and the departments within it. Most of the materials predate the re-establishment of the College of Arts and Sciences in 1993. Collection includes annual reports, 1968-76; dean's correspondence with divisions and departments; proposals for new courses and changes for existing ones, 1965-67; Arts and Sciences Council, Executive Committee, and Committee Meeting minutes, 1968-76; Chairmen's Meeting minutes, 1972-73; departmental program evaluations, three- and five-year plans.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_372a4ea574c0cf5d23c318f4f8c441f0">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged into 8 series:
Series 1: College of Arts and Sciences Website
Series 2: College of Arts and Sciences
Series 3: Self-Studies and Middle States Accreditation
Series 4: College of Humanities and Fine Arts
Series 5: College of Sciences and Mathematics
Series 6: College of Social and Behavioral Sciences
Series 7: Center for the Humanities Advisory Board
Series 8: College of Arts and Sciences Ad Hoc Committee on Harassment</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_7a15dfcec647c246162195bd0899c3d3">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>All items in this manuscript group were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_6356d233f13a4d19c1538368c2de9c7f">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_2db09cb632b5cd9eceaba089aad209a0">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_edb4d647e965890f14a24422c3e8781c">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, College of Arts and Sciences Records. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York. (hereafter referred to as the Arts and Sciences Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="meg">Web Archives</genreform>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Schools &amp; Colleges</subject>
    <corpname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany. College of Arts and Sciences</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_752994bbc635fb5a2248d07d429f6e1e" level="series"><did><unittitle>College of Arts &amp; Sciences Website</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial></did><phystech id="aspace_01ba2c26c52a634468372b88dd4462fa"><head>URL</head><p>http://www.albany.edu/cas/</p></phystech><controlaccess><genreform source="meg">Web Collection</genreform></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_8a9d0808c328f52f81be5228df0bf934" level="series"><did><unittitle>College of Arts and Sciences</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">18.4 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1955/1988" type="inclusive">1955-1988</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5506167d48062508ba212c7caa961150"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series is made up of materials from the first incarnation of the College of Arts and Sciences (CAS), before its split into the College of Fine Arts and Humanities, College of Social and Behavioral Sciences and College of Science and Mathematics. During the period covered by this series, the functions of those colleges were administered by Divisions along similar organizational lines. This series contains some materials that both predate the organization of CAS as well as other materials from after it was subdivided.  The bulk of the materials however focus on the college's administration and the various committees that the College of Arts and Sciences Deans L. Gray Cowan and Charles Colman served on during the 1960s and 1970s.</p><p>Series includes divisional and departmental annual reports, correspondence, graduate and undergraduate program reviews, degree and course proposals, memoranda, enrollment data, course listings, committee memberships lists and meeting minutes and budget materials. </p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_6421dcc94ad3b161328e0bbe8fd51076"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Series was maintained in the original order after it was transferred.</p></arrangement></c><c id="aspace_b24e58089f80db676feb88dba76405d1" level="series"><did><unittitle>Self-Studies and Middle States Accreditation </unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1968/1971" type="inclusive">1968-1971</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6347af55c67eb120adfcb62f1da2269f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series documents materials prepared for the University's accreditation by the Middle States Commission on Higher Education. These materials represent the Humanities Division's preparations for the accreditation process and include departmental reports, correspondence and memoranda, forms, self-studies by academic departments and articles circulated by members of the Humanities Division's committee charged with overseeing preparations for the accreditation.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_a5d2ce2c4472194ff3aca6b0c4134bbd"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Materials in this series appear to have been previously processed and foldered. They have been retained in the order they were found in.</p></arrangement></c><c id="aspace_ba6efcd620231ad8c73c857258e23741" level="series"><did><unittitle>College of Humanities and Fine Arts</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10.33 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1965/2011" type="inclusive">1965-2011</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_173b2093ad802dd5716991dd6abf667a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series documents the administration of the College of Humanities and Fine Arts, particularly between the college's founding in 1978 and 1993. Series contains correspondence, program and center proposals, committee meeting minutes, Three- and Five-Year Plans, VHS tapes of events of the College's China Institute, Capital District Humanities Project reports, faculty activity forms, annual reports.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_2b9e307d53ecdcc012a1a9a16c5a00ab"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Series contains VHS tapes.</p></phystech><arrangement id="aspace_b94cc95d887d75507c12dfb5de360d13"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Series was maintained in the original order after it was transferred.</p></arrangement></c><c id="aspace_5bd79ae9cd75dfbedd4815173ba0d0c1" level="series"><did><unittitle>College of Sciences and Mathematics</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7.17 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1962/2011" type="inclusive">1963-2011</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_73fb14eede4f353de4720b8c1e6ebdca"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Materials in this series have been maintained in their original order.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_988b8740da1e0e6a87b9a7856fa68005"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series documents the administration of the College of Sciences and Mathematics. Series contains annual reports, graduate and undergraduate program reviews, comittee meeting minutes, grant proposals, files of various chairs and departments, memoranda, recruitment plans, degree and program proposals, three- and five-year plans for the college and departments. Some materials in this series predate its creation as a separate college and were likely retained from the period in which it was a Division within the College of Arts and Sciences.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_5a1fa6d89cb49dabc3c9b52d8e685746"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Materials in this collection accessioned in 1994 and 1995 came from the College of Humanities and Fine Arts, the College of Social and Behavioral Sciences, and the College of Science and Mathematics. Materials were inititally intermixed but were separated from each other and arranged into their own series.</p></processinfo></c><c id="aspace_84a73cff7eb339ba05e18f33d9093e37" level="series"><did><unittitle>College of Social and Behavioral Sciences</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">11.66 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1967/2011" type="inclusive">1967-2011</unitdate></did><phystech id="aspace_e863fe4b01fae10d8cdeba6f8075f386"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Series contains 5" floppy disks.</p></phystech><scopecontent id="aspace_c343e6abfac70f83b3c9568fd0c8b874"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series documents the administration of the College of Social and Behavioral Sciences, particularly between the college's founding in 1978 and 1993. Series contains correspondence and letterbooks, graduate and undergraduate program reviews, three- and five-year plans, committee meeting agendas and minutes, task force and committee reports, degree and academic program proposals, faculty handbooks, administrative files related to the management of institutes including the Institutute for Research on Women and the Institute for Mesoamerican Studies. Some materials in this series predate its creation as a separate college and were likely retained from the period in which it was a Division within the College of Arts and Sciences.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_f073932d1ca68e45709984ca2ddbdefd"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Materials in this series have been maintained in their original order.</p></arrangement></c><c id="aspace_8d999308adeda900173209fc796297ac" level="series"><did><unittitle>Center for the Humanities Advisory Board</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.17 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1984/1988" type="inclusive">1984-1988</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_3c422b10d5759c9bf13683ffe3ab01c2"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Files in this series have arranged chronologically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_7efbd86bfe56b7be01a93b372ab90989"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series documents the administration of the Center for the Humanities, a University Center under the control of the College of Humanities and Fine Arts which put on conferences, seminars and fellowship programs.  Series includes Director's Reports, memoranda, correspondence, advisory board meeting minutes and proposals for faculty seminars.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e6a3626dfaee15705b11a54bcbc265a9" level="series"><did><unittitle>College of Arts and Sciences Ad Hoc Committee on Harassment</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.17 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1991/1996" type="inclusive">1991-1996</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_4e92b524830ee5af7d2cd1fe894d92de"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Materials in this series have been arranged chronologically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_e7184a21961ca68907ec454c2625c14b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series documents the drafting of the ad hoc committee's report on new procedures regarding allegations of harassment. Series includes the final report, drafts and revisions to the report, correspondence with the committee chair, sexual harassment policy documents from other universities, as well as publications produced by the University at Albany.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
