<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ua608</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Latin American, Caribbean, and US Latino Studies, Department of; Records</titleproper><titleproper>Latin American, Caribbean, and US Latino Studies, Department of; Records <num>ua608</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-04-03 14:30:24 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Department of Latin American, Caribbean, and US Latino Studies (LACS) Records</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua608</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1987/2021" type="inclusive">1987-2021</unitdate>
    <physloc id="aspace_8ace8a49355385940dd84380882ea230">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_d6a0585d380244bd964879add64e1547" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container>
    <container id="aspace_b5bee9bc34515f61fefb08c1c583152d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container>
    <container id="aspace_be4cf1ce2271d8d8d50a36f3d8978a27" label="mixed materials" type="Box">3</container>
    <container id="aspace_2c4dcedb131f282dcbb5dc9752768857" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container>
    <container id="aspace_c619549e057dd228ef9db6a01f27ad91" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">5</container>
    <container id="aspace_635f4d0ab84de20034038361ad6f98f9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">6</container>
  </did>
  <appraisal id="aspace_089816fea48572aaab2a6aba98ffa5d9">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>Administrative records of department offering interdisciplinary programs on the history, culture and development of Latin America and Caribbean nations and their relations between themselves and the United States.</p>  </appraisal>
  <processinfo id="aspace_43e599203dfd14a38aecad1b56b087f6">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection in unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_0f9086adb49da6a899fca3a60343f692">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Administrative records of the Department of Latin American, Caribbean, and US Latino Studies (LACS). Includes enrollment records, self studies, College of Arts &amp; Sciences (CAS) Dean correspondence, records of grants and other department initiatives, compact planning records, department executive committee records and minutes, department planning reports and self-studies.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_3af7c2685f6a144ca2c30d0f6e002fe4">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Most of the collection is in alphabetical order as maintained by the department. Some legal sized files were moved to Box 6 during transfer.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_2de0e9269205aa5749c91e92d17d1ca8">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Records were primarily managed by department administrator Librada Pimentel. All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in September 2021.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_2d1958e9a86fb83cf462f10d012ce874">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>This collection can be made available, but access must be arranged by the University Archivist to ensure all personally identifiable information has been removed.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_c0f3aac46da693247fa27cf9614daa64">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>

<p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>

<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>

<p>The M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collection and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_d17c2faea3431bfc213c92391ce1b34c">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Department of Latin American, Caribbean, and US Latino Studies (LACS) Records, 1987-2021. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the LACS Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="aspace_c97b510e02dead9c06f2701f02ddf28b">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The Department of Latin American, Caribbean, and US Latino Studies (LACS) offers interdisciplinary programs on the history, culture and development of Latin America and Caribbean nations, as well as the relations between these nations and the United States. LACS courses explore the interdependence between resident Latinx and immigrant populations in the United States and their countries of origin. Issues of race, gender, ethnicity and class are central to the curriculum.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Latin America</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Ethnic Groups</subject>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Academic Departments</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
