<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ua601.005.xml">ua601.005</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">University Art Museum; Records</titleproper><titleproper>University Art Museum; Records <num>ua601.005</num></titleproper><author>Mary-Margaret Giannini</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2016</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-12-15 01:06:22 -0500</date>.</creation></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2016 April 22</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Gregory Wiedeman</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>University Art Museum Records</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua601.005</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.33 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">69 captures</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1967/2013-06-01" type="inclusive">1997 June 16 - 2013 June 1</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_90993e59e48690c652486b49c593ed4a">Records of the Art Museum that was built on UAlbany's Uptown Campus with the support of Governor Nelson Rockefeller.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_20d6466afa252673883fca1a82110a95">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_aafba3ed3e74b20887d7d64e497e6194">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2016 by Mary-Margaret Giannini.</p>  </processinfo>
  <phystech id="aspace_35989651af09f043bf012646b08d2022">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Web Archives</p>  </phystech>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_8289542e4d2b276df65aa390c6fd1ae1">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_d06913d20920935aa115cbfdc3bda409">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_e37b0ecf0c631712977d4ec14b4d8c54">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by Kenneth D. Mosher, Jr., Class of 1946.<date normal="1998">1998</date></p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_f644cee0c290e0b95af8d16cf54e6c3b">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>The University Art Museum was officially opened and dedicated on October 5, 1967 as the University Art Gallery. However, its antecedents have been traced to at least 1929 when the State College News reported that the Art Department was sponsoring an exhibit of the work of Flemish artists. [1] While a formal gallery or exhibit place did not exist, the Art Department frequently sponsored such events, displaying art work in the hallways of the second and third floors of the Draper building as well often mounting exhibits in room 207 of Draper. In 1957, under the guidance and jurisdiction of Edward Cowley,who joined the art faculty in 1951 and served as head of the Art Department from 1955 to 1975, the Draper Gallery became an official entity. Existing simply as a room on the third floor of the Draper building in which lights and panels were installed, the Gallery nonetheless had an important function in supporting and enhancing the curriculum of the Art Department. Such a space not only allowed students to exhibit their own work but also enhanced the opportunity for them, as well as for members of the community, to be exposed to the work of local and regional artists. [2]</p><p> As a part of the new university campus, space in the Fine Arts Building was designated for an art gallery, which was officially opened in the Fall of 1967. The University Art Gallery was intended as a forum for contemporary art in the area. The "the initial exhibitions of the University Art Gallery, notably Nelson Rockefeller's collections and subsequent faculty shows, brought contemporary art of national and international significance to the Albany art public."[3] Furthermore, it has been argued that Rockefeller and the gallery's first director, Donald Mochon "had a vision of a gallery that would become a national show place for contemporary art of a regional, national and international stature."[4]</p><p> In 1971 the University Art Gallery, in conjunction with the Schenectady Museum and the Albany Institute of History and Art, enhanced its reputation as a forum for regional artists with the creation of the Mohawk-Hudson Regional Exhibit. Replacing the Artists of the Upper Hudson Exhibit which had been sponsored for over 35 years by the Albany Institute of History and Art, and the Schenectady Regional Exhibit which had been held at the Schenectady Museum for 16 years, the Mohawk-Hudson Regional Exhibit rotated among each sponsoring institution, each setting a different theme for the given exhibit that year. </p><p> Following the precedent set in the '20's, the University Art Gallery initially existed as a unit of the Art Department, but from the beginning it enjoyed a considerable amount of administrative and artistic freedom. Edward Cowley stated that he and Donald Mochon agreed that while the Gallery was a unit of the Art Department, its needs were not necessarily synonymous with those of an academic department. They decided that for the Gallery to be an efficient and effective body, it needed a degree of autonomy to operate and make its own policy decisions. Nonetheless, staff members from the Art Gallery played an integral role in the workings of the Art Department, attending faculty meetings and participating in policy decisions. [5] </p><p> The partial autonomy of the Art Museum from the Art Department was regularized in the mid- 1970's when the Art Gallery began reporting directly to the Dean of the College of Humanities and Fine Arts. As of 1993, the University Art Museum reports to Dean of the newly created College of Arts and Sciences. The Gallery and subsequently Museum continue to work closely with the Art Department. It plays a role in the M.A. and M.F.A. programs by exhibiting student's final exhibitions. Furthermore, the Art Museum staff often responds to the Art Department's standing invitation for their attendance at Department faculty meetings. Both the Art Museum and the Art Department use such meetings as an opportunity to share, discuss and coordinate their artistic efforts for the University at Albany, SUNY. [6]</p><p> In the 1991-1992 academic year the Gallery changed its name to the University Art Museum. [7] In doing so, the Museum has been able to better reflect its role as a space not only for the temporary exhibit of work, but also as a repository for a permanent collection. The educational role of the Art Museum made plain in its mission statement. </p><p> "The primary mission of the University Art Museum is public service and education which supports the core curriculum. The museum is a place for the exhibition of art and artifacts that reflect the diversity of peoples, cultures, and life experiences. Through its exhibitions, lectures, sponsored symposia, and film and video showings, the museum affords opportunities for interaction and collaboration among faculty, students and members of the larger community. The museum's program of developing the University's collections of contemporary art serves the artistic community by supporting living artists and preserving their work. It also creates a resource for enriching the campus environment though loans and exhibitions from these collections. Most essentially, the museum itself is a place for informal self-directed learning. The experience is voluntary and may provide a moment of reflection or a chance discovery that moves the visitor in a lasting way." [8]</p><p> Donald Mochon was the director of the Gallery from 1967 until his death in 1976. Before joining the staff at the State University of New York at Albany, he served as a professor of architecture at RPI. After his death, Donald Mochon was succeed by Nancy Liddle. Mrs. Liddle, a graduate of Indiana University and a member of the Art Department, had been involved with the Art Gallery from its inception aiding in planning the first year's exhibits. [9] Mrs. Liddle had served as the full time assistant director of the Gallery from 1966 to 1976, and director from 1976 to her retirement in 1993. Currently Marijo Dougherty is serving as the interim director of the museum.</p><p> [1] "Art Department Exhibits Flemish Paintings Here", State College News, p. 4, 11-22-29.</p><p> [2] Interview with Edward Cowley, Professor Emeritus, 7-19-93.</p><p> [3] "Strategy for Documenting 20th Century Art Activity in the Albany Region" developed by the McKinney Library Albany Institute of History and Art, December, 1991, p 26.</p><p> [4] Ibid., p. 31.</p><p> [5] Interview with Edward Cowley, Professor Emeritus, 7-19-93.</p><p> [6] Interview with Marijo Dougherty, Interim Director of Art Museum, 7-27-93. The exact date of the change in reporting relationships remains unclear.</p><p> [7] President's Report, 1992, p. 8.</p><p> [8] "Mission Statement, University Art Museum," State University of New York at Albany</p><p> [9] News Release 77-124, Office of Media Relations, "Nancy Liddle Heads University Art Gallery", 8-12-77, pp. 3-4. </p>    <chronlist>
      <head>List of Exhibitions</head>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1967 October 5-November 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Painting and Sculpture from Nelson A Rockefeller Collection</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1967 December</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Jack Bosson: Paintings and Prints</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1967 December</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Jazz Posters (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1967 December</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Recent Works in Fabric, Acrylic, and Stained Glass</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 January 8-25</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>A University Collects (NYU Collection)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 January 8-25</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>A Responsive Eye (M.O.M.A)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 February 16-March 14</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Big Prints (a national invitational)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 February 16-March 14</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>March-April 1</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 February 16-March 14</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>William Wilson: Recent Work</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 February 16-March 14</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Munson-Williams-Proctor:Artists of Central New York</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 May 19-June 9</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Monumental Brass Rubbings by Townsend Rich</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 May 19-June 9</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>William Clark: Recent Work</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 May 19-June 9</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Faculty Exhibition</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 May 19-June 9</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Student Exhibition</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 June 30-August 10</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Contemporary British Art (M.O.M.A.)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 September 15-October 13</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The Artist and His Subject (M.O.M.A.)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 September 15-October 13</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Guggenheim Fellows in Photography</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 September 15-October 13</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Raphael Villamil: Paintings</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 September 15-October 13</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Donald Ogier: Recent Paintings</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 October 29-November 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Project Art (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 October 29-November 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Carroll Cloar</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 October 29-November 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Articulate Subconsciousness</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 October 29-November 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Skidmore Faculty Exhibition (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 October 29-November 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Bette Saberlich: Ceramic Sculpture (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 December 10</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Donald Mochon: Sales</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 November 28-December 22</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Romare Bearden: Recent Work</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 November 28-December 22</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Donald Cole: Paintings</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1968 December 3-21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>William Wilson: Recent Works</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1969 January 7-19</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Young Printmakers (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1969 January 7-19</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Robles and Ehrenhalt: Paintings (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1969 January 26-February 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Alcoa Collection of Contemporary Art (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1969 January 26-February 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Degan Evans: Paintings</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1969 March 2-23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Architecture Without Architects</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1969 March 2-23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Critics Choice</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1969 March 21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Richard and Lee Wilkie in Concert</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1969 April 16-May 18</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>University Wide Convocation of the Arts</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1969 May 15</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Majority of One: A Celebration of Conscience</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1969 May 25-June 8</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Faculty-Student Exhibition</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1969 June 24-July 14</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Six Danish Graphic Artists</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1969 July 1-August 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Twenty Representational Artists</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1969 July 1-August 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Wall Hangings from the Museum of Modern Art</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1969 July 1-August 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Joe Alper - Photographer</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1969 September 29-October 19</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Kirk Newman: Bronze Sculpture (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1969 October 26-November 23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>A Leap of Faith: Art from Israel , Margaret Davies</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1969 December 15</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Green-Backed Money Pincher</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1970 January 4-February 22</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Contemporary American Painting and Sculpture from the Schwartz Collection (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1970 January 4-February 22</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>William Wilson: Recent Paintings</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1970 January 4-February 22</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Screen Prints (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1970 January 4-25</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Behan, Kerr, Walton, Scully (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1970 February</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master Thesis Exhibitions: Casper, Frinta, Madden (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1970 March 1-22</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Posters: International Poetry Forum (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1970 March 8 April 5</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Passionate Years (Post-Impressionist works on paper from M.O.M.A) (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1970 March 8 April 5</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Robert Cartmell: Recent Work</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1970 April 18-May 10</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>1970 Student Exhibition</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1970 May 7- 10</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The Many Sounds of Electronic Music: An International SamplingUniversity Art Museum</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1970 May 17-June 7</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Faculty-Student Exhibition (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1970 May 20-June 7</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master Thesis Exhibitions: Nieastri, Skolnik, Starkey</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1970 July 1-August 14</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Robert Rauschenberg Graphics</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1970 August 30-September 27</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Constructivist Tendencies (George and Edith Rickey Collection) (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1970 October 7-November 3</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The Representational Spirit</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1970 November 15-December 22</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Shozo Nagano: Paintings</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1970 November 15-December 22</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Marjorie Koster: Prints</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1970 December 6-22</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibition: Barsamian (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1971 January 18-February 21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Critic's Choice</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1971 January 18-February 21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Wayne Lennenbacker: Photographs</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1971 February</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Milton circa Olson, Charles T. O'Reilly: Reception</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1971 February 28-March 25</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Leonard Rossoman</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1971 February 28-March 25</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Oswego Exhibition</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1971 February 28-March 25</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Franz Kafka Exhibition</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1971 March 19</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>HSPCDH</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1971 April 1-25</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Washington Art</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1971 April 1-25</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Thom O'Connor: Prints and Drawings University Art Museum</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1971 April 1-25</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Spring 1971</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1971 April 1-25</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Fantauzzi, Fess, Penman and Spaziani</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1971 June 23-July</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Potsdam Prints (from the collection of the State University College at Potsdam)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1971 July 25-August 11</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Chilla, Jogo, Krems, Martin, Rodrigo, Schade, Steinbach</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1971 August 29-September 19</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Drawing USA/71 (organized by Minnesota Museum of Art)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1971 September 29-October 28</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Two Photographers: Alice Wells and Dan Blumberg (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1971 September 29-October 28</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Howe and Rheingold (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1971 September 29-October 28</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Selection `71 - Works from SUNY campuses</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1971 October 20-27</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master Thesis Exhibition: Reintsema (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1971 November 9-December 12</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Ten Artists from the Mohawk-Hudson Region</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1971 November 9-December 12</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Kenneth Welch: Jewelry</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 January 16-February 6</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Durer and His Time (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 January 16-February 6</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Eight Women Ceramists</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 January 16-February 6</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Xerox Prints by James Tyler Hoare (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 February 13-March 12</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Photographs by Roman Vishniac</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 February 13-March 12</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Prints by Robert Cartmell</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 February 13-March 12</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Illustrations for Children</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 March 19-April 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The World Between the Ox and the Swine: Hans Richter</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 March 19-April 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>New York State Craftsmen</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 March 19-April 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Neil Kagan: Photographer (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 March 19-April 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Studio Museum in Harlem (group exhibition)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 March 19-April 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Albert, Blanchfield, Jerome, McSheehy, Salata and Sauter (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 March 19-April 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Vietnam: Photo Essay June 18-July 16</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 March 19-April 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>L'Exposition Exhibition 1972 - co-sponsored by the United States</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 March 19-April 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>National Commission for UNESCO (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 July 24-August 4</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Kingston and Kirstel (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 August 27-September 20</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Our Own Things: University Collection (not in archival holdings) Larry Kagan and Sara Skolnik: Recent Works (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 October 1-November 5</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>New York Women Artists</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 October 1-November 5</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Photography of Canada (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 November 15-December 7</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Robert Cartmell (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 November 15-December 7</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Africoba (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 November 15-December 7</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Doody, Moore, Schwabe (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1972 December 10-17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Crafts Show: SUNYA Art Students (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1973 January 14-March 11</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The Civilization of Lluros: Norman Daly</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1973 April 2-29</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Australian Bark Paintings</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1973 April 2-29</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Stephen Antonakis: Neons</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1973 May 20-June 3</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>1973 Student Exhibition</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1973 May 20-June 3</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Ahern, Goodman, Herschberg, Ross, Thompson and Yohalem</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1973 June 24-August 5</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Artists of the Mohawk-Hudson Region</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1973 August 26-October 2</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The Iconography of the Picture Press</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1973 August 26-October 2</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>New Plastics (organized by Dennis Byng)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1973 October 16-November 18</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Walter Plate: Paintings, Drawings, Collages</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1973 October 16-November 18</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Martin Benjamin: photographs (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1973 November 26-December 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Langbart, Lipka, Price, Tierney and Nielsen</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1974 January 13-February 14</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Fantastics and Eccentrics</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1974 January 13-February 14</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Tight and Loose</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1974 February 24-March 27</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Wayne Lennebacker: Photographs</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1974 February 24-March 27</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Genocide: Photographs</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1974 April 14-May 5</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>1974 Student Exhibition</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1974 May 12-25</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: McDowell, Prince, Roman and Rowland</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1974 June 23-July 3</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Salon de Refuses (from 1974 Mohawk-Hudson Regional entries) (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1974 July 15-August 2</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Works on Paper: Thom O'Connor, Robert Cartmell and Peter Jogo</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1974 July 15-August 2</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Decade: Graphics in the Sixties (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1974 July 15-August 2</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Retz, Newby (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1974 August 25-October 3</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Five Artists from the Mohawk Hudson Region</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1974 August 25-October 3</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Selection `74: recent acquisitions to the University Collection (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1974 August 25-October 3</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Monumental Brass Rubbings by Townsend Rich (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1974 October 13-November 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Dan Budnik: Photographs of Albany Medical Center</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1974 October 13-November 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Terminal Iron Works: David Smith at Bolton Landing (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1974 October 13-November 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The Sculpture of Cyprus (Museum of Fine Arts, Boston)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1974 November 24-December 14</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Women in France: Photographs</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1974 November 24-December 14</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Tarlton and Mendelson (not in archival holdings)University Art Museum</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1975 January 19-February 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Nell Blaine: Paintings</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1975 January 19-February 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>William Wilson: Paintings</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1975 February 23-March 23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Martha Jackson Collection</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1975 February 23-March 23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Tod Bryant: Photographs (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1975 March 14</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Jazz Live</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1975 April 1-28</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>1975 Student Exhibition</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1975 May 4-25</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Ellis, Golash, Ioepitzi, Wawrla, Rivera, Rucker and Zeman-Rogers (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1975 June 14- August 7</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Exhibition by Artists of Mohawk-Hudson Region</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1975 June 30-August 8</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>55 Mercer Street</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1975 July 24-August 8</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Art Council Collection</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1975 July 24-August 8</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Bernatowitz, Keevil and Stewart (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1975 August 25-September 28</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Garo Antresian</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1975 August 25-September 28</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Clinton Adams</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1975 October 5-November 6</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Gerald DiGuisto Sculpture</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1975 October 5-November 6</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Irena Altmanova-Frinta: Pastels</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1975 November 23-December 21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Coast to Coast Coasters: Organized by Robert Cartmell</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1975 November 19-December 5</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Korber, Russ and Walker (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1975 December 8-21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Calo and Edelheit (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1975 December 3-21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Mochon Drawings: Auction of 300 drawings by Donald Mochon (benefit for Art Gallery)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1976 January 19-Feburary 15</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Paintings by Robert Huot</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1976 March 14-April 14</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Contemporary American Stage Design (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1976 April 9-30</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Jansson, LaPlante, Miller, Moskowitz, Stone</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1976 April 9-30</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>and Turner (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1976 April 9-30</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Portraits of Edith Rickey</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1976 April 9-30</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Ceramic Sculpture by Niles Wallace</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1976 June 27-August 8</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>1976 Artists of the Mohawk-Hudson Region</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1976 June 28-August 7</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Chamberlain, Chereskin and Armstrong</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1976 August 8</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Ted Chereskin: An Exhibition of Cast Lucite Sculpture</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1976 August 30-September 26</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Faculty Exhibition (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1976 August 30-September 26</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Sons and Others: Women Artists See Men</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1976 October 3-November 7</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The Sculpture of John Ferro</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1976 October 3-November 7</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The Manipulation of Light: 10 photographers (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1976 October 3-November 7</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Calligraphic Collages by Wolfgang Roth (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1976 November 14-December 19</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Paintings by Marilyn Giersbach</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1976 November 14-December 19</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Rhodes and Taylor (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1977 January 17-February 13</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Paintings and Prints by Richard Callner</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1977 January 17-February 13</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Alvin Napper: Photographs</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1977 January 17-February 13</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>William Cristenberry: Photographs</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1977 March 5-31</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>University-wide Exhibitions by SUNY students</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1977 April 11-May 1</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Annual Student Exhibition (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1977 April 11-May 1</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Kathleen Grove and Larry List: Recent Work</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1977 May 8-29</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Boyer, Garrett, Rivette and Bryant</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1977 May 8-29</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Medieval Musical Notations: organized by Drew Hartzell of the</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1977 May 8-29</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>University at Albany Music Department (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1977 June 26-August 5</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Jim Dine Prints</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1977 July 16-August 5</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Cho, Davidson and Faiola</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1977 July 16-August 5</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Annual Faculty Exhibition (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1977 August 29-September 25</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Contemporary Yugoslav Prints</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1977 September 30-October 23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Printed Quilts/Quilted Prints</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1977 September 30-October 23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Dougherty and Tsamardinos</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1977 October 30-November 27</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>A Don Mochon Celebration (two copies)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1977 December 4-23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Frances Simches Memorial Exhibition</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1977 December 4-23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Bernatowitz, Buerkley and Johnson</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1978 January 23-February 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Graphic Artists of New York State (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1978 January 23-February 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Fantasy Sculpture: Joan Danziger (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1978 February 27-April 2</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>J. Pindyck Miller: Sculpture</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1978 February 27-April 2</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Polly Hope: Stuffed Pictures (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1978 March 19- April 30</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Ed Cowley</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1978 April 10-May 1</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Annual Student Exhibition (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1978 May 8-21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Adam, Bida, Bartholomay, Delis, Golojuch,</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1978 May 8-21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Grindle, Gugell, Heikolf, Honon, Kempf, Silver and Lawrence</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1978 June 17-September 1</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>World Print Competition (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1978 July 5-August 3</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Blake, Dietrich, Feroleto, Kite and Saddlemire (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1978 September 12-October 8</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Annual Faculty Exhibition (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1978 September 12-October 8</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>On the Offset Press</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1978 September 12-October 8</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>David Hayes: Sculpture Out-of-Doors</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1978 September 22-October 22</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>I Am Not Blind: organized by the Wadsworth Atheneum</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1978 October 19-November 20</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Tenth Street Days (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1978 October 19-November 20</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Mohawk-Hudson Invitational: Rheingold and Rymanowski</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1978 December 1-21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Young American Printmakers</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1978 December 1-21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Antos, Formanek, Labaree and Mastrianni</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1979 January 22-February 18</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Faculty Choice</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1979 January 22-February 18</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>S.A.G.A. (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1979 March 2-April 1</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Mauricio Lasansky</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1979 April 17-29</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Annual Student Exhibition (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1979 May 11-27</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Califano, Colon, Eadie, Graham, Greenfield,</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1979 May 11-27</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Hogan, Johnson, Leavitt, Malloy, McFerran, Pell, Pletts, Rehm, Spitsbergen and Wager (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1979 June 25-July 29</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>1979 Artists of the Mohawk-Hudson Region</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1979 August 28-September 23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Hall, Rounds, Witkowski and Woolsey (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1979 August 28-September 23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Traditions in American Basketry</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1979 October 6-November 18</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The Sculpture of Richard Stankiewicz 1953-1979</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1979 December 4-20</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Irish Tinkers: Photographs by SUNYA Anthropology</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1979 December 4-20</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Professor George Gmelch</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1979 December 4-20</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Eight from the Northern Interior: Handmade Books and Broadsides</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1979 December 4-20</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Brownell, Dutt, Edgar, King, Meyers, Holdridge</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1980 January 22-February 29</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The American Landscape: Paintings by Allan D'Arca</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1980 January 22-February 29</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Phyllis Galembo: Recent Color Photographs (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1980 January 22-February 29</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Archaeology--Past, Present, Future: Photographs (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1980 March 14-April 20</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Dorothea Lange: Her Collection (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1980 March 14-April 20</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Jason Stewart: Works on Paper (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1980 May 6-25</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Giscombe, Harland, Kim, Levitt, Mulero, Rosenthal, Tansey, Strauss, Townsend</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1980 July 8- August 31</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Clay, Fiber, Metal (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1980 June 24-August 1</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Mowhawk-Hudson Regional Art Exhibition</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1980 September 4-October 5</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The Sculpture of Hugh Townley</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1980 September 4-October 5</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Invisible Light: Infrared Photographs (organized by Robert Cartmell)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1980 October 18-November 23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>U.S. Eye: Photography (organized for 1980 Olympics) (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1980 December 2-18</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Gessinger, Kingsbury, Langworthy, Robert</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1980 December 2-18</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Edward Cowley: Recent Works (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1981 January 26-February 28</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>University Student Art Exhibition</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1981 January 26-February 28</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Mohawk-Hudson Invitational Exhibition: Ethel Magafan and Robert Blood</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1981 March 1-April 26</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>O. Louis Guglielmi Retrospective</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1981 March 17-April 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Photos of Romanesque Mural Paintings (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1981 May 10-24</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibition: Barron, Blechman, Carr, Cavalier, Fontaine, Gala, Gallagher, Gerstenberger, Greenberg, Gonzalez, Hass, Johnson, Kreisher, Lineweaver, Long, Maurello, Palmersheim, Scullion, Silverstein, Witzel</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1981 June 24-August 1</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Brooke Alexander: A Decade of Print Publishing</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1981 June 23-July 12</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Jeffrey Studenroth: Watercolors (Lobby) (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1981 June 30-July 31</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Margaret Crawford: Serigraphs and Small Sculpture (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1981 September 8-October 7</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Nathan Oliveira: Print Retrospedtive 1949-1978</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1981 September 8-October 7</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Aldo Casanova: Recent Bronzes</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1981 October 23-December 18</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Yugoslav Drawings: Current Trends</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1981 November 5-December 12</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Small Sculpture by Vava Stankovic, Marja Vallila, Stephen Day</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1982 January 26-February 28</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Anand Manu (Bill Wilson): Recent Works</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1982 January 26-February 28</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Paul Garland: Large Watercolor Abstractions</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1982 March 16-April 18</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Fabric Into Art</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1982 March 16-April 18</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The University at Albany Permanent Collection: Selected Works from 1970 to 1980</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1982 May 4-23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Bartholomay, Bayly, Benenson, Bowen, Brzezowski, Curtin, Fair, Febbo, Gordon, Johnson, Karp, Lohner, Matzke, Mohn, Mooney, Popper, Scharl, Spelich, Simon, Triedman, Wagoner, Weinman (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1982 June 24-August 1</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>1982 Exhibition by Artists of the Mohawk Hudson Region</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1982 September 7-October 10</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Edward Koren: Prints and Drawings</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1982 October 22-November 21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Lotti Jacobi: Thirty Photographs (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1982 October 22-November 21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Shamans and Spirits: Myths and Medical Symbolism in Eskimo Art (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1982 October 22-November 21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Edward Cowley: Free-Hand Perspective (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1982 December 7-19</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Fall 1982 SUNYA Student Exhbition (not in archival holdings) Museum</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1983 January</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Movie Memorabilia: From the collection of Arthur Lennig (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1983 February 12-March 25</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Thom O'Connor: 20 Year Print Retrospective</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1983 February 12-20</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Albany Impressions (Lobby) (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1983 February 23-March 25</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Black Women Achievements Against the Odds (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1983 April 19-May 22</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters of Fine Arts Thesis Exhibitions: Bowen, Chapin, Curtin, Fair, Formanek, Frakes, Gordon, Hass, Matzke, Mooney, Mulero, Row, Smith, Wagoner, Weinman (not in archival holdings)University Art</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1983 June 28-August 5</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Atelier 17: New Directions</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1983 June 28-July 10</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters Thesis Exhibitions: Bari, Andersen, Mary Anderson, Arat, Ashley, Auger, Bonk, Corigliano, Coughtry, DeAndrade, Fitterer, Jaremko, Keane, Lorenz, Lynes, Ressler, Ripps, Scultz, Stinson (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1983 July 15-Augut 5</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Abstract/Concrete: Clay works by Regis Brodie and Bill Knoble (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1983 September 13-October 23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>New Decorative Art (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1983 September 13-October 23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Artists at Large: Photographs by Rollie McKenna</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1983 October 18-December 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Recent Work by the Univerity Art Faculty</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1983 November 1-December 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Recognitions: Faces and Places / Photographs by Charles Traub</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 January 24-February 26</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Mohawk-Hudson Invitational: Enid Blechman and Allen Grindle (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 January 24-February 26</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Robert Motherwell: Lyric Suite</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 January 24-February 26</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Prints by Fairfield Porter (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 January 24-February 26</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Oshima/MacGregor - Paintings (Lobby)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 January 24-February 26</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Albany Impressions Suite</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 March 9-April 13</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Rural Vistas: Rediscovery of the American Landscape (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 March 9-April 13</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Twentieth Century American Watercolor (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 March 9-April 13</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Richard Stankiewicz Memorial Exhibition</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 May 3-20</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Fine Arts Thesis Exhibitions: Arat, Anderson, Ashley, DeAndrade, Gala, Giscombe, Jaremko, Leavitt, Lohner, Moninski, Park, Ripps, Rogers, Scharl, Schultz, Spelich, Nancy Engle: Photographs (Lobby) (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 June 26-August 3</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Forever Wild: Photographs from the Adirondacks by Eliot Porter (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 June 26-August 3</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Glory Glory: Photographs by Lionel J. M. Delevingne (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 June 26-August 3</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Freda Hall: Flower Photographs (Lobby) (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 June 26-August 3</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Arbor Hill Children's Art (Lobby) (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 June 26-July 12</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Arts Thesis Exhibitions: Chen, Hollinde, Keays, Lee, Ojalvo, Roberts, Rolando, Testo, Tofield (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 July 17-August 3</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Two Polish Printmakers: Andrzej Kalina and Andrzej Dworokowski (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 July 17- 24</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Two Cool Evenings</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 September 4-November 14</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>New York Painters: New Directions (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 September 4-November 14</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The Art of Adornment: Contemporary Wearable Art from Africa and the Diaspora (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 September 4-November 14</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Videotape: Six Works by John Sturgeon (West Gallery) (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 September 4-November 14</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Mural Drawings: Humanities Lounge Project (Lobby) (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1984 November 30-December 21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Fine Arts Thesis Exhibitions: Coughtry, Schaming, Stewart (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1985 January 22-January 27</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The Janus Press 1975-80 - Claire VanVliet</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1985 January 22-January 27</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Artists' Books: Callner, O'Connor, Schade</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1985 February 13-March 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Eadweard Muybridge: Animal Locomotion</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1985 February 13-March 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>New York Printmakers: A Dozen Directions</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1985 February 13-March 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Helmmo Kinderman: Camera Works</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1985 April 9-May 19</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Fine Arts Thesis Exhibitions: Benenson, Depew, Keane, Klein, Ojalvo, Roberts, Rolando, Testo (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1985 April 9-24</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Arts Thesis Exhbitions: Chang, Lee, Nutting, Williams (not in archival holdings)University Art May 1-19</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1985 April 9-24</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Arts Thesis Exhibitions: Webster-Frederick, Reid, Smith (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1985 June 25-August 4</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>1985 Artists of the Mohawk-Hudson Region</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1985 September 4-15</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Maritime Prints (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1985 September 4-October 13</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Edward Mayer Sculpture (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1985 September 4-October 13</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Screenprints by Contemporary Painters (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1985 October 25-November 24</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>David Hockney: Photocollages (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1985 October 25-November 24</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Photos from the Collection of the University (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1985 December 6-20</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Fine Arts Thesis Exhibitions: Chen, Egan, Hollinde, Lee,</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1985 December 6-20</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>McCartan, Murphy (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1985 December 6-20</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Arts Exhibitions: Cheng, Peters, Rochow (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1986 February 12-March 23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>New York State--An Aerial Perspective: Photographs by Marilyn Bridges</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1986 February 12-March 23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Transparencies--Multi-media works by Ten New York Artists</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1986 April 14-May 18</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Fine Arts Thesis Exhibitions: Avakian, Brandt, Charlton, Englander, Goren, Mohn, Perkins, Warner</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1986 April 14-May 18</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Arts Exhibitions: Rogula, Simmons, Siren, Sweet (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1986 June 24-August 1</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>A Birthday Party: 50 Years of the Mohawk Hudson Regional</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1986 September 2-October 19</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The Faces of the City: Albany Portraits from Three Centuries</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1986 November 1-26</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Olokun Imagery/Objects of Prayer: Cibachrome Photographs by</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1986 November 1-26</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Phyllis Galembo (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1986 November 1-26</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Bill Wilson: Return to Landscape</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1986 November 1-26</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Recent Works by Five Faculty Artists: Ballester, Buchman, Carson,</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1986 November 1-26</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Plaxco and Vallila (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1986 December 9-21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Fine Arts Thesis Exhibitions: Kreishner, Nutting, Vatsky,</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1986 December 9-21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Williams Zupnick</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1986 December 9-21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Masters of Arts Exhibitions: Ryder, Valenti (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1987 January 20-25</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Arts Exhibitions: Ryder, Valenti</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1987 February 3-March 1</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>New Drawings - The Drawing Center, NY</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1987 February 3-March 1</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Elders of the Tribe</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1987 March 10-April 10</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Beijing/New York: Avant-Garde Chinese Art</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1987 March 10-April 10</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The New York School: Prints from the University Art Collection (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1987 April 21-May 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Fine Arts Thesis Exhibitions: Chen-yu, DePietro, Peters, Rochow, Stiglich, Wineland (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1987 April 21-May 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Arts Thesis Exhibitions: Clernents, Cuadra, DiGangi, Gray Be, Leff, Liburdi, Papele, Schoonmaker, Trabka, Valentino (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1987 June 13-September 6</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>1987 Mohawk Hudson Regional Exhibition (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1987 September 8-October 11</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Edward Cowley - A Retrospective (two copies)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1987 September 8-October 11</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Donald Mochon Remembered (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1987 October 24-November 22</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Katherine Porter: Recent Paintings (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1987 October 24-November 22</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Sandi Fellman: Japanese Tattoo Series (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1987 October 24-November 22</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Youth Books of Yore: From Pilgrim's Progress to Pinocchio (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1987 December 8-23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Fine Arts Thesis Exhibitions: Anderson, Kahn, Shoebridge, Swearingen (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1987 December 8-23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Arts Thesis Exhibitions: Brady, Brenner, Miller, Squillace, Wang, Yan</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1988 January 20-February 21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Recent Works on Paper by the Fine Arts Faculty (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1988 January 20-February 21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The Art Students League: Selections from the Permanent Collection Undergraduate Artists (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1988 March 8-April 10</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Contemporary Finnish Prints</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1988 March 8-April 10</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Kosta Bogdonovitch (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1988 March 8-April 10</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Quilts by Linda O'Connor (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1988 April 26-May 15</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Fine Arts Thesis Exhibition: Chinian, Huntington, Machell, Ryder (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1988 April 26-May 15</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Arts Thesis Exhibition: Bocci, Woodbury (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1988 June 17-July 24</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Artists of the Mohawk-Hudson Region Juried Exhibition</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1988 September 6-October 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The Paintings of Ethel Schwabacher</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1988 September 6-October 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Alumni I</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1988 September 6-October 9</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Living gods/Hindu Faces (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1988 October 25-November 23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Richard Callner: A Retrospective Exhibition</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1988 October 25-November 23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Four Centuries of Italian Master Drawings</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1988 December 9-December 23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Fine Arts Thesis Exhibition: DiGangi, Papele, Walters (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1988 December 9-December 23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Arts Thesis Exhibition: Dermansky, Martin (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1989 January 24-March 10</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Contemporary American Collage: 1960-1986 (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1989 January 24-March 10</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Photographs from the University Collection (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1989 January 24-March 10</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Albany Project: An installation by Susan Rees (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1989 March 14-April 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Seymour Drumlevitch (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1989 March 14-April 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Photographs from the University Collection (cont'd) (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1989 May 2-May 21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Fine Arts Thesis Exhibition: Clements, Michael, Squillace, Tabka (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1989 May 2-May 21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Arts Thesis Exhibition: Alterman, Bae, Buvoli, Grunwaldt, Harris (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1989 June 20-August 1</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Reclaiming Paradise: American Women Photograph the Land (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1989 September 5-October 15</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Sculpture'89: Fellowship Recipients of the New York Foundation</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1989 September 5-October 15</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>for the Arts (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1989 September 5-October 15</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Olivia Parker: Anima Motrix (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1989 October 24-November 19</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Zuka: The French Revolution through American Eyes</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1989 December 8-December 21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Fine Arts Thesis Exhibition (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1989 December 8-December 21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Arts Thesis Exhibition (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 January 16-February 25</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>University at Albany Fine Arts Department Faculty Exhibition (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 March 13-April 12</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Aaron Karp (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 March 13-April 12</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The Atelier Project (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 March 13-April 12</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The Albany Impressions Series:Editions made for artists at the print studios of the University (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 May 1-20</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Fine Arts Thesis Exhibitions</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 May 1-20</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Arts Thesis Exhibition</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 June 26-August 3</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Antonio Frasconi: An Artist's Journal</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 June 26-August 3</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Edward Colker</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 September 5-November l8</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Contemporary Art of the African Diaspora (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 September 5-November l8</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>New York Foundation for the Arts Fellowship Recipients (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 September 5-November l8</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Portraits of an Epoch: The Drawings of Benedikt F. Dolbin (West Gallery)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 December 1-21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Fine Arts Thesis Exhibitions (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 December 1-21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Arts Thesis Exhibitions (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 February 2-March 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Our Land/Ourselves: American Indian Contemporary Artists</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 April 3-April 21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Robert Arrandale Williams: The American Terrain</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 April 3-April 21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Rudolph Serra: Sculpture (West Gallery) (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 May 4-26</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Fine Arts Thesis Exhibitions: Krepfle, Lail, Lipman, Schloemer, Valentino, Walters, Wright-Sedam (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 May 4-26</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Arts Thesis Exhibitions: Rock, Ryan, and Setchfield (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 July 16-September 8</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Artists of the Mohawk-Hudson Region Juried Exhibition</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 October 1-November 24</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Art Faculty Exhibition</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 October 1-November 24</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Dorothy Lathrop: A Centenary Celebration (West Gallery)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 December 4-22</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Fine Arts Thesis Exhibitions: Brenner, Ginett, Jones,</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 December 4-22</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Lewis, McGreevy (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1990 December 4-22</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Arts Thesis Exhibitions: Flynn, Green (not in archival holdings)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1992 January 15-February 16</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Gardens: Real and Imagined</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1992 March 3-April 12</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Through the Object's Eye: Paintings by Joan Semmel</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1992 March 3-April 12</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Swiss Poster Art 1906-1990 from the Ciba-Geigy Collection</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1992 March 3-April 12</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>California/Albany (West Gallery)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1992 March 3-April 12</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The View From Here: Claremont</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1992 May 8-17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Fine Arts Thesis Exhibitions</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1992 May 8-17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Master of Arts Thesis Exhibitions</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1992 June 23-July 26</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Convergence: Eight Black Photographers</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1992 September 12-November 24</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Living Traditions: Mexican Popular Arts (two copies)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1993 March 2- April 23</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Jasper Johns: Prints and Multiples</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1994 March 8 - April 17</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Dennis Byng, Richard Callner, Edward Cowley: Creating After Teaching: Three Faculty Emeriti (two copies)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1994 June 7 - July 31</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Artists of the Mohawk Hudson Region Juried Exhibit</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1994 September 24-November 13</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Democratic Vistas: 150 Years of American Art from Regional Collections (two copies)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1995 January 17-February 19</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Warrington Colescott: A Retrospective Exhibition</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1995 March 25-May 21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Geoffrey Holder: Painter</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1996 March 12-April 21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Robert Cartmell: Painting, Prints, Drawings, 1971-1996. A Twenty-five Year Retrospective</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1996 June 5-July 21</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Artists in the Kitchen (two copies)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1996 September 7-November 3</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Visions of New York State: The Historical Paintings of L. F. Tantillo (includes a copy of the teachers guide)</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1996 September 7-November 3</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Witness and Legacy: Contemporary Art About the Holocaust</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1997 June 17-July 31</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>1997 Artists of the Mohawk Hudson Region Juried Exhibit</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1997 September 21-November 9</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Memory and Morning. Shared Cultural Experience</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
    </chronlist>
  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_d21e83d451ba459a4b4cc5717b729a14">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Exhibit Publications contains exhibit leaflets, flyers, catalogs, and programs from 1967 to 1993. All exhibits held by the University Art Gallery and subsequently Art Museum are listed. The items are arranged chronologically by exhibition. The list of exhibits was compiled and annotated by both the Museum and the University Archives to describe holdings relating to the exhibits. While all exhibits held by the University Art Gallery and subsequently Art Museum are listed, full documentation for all the exhibits may not exist. For the most part the University Archives and the University Art Gallery have duplicate holdings. Where an item is not held by the University Archives the note (not in archival holdings) will appear.</p><p> Newspaper clippings were gathered by both the University Archives and the Art Gallery and subsequent Museum. For the most part, clippings were gathered from local publications relation to exhibits.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_48e6aef34e2aba07189df38f86390a30">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is divided into two series: exhibit publications, and a clippings file.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_64ea606d34b0d5b624cb73b50f01283d">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, University Art Museum Records, 1967-1993. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the University Art Museum Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">Art</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art museum architecture</subject>
    <genreform source="meg">Web Archives</genreform>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Centers &amp; Institutes</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Wages -- New York (State)</subject>
    <corpname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_a91bb16283b3d9c2e97358d0c9c30507" level="series"><did><unittitle>Exhibition Publications</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1967/1997" type="inclusive">1967-1997</unitdate></did></c><c id="aspace_b73b6e93789e5f387a283d4b0f15f566" level="series"><did><unittitle>Clippings</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1965/1992" type="inclusive">1965-1992</unitdate></did></c><c id="aspace_de18824410651febeec71baef299edf4" level="series"><did><unittitle>Art Museum Website</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">69 captures</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1997-06-16/2013-06-01" type="inclusive">1997 June 16 - 2013 June 1</unitdate><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial></did><phystech id="aspace_fe12a59ce11c3374b3a5c8a678c5a0a8"><head>URL</head><p>http://www.albany.edu/museum</p></phystech><phystech id="aspace_b0e5c12df57604df8def170e705de7cd"><head>Access Requirements</head><p>The item contains web archives preserved as WARC files. They must be access though web archival replay tools such as the "Wayback Machine." The links here direct you to files hosted by the Internet Archive, but you may also request WARC files.</p></phystech><acqinfo id="aspace_fd3dcdf98c7be1fbc61bbc7d03851a69"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>
Web crawling is managed through the Internet Archive's Archive-It service.</p><p>This item is not a seed within an Archive-it collection, but capures of this page are found within: </p><p><b>collection:</b> University at Albany, SUNY Website</p><p><b>created_date:</b> 2012-09-17T13:15:00Z</p><p><b>created_by:</b> bkeough</p><p><b>state:</b> ACTIVE</p><p><b>last_updated_date:</b> 2016-09-26T23:38:05Z</p><p><b>last_updated_by:</b> system</p></acqinfo><controlaccess><genreform source="meg">Web Collection</genreform></controlaccess><c id="aspace_26eb23b6d5206205de780d6870cb3c18" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum, Albany, NY</unittitle><unitdate normal="1997-06-16/1997-06-16">1997 June 16</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/19970616070847/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum, Albany, NY" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum, Albany, NY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_8667c1192e08bed59c737d606c2246a2"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_f28f4321b2cdd127d7813e64a17cfbbb" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum, Albany, NY</unittitle><unitdate normal="1997-07-25/1997-07-25">1997 July 25</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/19970725200839/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum, Albany, NY" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum, Albany, NY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_bfe77192fc707cfe7d76e1a69c6a0cc2"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_20a0ba6b75871d7588dfff5b84bb1753" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum, Albany, NY</unittitle><unitdate normal="1997-10-22/1997-10-22">1997 October 22</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/19971022085749/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum, Albany, NY" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum, Albany, NY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_663e26fb0c09f5df47dcb124db142765"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_061e1cc4d67913b9f829c12bc122a6bc" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum, Albany, NY</unittitle><unitdate normal="1999-01-16/1999-01-16">1999 January 16</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/19990116233116/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum, Albany, NY" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum, Albany, NY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_6cf88eff81196fabe10ca49dd10e21ce"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_0e8862cedf87a9b704d48bad613bdfbc" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum, Albany, NY</unittitle><unitdate normal="1999-02-19/1999-02-19">1999 February 19</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/19990219130341/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum, Albany, NY" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum, Albany, NY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_e3ee0738bf08bc2798b2a35055923b41"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_ebb252f8b60747ebdb351fa59c14a2bf" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum, Albany, NY</unittitle><unitdate normal="2000-02-29/2000-02-29">2000 February 29</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20000229213146/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum, Albany, NY" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum, Albany, NY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_95d10117368c881edd78024bdaeae80c"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_f6bacecb6cf09cda90cdbb268d3b4057" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum, Albany, NY</unittitle><unitdate normal="2000-08-15/2000-08-15">2000 August 15</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20000815214557/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum, Albany, NY" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum, Albany, NY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_cac39db7902c9d704ef507a754a023d5"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_6db29d644c91b90329657635f3f082bd" level="item"><did><unittitle>Page Not Found -- University at Albany</unittitle><unitdate normal="2000-10-03/2000-10-03">2000 October 3</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20001003063310/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Page Not Found -- University at Albany" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Page Not Found -- University at Albany</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_be05948a982fdfad4b4b94ae0d75209e"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_f8c8a7e19955386dbb2f7c05e5fcf995" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum, Albany, NY</unittitle><unitdate normal="2001-01-24/2001-01-24">2001 January 24</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20010124062800/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum, Albany, NY" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum, Albany, NY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_6188ca9a26ec81963fea2ec7daa3933c"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_8b1169a9c63b7468a8bbd526a103d769" level="item"><did><unittitle>Page Not Found -- University at Albany</unittitle><unitdate normal="2001-04-22/2001-04-22">2001 April 22</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20010422045929/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Page Not Found -- University at Albany" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Page Not Found -- University at Albany</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_5774b548ad7ed51c595165b497153511"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_470e8d0cf309fbd8c44b7c09647b8839" level="item"><did><unittitle>&amp;lt;title&amp;gt; not present</unittitle><unitdate normal="2001-04-24/2001-04-24">2001 April 24</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20010424150707/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="&amp;lt;title&amp;gt; not present" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>&lt;title&gt; not present</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_5b7fe704648e6745d2e867799c0ff0fd"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_73d105c06a74c41e44c172f7a2e1762a" level="item"><did><unittitle>&amp;lt;title&amp;gt; not present</unittitle><unitdate normal="2001-06-03/2001-06-03">2001 June 3</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20010603031427/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="&amp;lt;title&amp;gt; not present" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>&lt;title&gt; not present</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_3c402c2d3bb25d332476fd7afdd5bdaf"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_4e816527f159dad18cad46e9aca994f1" level="item"><did><unittitle>&amp;lt;title&amp;gt; not present</unittitle><unitdate normal="2001-06-03/2001-06-03">2001 June 3</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20010603031428/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="&amp;lt;title&amp;gt; not present" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>&lt;title&gt; not present</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_60df5c6a4a6df246d940375ff4a0255f"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_43eee128d066dfa6656b2089fa009356" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum, University at Albany</unittitle><unitdate normal="2001-08-11/2001-08-11">2001 August 11</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20010811134747/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum, University at Albany" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum, University at Albany</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_d0eb4cbaf2cce45badf1883be7474416"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_a90b3c3a28a8bd5d4ffdd9d6cf0f72e3" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum, University at Albany</unittitle><unitdate normal="2001-11-09/2001-11-09">2001 November 9</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20011109233611/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum, University at Albany" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum, University at Albany</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_adc8a9e36fc2836f932e9d4a640084f1"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_2b5b578ed217d5cfaf0db6fbd72dbf9d" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum, University at Albany</unittitle><unitdate normal="2002-08-06/2002-08-06">2002 August 6</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20020806075821/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum, University at Albany" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum, University at Albany</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_92cfd1e09d0e02a4f6fee8e08e710112"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_b1dec1e291038554728a98e51c92d640" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum, University at Albany</unittitle><unitdate normal="2002-10-10/2002-10-10">2002 October 10</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20021010094329/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum, University at Albany" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum, University at Albany</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_1b95a69a1d02ec578bae769f44541104"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_0a4ba891c311766a630be25d1ad8bd5f" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum | University at Albany </unittitle><unitdate normal="2003-12-04/2003-12-04">2003 December 4</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20031204221019/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum | University at Albany " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum | University at Albany</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_fefc615542c7a1bfdbc09c442da940eb"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_02a6bd2204ff143a3f9d82201ef29788" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum | University at Albany </unittitle><unitdate normal="2004-10-13/2004-10-13">2004 October 13</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20041013092239/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum | University at Albany " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum | University at Albany</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_f4dce7bb2982be8218d0b1f28dfa2cb0"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_11db9cdb870c34b8342d661a69acbaa6" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum | University at Albany </unittitle><unitdate normal="2005-02-03/2005-02-03">2005 February 3</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20050203014459/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum | University at Albany " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum | University at Albany</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_88d56e1a6a5859a3073ec5d9d3c9dae0"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_57ef08d62604e1fd2cca5d45c680d982" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum | University at Albany </unittitle><unitdate normal="2006-04-02/2006-04-02">2006 April 2</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20060402235757/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum | University at Albany " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum | University at Albany</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_6a4391d9d92aec90216945820919afbd"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_c02e19e5a0a9ce902ff83c2dc9801732" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2010-05-27/2010-05-27">2010 May 27</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100527130711/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_949f033ce6dc1f82ab83682a8337d524"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_095a984a09a54c4d0803bb163e9b52d9" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2010-12-07/2010-12-07">2010 December 7</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101207191103/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_c1fed5047c98bcc06281ccd21ef6f8bd"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_6ba3e4acf9c85c253ae11e6a8274f774" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2010-12-08/2010-12-08">2010 December 8</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101208212503/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_730307e2f13c5413b0da4cba8231cd24"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_0fbb95c71030c28415c3b79f61398aa9" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2010-12-15/2010-12-15">2010 December 15</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101215185325/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_ad5c3bc0642f84d048fdaab3cefaf5c5"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_13fd7a056b2b47a1df8f0cce754969a8" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2011-01-05/2011-01-05">2011 January 5</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110105154706/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_33c2bbb660ff4c3cb39dbc1f62c576d6"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_524c37b5342e96a1fecafb7ed36620b5" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2011-01-12/2011-01-12">2011 January 12</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110112140624/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_3d45df366777dae81e37302d84bac4b5"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_2887310e120da8b7fc8709e8461fd111" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2011-02-07/2011-02-07">2011 February 7</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110207090948/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_0a753031212d665db7c02350ed29dc06"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_df9ff264f1d3b9f7fda43c28b687b452" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2011-03-09/2011-03-09">2011 March 9</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110309084235/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_b5b1874f34a235c67352c9daf974c0e7"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_3f6440180b6a72a3146e70bfdb9f4760" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2011-03-23/2011-03-23">2011 March 23</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110323142321/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_508b23ea5bfccc7b3d901708a3e1772f"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_9bd965cdd96a2daf94fc0dcf6556b270" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2011-04-27/2011-04-27">2011 April 27</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110427164448/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_159271abec42ab5922a9a09acd4163e8"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_1bb41fe55796360ea5f79eb76dc52b2d" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2011-05-18/2011-05-18">2011 May 18</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110518192309/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_f0369085165a6d4022c40fb95a518727"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_cc6e0411ad81a809c428a06d2f96b018" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2011-05-25/2011-05-25">2011 May 25</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110525162036/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_cde140eba455e5936ee2913c17e823d2"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_82e4e207217a070d24ca48157ba2a5f2" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2011-06-01/2011-06-01">2011 June 1</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110601152436/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_07265aec4c9ae72f54ea6331e96528e4"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_f87e49983d2e2ba2f3377a1eb82781ee" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2011-06-03/2011-06-03">2011 June 3</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110603232126/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_5bd96fa5b4f98c6bc8058bd3943c0282"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_6e7db5e6a6e0a5d675b55b62d77cbfaf" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2011-06-08/2011-06-08">2011 June 8</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110608102745/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_8df32752a91c69eafd4d3afbd6888d01"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_73b84f182fde69e09076d1e90c089a47" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2011-06-28/2011-06-28">2011 June 28</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110628194904/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_b468b3991e16433fc0df5e6322e5f489"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_91985d096e69b00d62bb1dcd05725098" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2011-08-19/2011-08-19">2011 August 19</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110819024019/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_9ea6cc9021c41cfdcf2136606e726aab"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_30c44f0cce16146fec442567557ba276" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2011-10-12/2011-10-12">2011 October 12</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20111012004007/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_8fe6b9660d87e8115bd9b1ad6ddead33"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_df00430642f622f9db85ddbc7cb83e2f" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2012-01-21/2012-01-21">2012 January 21</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120121185924/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_29d62295336c0d2edd32e3075f420745"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_c705c1d1915cd365c46f1f731e838ab0" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2012-01-23/2012-01-23">2012 January 23</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120123011452/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_1fa4c78d29273b18505caf930b509958"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_e8fc9f597960f2c2546e211a70a92780" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2012-02-10/2012-02-10">2012 February 10</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120210104733/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_0defdaf1cfb6d30463ff2d9633730d53"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_49e329d775e0e6b89b6b35a418ca5aff" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2012-05-04/2012-05-04">2012 May 4</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120504061405/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_4d41d67e54ef339c29ebf0aa0031fd68"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_e1d937461ae7071ce217074ec4ca9f66" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2012-05-08/2012-05-08">2012 May 8</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120508223215/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_96aba59303f22afc7d74078544c1e81e"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_dede0f8a794e4748c54d1a896cc64816" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2012-06-11/2012-06-11">2012 June 11</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120611020845/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_f71edfad117b41cbfb4ae39e6855b90a"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_e9b08ec74b27c1b6e41f7e8be2df3fe0" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2012-06-15/2012-06-15">2012 June 15</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120615032856/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_88f8537fb9197be8eb9a33ddfe2f2943"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_71dbb7daedc6c9d9da1a52953ed710ad" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2012-07-01/2012-07-01">2012 July 1</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120701225803/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_7c34eda15865ac12d0af2655a7f5af7f"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_4b8645b28be73366d922f7dac11ae1ea" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2012-07-04/2012-07-04">2012 July 4</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120704002636/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_afee0de7f59fa54bbc2d402f99360675"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_c969183988932f93b986a3a3ed15dae6" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2012-07-16/2012-07-16">2012 July 16</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120716182448/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_e11af1e19a71769f1fc9a0506b9a3a22"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_20edd61dbb8c18fb9e1c87ecc61f0354" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2012-08-11/2012-08-11">2012 August 11</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120811003711/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_3df92b0a0d20ed685cd5d49e5d9fd578"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_e8ad30b9e36fbd4d4d98de8ab2dcbf34" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2012-10-12/2012-10-12">2012 October 12</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20121012030534/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_cec095c86292c5f2d234c3c70fd73c47"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_77ec7a5778a5692d569a5e5c769d1e67" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2012-10-15/2012-10-15">2012 October 15</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20121015215413/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_397baa86e47d531a59bc67735c65b9f0"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_74f10da3e23ec0cf040438c4faf38164" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2012-12-01/2012-12-01">2012 December 1</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20121201175945/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_6085e9ab1b525898847be755280d23a2"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_a81a7388b9b3cd7988d7e43e5cb1dc73" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2013-01-02/2013-01-02">2013 January 2</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130102173851/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_b8f95fd95dc2f994f8a326944275ab25"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_99eca8d9645db92ebf3f7e3821df610a" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2013-01-19/2013-01-19">2013 January 19</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130119170820/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_51c42acc2265cbcf3e0d59c50b0593c9"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_92cac89e2432aa72f9a44917844695fd" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2013-02-01/2013-02-01">2013 February 1</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130201103500/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_5d179f152c7419b0cb12c8ebe1a03688"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_971008bfb470dd21b08e3cddcfbd825c" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2013-02-22/2013-02-22">2013 February 22</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130222083753/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_d11eb43a78708fc8fa8f59ca0a50fc3c"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_4f8c6f8d17128406e37c7f87f829fb77" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2013-02-22/2013-02-22">2013 February 22</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130222083757/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_453924573c502cd9d43c90e0c83691bf"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_ffc0b9929acf0e6f610442a9ee276f97" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2013-03-01/2013-03-01">2013 March 1</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130301173507/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_e5894caebe94503d337242c98cac216a"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_364236773c37bf150005344b0e769fa5" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2013-03-24/2013-03-24">2013 March 24</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130324184419/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_da53db1a551f10e54345ef19f6f256fb"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_c5bf6740f18868342163f8442da72504" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2013-04-01/2013-04-01">2013 April 1</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130401131317/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_696cfe4ada94a3f2977f058415579419"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_60f698c150bf491242d2dba398b4234f" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2013-04-13/2013-04-13">2013 April 13</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130413004931/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_86519feec2594bf29bccf866dbde7f66"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_77cdd9ecabf216db5df1db760091f778" level="item"><did><unittitle>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2013-05-01/2013-05-01">2013 May 1</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130501213104/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_78381427074e466d277e774064fca760"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_5425fff84684464f029995fb7712bae4" level="item"><did><unittitle>WARC file for University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2013-05-08/2013-05-08">2013 May 8</unitdate></did><acqinfo id="aspace_63e6c5720f12ec151853e43416ee6fbb"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p> This item had no crawl rules.</p><p>The CDX index for this capture did not contain crawl information.</p></acqinfo><phystech id="aspace_e55ed2592237dd0150f320540b19db5c"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Researchers interested in data analysis with web archives may request a WARC file. WARC files are very large and difficult to work with. Your request may take time to process, and we may be unable to deliver your request remotely. Please consult an archivist if you are interested in advanced research with web archives.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_c9c6f9105622327c64edcf827f03dea4" level="item"><did><unittitle>WARC file for University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2013-05-08/2013-05-08">2013 May 8</unitdate></did><acqinfo id="aspace_ea31916db71f3c52a206e4c2e18e3dd7"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p> This item had no crawl rules.</p><p>The CDX index for this capture did not contain crawl information.</p></acqinfo><phystech id="aspace_8cf77404a16bc671f13a47adca268cdf"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Researchers interested in data analysis with web archives may request a WARC file. WARC files are very large and difficult to work with. Your request may take time to process, and we may be unable to deliver your request remotely. Please consult an archivist if you are interested in advanced research with web archives.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_217d3ee431d2ee3dbfab784fb729c772" level="item"><did><unittitle>WARC file for University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2013-05-15/2013-05-15">2013 May 15</unitdate></did><acqinfo id="aspace_416119d56f0721a483631300981af72c"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p> This item had no crawl rules.</p><p>The CDX index for this capture did not contain crawl information.</p></acqinfo><phystech id="aspace_34ef8093edd7f18aeb50e667ab2bf8b8"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Researchers interested in data analysis with web archives may request a WARC file. WARC files are very large and difficult to work with. Your request may take time to process, and we may be unable to deliver your request remotely. Please consult an archivist if you are interested in advanced research with web archives.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_4c2acf7e166b5a1e0769a49564292b9d" level="item"><did><unittitle>WARC file for University Art Museum - University at Albany - SUNY </unittitle><unitdate normal="2013-05-22/2013-05-22">2013 May 22</unitdate></did><acqinfo id="aspace_b728621d6c9d2d519f3ff0ae65f6d8a7"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p> This item had no crawl rules.</p><p>The CDX index for this capture did not contain crawl information.</p></acqinfo><phystech id="aspace_b441ee91cc28171405863d374c28a971"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Researchers interested in data analysis with web archives may request a WARC file. WARC files are very large and difficult to work with. Your request may take time to process, and we may be unable to deliver your request remotely. Please consult an archivist if you are interested in advanced research with web archives.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_8425039eb6faf02828b9b4bd2e9c9785" level="item"><did><unittitle>WARC file for &amp;lt;title&amp;gt; not present</unittitle><unitdate normal="2013-05-29/2013-05-29">2013 May 29</unitdate></did><acqinfo id="aspace_5fc3763a7cb47833c8ff205b161054b8"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p> This item had no crawl rules.</p><p>The CDX index for this capture did not contain crawl information.</p></acqinfo><phystech id="aspace_f8230b9e11d64fd2d2d0f5ee57c20bd6"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Researchers interested in data analysis with web archives may request a WARC file. WARC files are very large and difficult to work with. Your request may take time to process, and we may be unable to deliver your request remotely. Please consult an archivist if you are interested in advanced research with web archives.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_f9e2bf729172a936073adb054671724c" level="item"><did><unittitle>&amp;lt;title&amp;gt; not present</unittitle><unitdate normal="2013-06-01/2013-06-01">2013 June 1</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="none" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130601193134/http://www.albany.edu/museum" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="&amp;lt;title&amp;gt; not present" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>&lt;title&gt; not present</p></daodesc></dao></did><acqinfo id="aspace_6897deaf181d02d33e023b2d2ac0700e"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.</p></acqinfo></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
