<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ua618.xml">ua618</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Sociology, Department of; Records <num>ua618</num></titleproper><author>Scott Saperstein</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>1993 April 28</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-06-12 05:36:14 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2016 April 22</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Gregory Wiedeman</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Department of Sociology Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany. Department of Sociology</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ua618</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1966/1977" type="inclusive">1966-1977</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_552c3108881bdee73ce7609e60a06792">The Department of Sociology was created in 1966 as UAlbany evolved into a large public research university.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_3354ef3914fe3d0f7ca1cf0684b7c9b2">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_35bbab016b3ec8e9fae7725b791872cc">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_db615f0db7fa0145d5cb863982902e0c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_62dabde3ab0e7fed8a2763efb520352e">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 1993 April 28 by Scott Saperstein.</p>  </processinfo>
  <phystech id="aspace_f8036b1eb5e8135c634f79abe5968430">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Web Archives</p>  </phystech>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_b7e122c2712fad368c4fa2b34cf55498">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_4c62191266dd2f655212883118459070">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_e8318a996b3a966ae413b8e8284dc683">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_df782491cd13ff2fd84b3c117c702b9d">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>The current Department of Sociology was created in 1966 as a joint department with Anthropology called the Department of Sociology and Anthropology. The department was part of the Division of Social Sciences.[1] The first identifiable Sociology course, titled "The Evolution of Social Science," was offered at the then New York State Normal College in 1904. Though no departmenal structure existed at the school until 1909, the course, taught by Professor Groat, was listed with the History and Polticial Science course offerings. The Annual Circular describes the course as the study of "practical social probelms and their effect upon the formulation of the science of sociology."[2] In 1907 a Sociology course, now called "Principles of Sociology" was listed with the Economics courses.</p><p> As part of a series of changes initiated in 1905 when the Normal College became a four year liberal arts college with a special mission to train teachers, the College adopted a traditional departmental structure in 1909. Among the newly created departments was the Department of Government and Economics, headed by Adam A. Walker. The joint department offered courses in Sociology.[3] In 1914 Economics and Government became separate departmsnts. The Department of Economics, headed by Professor Walker, offered a two semester course titled "Principles of Sociology" and "Problems in Sociology."[4]</p><p> Sociology courses continued to be taught in the Department of Economics until 1934 when that deparment was renamed the Department of Economics and Sociology. No longer would the index state, Sociology: See Economics.[5] In 1937 this joint department became part of the Social Studies division, still headed by Adam A. Walker.[6] In the 1953 General Catalogue Sociology was listed independently as a program in the Social Studies department headed by Joseph T. Phinney. A much broader range of courses were now being offered.[7] Sociology contineud to be taught within the Social Studies Department until 1964,[8] when that department was enlarged and renamed the Division of Social Sciences headed by Kendall A. Birr. That same year the Undergradate Bulletin, for the first time, stated that students in the General Program, but not in the Teacher Education Program, could major in Sociology and receive a Bachelor of Arts.[9]</p><p> In 1966 the joint Department of Sociology and Anthropology was created chaired by Paul F. Wheeler. The department offered the student body 28 Sociology courses.[10] In 1969 the department reported to the new Division of Social and Behavioral Sciences.[11] 1970 saw the joint department split into independent departments of Sociology and Anthropology.[12] That same year the Undergraduate Bulletin stated that a student must take three credits of Sociology or Anthropology in order to meet the requirements for certification as a Social Studies teacher.[13]</p><p> Master of Arts were first offered by the Department of Sociology in 1966,[14] while a Doctor of Philosophy in Sociology was first offered in 1970. The purpose of this Ph.D program was to "prepare qualified students for careers in teaching and research in colleges and universities."[15] The degree and course offerings of the department remain substantially the same to this day.[16]</p><p> [1] State University of New York at Albany, Undergraduate Bulletin 1966-67, p. 151.</p><p> [2] New York State Normal College, Annual Circular and Announcement, 1904, p. 39.</p><p> [3] New York State Normal College, Annual Circular and Announcement, 1907-08, p. 50.</p><p> [4] New York State College for Teachers, Annual Circular and Announcement, 1914-15, p. 54-55.</p><p> [5] New York State College for Teachers, Annual Catalogue, 1934-35, p. 41.</p><p> [6] New York State College for Teachers, Annual Catalogue, 1937-38, p. 64.</p><p> [7] New York State College for Teachers, General Catalogue, 1953-54, p. 123.</p><p> [8] New York State College for Teachers and State University of New York at Albany's, Catalogues and Bulletins, 1937-63.</p><p> [9] State University of New York at Albany, Undergraduate Bulletin, 1964-66, p. 153.</p><p> [10] State University of New York at Albany, Undergraduate Bulletin, 1966-67, p. 151.</p><p> [11] State University of New York at Albany, Undergraduate Bulletin, 1969-70, p. 155.</p><p> [12] State University of New York at Albany, Undergraduate Bulletin, 1970-71, p. 152.</p><p> [13] State University of New York at Albany, Undergraduate Bulletin, 1970-71, p. 180.</p><p> [14] State University of New York at Albany, Graduate Bulletin, 1966-67, p. 135.</p><p> [15] State University of New York at Albany, Graduate Bulletin, 1970-71, p. 115.</p><p> [16] State University of New York at Albany, Undergraduate and Graduate Bulletins, 1971-.</p><p> <chronlist> <head>Department Chairs</head> <chronitem> <date>1966-1968</date> <event>Paul F. Wheeler</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1968-1973</date> <event>Paul Meadows</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1973-1976</date> <event>Raymond Forer</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1976-1980</date> <event>Ronald Farrell</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1980-1982</date> <event>Nan Lin</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1982-1986</date> <event>Richard Hall</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1986-1988</date> <event>Allen Liska</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1988-1991</date> <event>John Logan</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1991-1992</date> <event>Richard Alba</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1992-1995</date> <event>Marvin Krohn</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1995-1997</date> <event>Richard Alba</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1997-2000</date> <event>Glenna Spitze</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>2000-2003</date> <event>Steven Messner</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>2003-unknown</date> <event>Russell Ward</event> </chronitem> </chronlist></p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_4e7af63cea038dd592e5c355eecd43f0">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The records of the Department of Sociology include reports, 1971–1977, proposals for 1977, and budgets.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_04dbd30b23a53d2280a921e446c9b195">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_d13f1be9cb4c40115fe0c78969773cd0">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Department of Sociology Records, 1966-1977. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Department of Sociology Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Higher education and state.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Sociology--Study and teaching (Higher)</subject>
    <genreform source="meg">Web Archives</genreform>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Academic Departments</subject>
    <corpname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany.</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_b34f19132d1d9a3a5565200690f53ad9" level="series"><did><unittitle>Web Archives</unittitle><unitid>nam_ua618-1</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">800 captures</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1997-06-07/2016-09-18" type="inclusive">1997 June 7-2016 September 18</unitdate></did><acqinfo id="aspace_8d3c34e569a7f0521b8921f7470a559e"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>Web crawling is managed through the Internet Archive's Archive-It service. This page includes links to both the university's collection and the Internet Archive's public collection.</p><p> Surface-level crawling of www.albany.edu is performed daily which should includes most top-level webpages. Separate targeted crawls of every albany.edu subdomain are performed monthly to attempt to gather all content. This includes: www.albany.edu, www.rna.albany.edu, www.ctg.albany.edu, www.ualbanysports.com, www.albany.edu/rockefeller, www.albany.edu/cela, www.albany.edu/asrc, m.albany.edu,	library.albany.edu,	events.albany.edu,	cstar.cestm.albany.edu, csda.albany.edu, and alumni.albany.edu</p></acqinfo><phystech id="aspace_df6c1cb6eb817ceec16b2c17162f7fee"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Web Archives</p></phystech><c id="aspace_9acba589a0d957e372822a77fae85ac7" level="file"><did><unittitle>http://www.albany.edu/sociology/ - University Archives collection</unittitle><unitdate normal="2013-05-08/2016-09-18" type="inclusive">2013 May 8-2016 September 18</unitdate><container id="aspace_cda7499ed6b2d9ee2fde3b2e372bd786" label="Mixed Materials" type="Web-Archive">1</container><dao xlink:actuate="onrequest" xlink:href="http://wayback.archive-it.org/3308/*/http://www.albany.edu/sociology/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.albany.edu/sociology/ - University Archives collection"><daodesc><p>http://www.albany.edu/sociology/ - University Archives collection</p></daodesc></dao></did></c><c id="aspace_cd7e815177f190e135283ce0e03bda1e" level="file"><did><unittitle>WARC file for http://www.albany.edu/sociology/, (please see https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_ARChive for more details)</unittitle><unitdate normal="2013-05-08/2016-09-18" type="inclusive">2013 May 8-2016 September 18</unitdate><container id="aspace_6cc64eb023fe457daf970c704b11e022" label="Mixed Materials" type="WARC">1</container></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_e637240ab89958d8b68eb177a343773f"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>WARC files are very large and difficult to work with. Your request may take time to process, and we may be unable to deliver your request remotely. Please consult an archivist if you are interested in researching with web archives.</p></accessrestrict></c><c id="aspace_f0f337eeb2ec53410fa748a9e07600cc" level="file"><did><unittitle>http://www.albany.edu/sociology/ - Internet Archive collection</unittitle><unitdate normal="1997-06-07/2016-09-18" type="inclusive">1997 June 7-2016 September 18</unitdate><container id="aspace_ffe0c5483816c450a98c573e20bcd728" label="Mixed Materials" type="Web-Archive">2</container><dao xlink:actuate="onrequest" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.albany.edu/sociology/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.albany.edu/sociology/ - Internet Archive collection"><daodesc><p>http://www.albany.edu/sociology/ - Internet Archive collection</p></daodesc></dao></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
