<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ua612.xml">ua612</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Anthropology, Department of; Records <num>ua612</num></titleproper><author>unprocessed</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2017</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-09-03 12:19:22 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Department of Anthropology Records</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua612</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.33 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1968/1987" type="inclusive">1968-1987</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_a0727e5e2bd380f8750b1f3f9a71a8bc">Contains inactive records of the Department of Anthropology.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_16adf2f86b841ad5766526e6298243ba">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_aade8a96470def10d98421c36a31c6ba" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_328f718c2cad28f164ab3a4a8ddc340e">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2017 by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_0ac2afd784d5a259ddc0e8b845728498">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_823960dbff79022646c02b8caf67404c">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_12537a58fb71f5414e1a2c9fb2bc5411">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_186c210c535ff1c7e1e23e5631f0a5d5">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Department of Sociology and Anthropology was created in 1966, although these subjects had previously been taught at the University within other departments. In 1970, the departments split, creating separate Departments of Anthropology and Sociology. The B.A. in Anthropology was first offered in 1967, an M.A. was introduced in 1969, and a Ph.D. followed in 1971. Currently, the Department of Anthropology offers undergraduate degrees in Anthropology, Linguistics and Cognitive Science, and Human Biology, minors in Anthropology and Medical Anthropology, and an M.A. and Ph.D. Additionally, the Department of Anthropology is associated with several specialized institutes at the University, including: the Institute for Mesoamerican Studies and the Institute for Cypriot Studies and publishes <emph>Northeast Anthropology</emph>, a bi-annual journal dedicated to scholarly study of the northeastern United States and nearby Canadian provinces.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_f7942dbccc91d378051e9bd4dc07864a">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection includes: M.A. and Ph.D. program proposals, course syllabi, informational materials about archaeological field programs (1972-1984), annual reports (1974-1978), and publications.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_8ebda67411dd5aa656e7f67b4799e586">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_e65adb8bd27d26f2e4963d7db767ddca">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Department of Anthropology Records, 1968-1987. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Department of Anthropology Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher--Administration</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Anthropology</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Syllabi</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">curricula</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Administrative records</genreform>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Academic Departments</subject>
    <corpname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
