<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ua653.xml">ua653</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Career Education Institute; Records <num>ua653</num></titleproper><author>unprocessed</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2017</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-06-12 05:43:18 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2017 February 27</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Benjamin Covell</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Career Education Institute Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="local">State University of New York at Albany. Career Education Institute</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ua653</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1974/1976" type="inclusive">1974-1976</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_9e1e173921d6b9ba23e5e510c5c118d2">Contains the records of the Career Education Institute, which was a professional development program that ran from 1974-1976 for secondary school teachers in the Capital District aimed at helping integrate career education into secondary school curricula. The collection consists of administrative correspondence, financial documents, and informational materials from the program.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_e60419ab8c1730d2253ee70368d831de">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_f549401a600928a6a0be2175cbcf1df6">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_2aa4bf22ae4a003028222581006454ef" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_7dba8cbb6cfe6a47b1416c3bc0578cf2">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2017 by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_4ca2db03ec71524bbbde9b3264241de4">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_d2ebe64327890fa4fcf7f464fdc0ae12">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_365fd8e729c43a5a2ac21314411016ce">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_dc20ba284f7f7e006b16c072cbac34e5">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Career Education Institute was a professional development program, funded by the Education Professions Development Act, that offered summer courses to secondary school teachers in the Capital District. The courses included lectures, field trips, and workshops aimed at educating secondary school teachers about concepts in career education.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_204d7881c7842309fc0cd35304b63596">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection includes: financial records, class rosters, correspondence with speakers, applications from secondary school teachers interested in enrolling in the program, field trip reports, and informational materials.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_271c682f1ec6cecb407111f2ca13cc3d">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_2f1c93331c3ec70b4c3eddb8581965ee">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Career Education Institute Records, 1974-1976. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Career Education Institute Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher--Administration</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Career education</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Administrative records</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Financial Records</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Application Forms</genreform>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Centers &amp; Institutes</subject>
    <corpname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
