<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ua671.xml">ua671</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Information Studies, Department of; Records <num>ua671</num></titleproper><author>Jason Thomas</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2016</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-09-16 23:00:46 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>1997 June 30</date><item>Originally Processed as School of Information Science and Policy Records</item></change><change><date>2015 September</date><item>Reprocessed with accretions</item></change><change><date>2016 February 16</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Gregory Wiedeman</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Department of Information Studies Records</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua671</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">18.47 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1912/2004" type="inclusive">1912-2004</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_9c9bc81c221176c55145dccedcd3b7e2">Documents the administrative, curricular, and social activities of the Department of Information Studies from its establishment as a one year undergraduate school for librarians in 1926 through the early part of the twenty-first century.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_bc9f88e5469734db9eaee1a23d8d47ac">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_d823c470eb4b697d7d32d16bc9ef9f27" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2021.015</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_84a4340ee5bcce0b863f4d7666fc0301">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2016 by Jason Thomas.</p>  </processinfo>
  <phystech id="aspace_6c75e022372cee5e66fe2146b1ddab58">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Web Archives</p>  </phystech>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_a9f095785ac12677e1a2b37d618bbd22">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p><p> Some files in series 1 and all of the personnel files in series 4 are restricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_3eca9c0fabf594a6fe85d207e739ab1d">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_0f123f2fb7606bbebd14cc7d046905bd">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>The first of these records (1926-1965) were transferred to the University Archives, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by John Farley, Dean of the School of Library and Information Science, on December 16, 1974. Sometime in the late 1980's, several more items from the University Archives vertical files were combined with those previously transferred by the School of Library and Information Science. More records were received in August 2008 from Phil Eppard.<date normal="1974/2006">1974-2006</date></p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_18937806164d5fda928f8fbcd198a9f7">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>Although the Department of Information Studies officially opened in September, 1926, it traces its origins to January 5, 1887, when Melvil Dewey first opened the Columbia College School of Library Economy. Two years later, Dewey resigned from Columbia to assume the position of Director of the New York State Library in Albany. Before he left, he insured that his young library school also moved to Albany were it became an adjunct of the New York State Library and was renamed the New York State Library School. This two-year program remained in Albany until 1926 when the State Board of Regents and Columbia University's Board of Trustees combined the School with the Library School of the New York Public Library and moved it once again to Columbia University. In order to insure that a facility capable of training secondary-school librarians remained in the Capital Region, James Sullivan, the State Commissioner of Secondary Education, established a new Library School as part of the New York State College for Teachers in 1926.</p><p> However, this was not the first time that the State College had offered courses in librarianship. In 1916, the College Board of Trustees hired Elizabeth Cobb as the school's librarian and as an instructor. The 1917 College Bulletin reveals that she instructed two courses in the English Department entitled "Library Methods" and "High School Library Management." In 1921, Elizabeth Cobb became the primary instructor in the State College's new Department of Library Science, which offered in courses in "conjunction with and upon the suggestion of the New York State Library School." Cobb supervised the department until 1926, when the Department of Library Science was replaced by the new State College Library School. Martha Caroline Pritchard, herself a graduate of Dewey's New York State Library School, became the first head of the New York State College for Teachers Library School in 1926. The new one-year undergraduate curriculum consisted of a combination of classroom instruction, field work in the department's library, and organized field trips to libraries in the Capital region and in New York City. The nascent program soon received national recognition when the American Library Association's (ALA) Board of Education accredited the department as a Type III (undergraduate) library school in 1934.</p><p> By 1951 the school had expanded to a five year curriculum and in that year it offered its first Masters degree. However, six years later the school failed to gain accreditation under the 1951 standards for five-year programs adopted by the ALA. The reasons cited in the ALA's Report were that the department's small number of full-time faculty and its location in a state college rather than a university rendered it incapable of fulfilling the requirements of its new graduate program. In 1962, the same year that the New York State College for Teachers became the State University of New York at Albany, the department changed its name to the School of Library Science. The school now prepared students for jobs in school, public, and college libraries, and for careers in library education. The school's faculty were engaged in securing research and education grants, publishing, and redesigning the school's curriculum. In response to the school's advancements, the ALA re-accredited the program in 1966. The school's plan to implement a Doctoral Program in Library Science was approved by the University Senate and by the State University of New York (SUNY) central administration in 1971, but the State Education Department refused to register the new program the following year.</p><p> In 1986, the school merged with the Rockefeller College of Public Affairs and Policy. The new School of Information Science and Policy prepared its students for an assortment of careers including information systems and library management, information policy, the economics of Information, government information resource management, archives and records management, and information technology applications. In 1990, the School of Information Science and Policy and several other schools in Rockefeller College implemented a new interdisciplinary Doctoral Program in Information Science. Beginning in 1995, the school introduced the M.S. in Information Science (M.S.I.S.), a degree designed to emphasize interdisciplinary studies in information science and public policy and offer an advance internship experience. In 2000, Rockefeller College was restructured and the School of Information Science and Policy became its own school once again. This lasted until 2005, when the School of Information Science and Policy joined the new College of Computing and Information and became the Department of Information Studies. </p><p>  <chronlist> <head>School Names</head> <chronitem> <date>1917-1921</date> <event>English Department (two courses)</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1921-1926</date> <event>Department of Library Science</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1926-1932</date> <event>Library School</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1932-1961</date> <event>Department of Librarianship</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1961-1962</date> <event>Division of Library Science</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1962-1971</date> <event>School of Library Science</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1971-1986</date> <event>School of Library and Information Science</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1986-2005</date> <event>School of Information Science and Policy</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>2005-present</date> <event>Department of Information Studies</event> </chronitem> </chronlist> </p><p>  <chronlist> <head>Chairmen and Deans</head> <chronitem> <date>1917-1926</date> <event>Mary Elizabeth Cobb (College Librarian and Head Instructor)</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1926-1940</date> <event>Martha Caroline Pritchard (First Chairman)</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1941-1948</date> <event>Esther Stallman (Acting Chairman 1940-1941)</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1948-1961</date> <event>Robert S. Burgess (Advising library science educators in Korea 1958-1961)</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1958-1961</date> <event>H. Carolyn Howard (Acting Chairman in Burgess' absence)</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1961-1966</date> <event>Irving A. Verschoor (First Dean)</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1966-1967</date> <event>Edgar W. Flinton (Acting Dean)</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1967-1977</date> <event>John J. Farley</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1977-1978</date> <event>Robert S. Burgess (Acting Dean)</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1978-1981</date> <event>Ben-Ami Lipetz</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1981-1993</date> <event>Richard Halsey</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1993-1995</date> <event>Richard P. Nathan (Acting Dean)</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1995-2003</date> <event>Phillip Eppard (Acting Dean 1995-1997)</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>2003-2005</date> <event>Peter A. Bloniarz</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>2005-2006</date> <event>Carol A. Doll</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>2006-2007</date> <event>Stephen DeLong (Interim Department Chair)</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>1967-1977</date> <event>Terry Maxwell</event> </chronitem> <chronitem> <date>2011-present</date> <event>Phillip Eppard</event> </chronitem> </chronlist></p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_7f8295b83f0bdf2360b5612316d4f602">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>These records document the administrative, curricular, and social activities of the Department of Information Studies from its establishment as a one year undergraduate school for librarians in 1926 through the early part of the twenty-first century. The bulk of the records, which consist of correspondence, meeting minutes, memoranda, annual reports, accreditation reports, and course outlines and syllabi were created between 1926 and 1990.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_6193a3b01ae199d3318856bdbfe3f932">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is organized into five topical series.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_ee87cd8e3e485ed68da6b80d84f82d82">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Department of Information Studies Records, 1912-2004 . M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Department of Information Studies Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Higher Education Administration</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Library Education</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Professional Education</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Library Schools</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Information Science</subject>
    <genreform source="meg">Web Archives</genreform>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Academic Departments</subject>
    <corpname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">State University of New York at Albany. Department of Information Studies</corpname>
    <corpname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany. School of Information Science and Policy</corpname>
    <persname source="lcsh">Martha Caroline Pritchard</persname>
    <persname source="lcsh">Esther Stallman</persname>
    <persname source="lcsh">Irving A. Verschoor</persname>
    <persname source="lcsh">John J. Farley</persname>
    <persname source="lcsh">Robert S. Burgess</persname>
    <persname source="lcsh">Ben-Ami Lipetz</persname>
    <persname source="lcsh">Richard Halsey</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_2be7c6a46ce6133164784243356a4779" level="series"><did><unittitle>Administration and Faculty</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.9 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1912/2001" type="inclusive">1912-2001</unitdate></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_4533c75b7cf2d1ded9de72dfaf7fa0db"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Seven files contain personally identifiable information and are restricted.</p></accessrestrict><scopecontent id="aspace_3b6d3ee968bc6791b6d267b047ffb006"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains correspondence, meeting minutes, annual reports, memoranda, enrollment statistics, inventories, and other records that pertain to the administration and faculty of the Department of Information Studies and its past iterations. This series documents routine activities such as internal and external faculty and departmental correspondence, faculty meetings, admission information, curriculum development, annual reports, grants and fellowships offered through the department, special projects conducted, and enrollment statistics. Prominent dates include the foundation of the Library School (1926), the development of the Master's Program (1949-1950) and later the Doctorate Program (1968-1971), the school's union with Rockefeller College (1986).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5b5a61b711af952b7ad7eacdac450183" level="series"><did><unittitle>Course Materials</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.2 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1927/1992" type="inclusive">1927-1992</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e342b90716e1131327e2a00cfe4be495"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series consists of both bound volumes (1927-1954) and folders (1963-1992) that each contain syllabi, assignment sheets, handouts, examinations, and other class material related to the courses taught by the Department of Information Studies and its various incarnations.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_169439ad074e30f52fd72589b572393c" level="series"><did><unittitle>Professional Organizations and Associations</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.3 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1916/1990" type="inclusive">1916-1990</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a3c1e1ac5cb9a3f708484cf46f8ad703"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains correspondence and information provided to and from the various national, regional, state, and local organizations and associations in which the Department of Information Studies was involved as well as records pertaining to committees and other groups involved with the State University of New York (SUNY) in general. Of particular note is the large amount of records to and from the American Library Association (ALA), a professional organization whose function, among others, is the accreditation of all the information science and library schools in the nation.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d4c435b4bab992ac5908addf55a482e3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Former Faculty Personnel Files</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.17 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1956/2004" type="inclusive">1956-2004</unitdate></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_02e76090177f9f9aebc507cba79ee1e7"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>RESTRICTED. Contains personally identifiable information. Consult an archivist for details.</p></accessrestrict><scopecontent id="aspace_6640b909e344d78907c3875d23028979"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains the personnel files of a number of former faculty members in the Department of Information Science. This series contains transcripts, applications for employment, correspondence with the various deans and chairs, material related to tenure review and promotions, student evaluations, newspaper clippings and news reports, photographs, retirement documents, and the curriculum vitae of the faculty. Because of the large amount of private information included, this series has been restricted.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_07d7586abf23224c42cc17715566d379" level="series"><did><unittitle>Subject Files</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.9 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1923/1979" type="inclusive">1923-1979</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_594074da298b74310244aae84424e19b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains records that do not fit into the other series, this includes a scrapbook, biographical histories of the department as well as certain members of the faculty, and accession and circulation records from the now defunct Hawley Library.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d0d6aed2d1e65542b13e550c36741188" level="series"><did><unittitle>Web Archives</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">313 captures</extent></physdesc><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2011-02-02/2016-09-18" type="inclusive">2011 February 2-2016 September 18</unitdate></did><acqinfo id="aspace_1d7ba2984930ff5b3cc088e6f68e2cea"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>Web crawling is managed through the Internet Archive's Archive-It service. This page includes links to both the university's collection and the Internet Archive's public collection.</p><p> Surface-level crawling of www.albany.edu is performed daily which should includes most top-level webpages. Separate targeted crawls of every albany.edu subdomain are performed monthly to attempt to gather all content. This includes: www.albany.edu, www.rna.albany.edu, www.ctg.albany.edu, www.ualbanysports.com, www.albany.edu/rockefeller, www.albany.edu/cela, www.albany.edu/asrc, m.albany.edu,	library.albany.edu,	events.albany.edu,	cstar.cestm.albany.edu, csda.albany.edu, and alumni.albany.edu</p></acqinfo><phystech id="aspace_5a0efb61fb752e00c83f899e2e6496a8"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Web Archives</p></phystech><c id="aspace_1fa8040ee831df4bb68a9422db7fc5d3" level="file"><did><unittitle>http://www.albany.edu/informationstudies/ - University Archives collection</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2013-05-08/2016-09-18" type="inclusive">2013 May 8-2016 September 18</unitdate><container id="aspace_1c32b433b0d9ea77988cb21230806ed7" label="Mixed Materials" type="Web-Archive">1</container><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="300fd815-5b47-4100-b227-2b735cb96fb0" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.albany.edu/informationstudies/ - University Archives collection" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>http://www.albany.edu/informationstudies/ - University Archives collection</p></daodesc></dao></did></c><c id="aspace_fd5a727a5bb4958d55b186ebc58d0d67" level="file"><did><unittitle>WARC file for http://www.albany.edu/informationstudies/, (please see https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_ARChive for more details)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2013-05-08/2016-09-18" type="inclusive">2013 May 8-2016 September 18</unitdate><container id="aspace_0ab59a0455b675e8e10e59f9f735372f" label="Mixed Materials" type="WARC">1</container></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_0dca509bb4017cfa415be2ff424dd60c"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>WARC files are very large and difficult to work with. Your request may take time to process, and we may be unable to deliver your request remotely. Please consult an archivist if you are interested in researching with web archives.</p></accessrestrict></c><c id="aspace_59275cc846f7b4766fee0c251dc21ea3" level="file"><did><unittitle>http://www.albany.edu/informationstudies/ - Internet Archive collection</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2011-02-02/2016-09-18" type="inclusive">2011 February 2-2016 September 18</unitdate><container id="aspace_6f2736ba912cf74fdb6063766c59f9dd" label="Mixed Materials" type="Web-Archive">2</container><dao xlink:actuate="onrequest" xlink:href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.albany.edu/informationstudies/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.albany.edu/informationstudies/ - Internet Archive collection" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>http://www.albany.edu/informationstudies/ - Internet Archive collection</p></daodesc></dao></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
