<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ua680.010.xml">ua680.010</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Center for Legislative Development; Records <num>ua680.010</num></titleproper><author>unprocessed</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2017</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-06-12 05:51:51 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2017 March 20</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Benjamin Covell</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Center for Legislative Development Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany. Center for Legislative Development</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ua680.010</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">82 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1966/2000" type="inclusive">1966-2000</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_e6c4f76f17f08487ed6cd1d9b40a582d">Contains the inactive records of the Center for Legislative Development (formerly the Comparative Development Studies Center), which delivers training and technical assistance programs to strengthen governmental institutions around the world.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_4bd68a8641c6c3ce550e5b8578efc588">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_36e135a54980aee9defe73679333fd9b">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_ffd42154481f732c0067ad19eaf4e8fb" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_c72feeb15ea5415cd5e666c2c0c4e1b2">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2017 by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_4d0a524aea0125c36f776613138bbc9e">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_415547aa4c6c072da9f6b46b72dcb47d">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_2016377502a5a65ea2e58d484c86192e">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_2b6e577c36818ff6162619814f8ebf77">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Center for Legislative Development is the successor to the Comparative Development Studies Center. Dr. James Heaphey served as director of the Center for Legislative Development from its founding until 1978 when he was succeeded by Aldo Baakalini who served as Director until his death in 2003. The Center's primary function, under both names, has been and is to assist in the development of legislative effectiveness around the world by studying and accessing legislative needs for resources and information, and formulating plans to acquire those resources so that legislatures can negotiate agreements with their executives.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_fbb91ef549d5944c0764fb56673e7b10">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Contained in the Centers records are program proposals, records of site visits, correspondence, contracts, and reports. In the early 1970s the Center was interested in the problems of legislative security in the United States. Of interest might be extensive documentation, including tapes, of the Legislatures and Human Rights Conference in Dublin, Ireland in 1976. In the 1990s the Center assisted the former Soviet satellite of Hungary in developing legislative institutions, but was largely unsuccessful in attempting to assist the Central Asian Republics in their transition. The Center was fund for a Rule of Law Project in Kazakhstan but internal problems in the country prevent the carrying out of the project. The records also contain proposals for an unfunded Mongolian Rural Civil Society Program, one of whose aims was to enhance the status of women in rural society. The Center had active programs of legislative development in Korea, Kuwait, and Yemen. There are 2.5 cubic ft. of records regarding the Committee on Viable Constitutionalism (COVICO), 1993-1999. In East Africa the Center had a program in Ethiopia in the mid 1970s, in West Africa the Center has had long term programs in Ghana, 1969-1981, in Guinea-Bissau, 1992-1997, and in North Africa, Egypt, 1970s, 1994-98. In the Eastern Mediterranean the Center has had programs in Lebanon. The Center has had a long term presence in South and Central America and the Caribbean from the 1960s through the 1990s. Found in the records are materials relating to the Centers assistance to the following countries to develop their legislative branches: Argentina, Belize, Bolivia, Brazil, Chile, Costa Rica, the Dominican Republic, Ecuador, El Salvador, Haiti, Honduras, Guatemala, Nicaragua, Panama, Paraguay, Peru, Uruguay and Venezuela.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_9c5a47f4f5b723c179a9b28dae677440">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_20c4231499e8546892661c2492983593">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Center for Legislative Development Records, 1966-2000. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Center for Legislative Development Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">Women</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Public Servants</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Medicine and Health Care</subject>
    <subject source="meg">Conservation and the Environment</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International cooperation</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Government policy</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Administrative records</genreform>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Centers &amp; Institutes</subject>
    <corpname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
