<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ua680.005.xml">ua680.005</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Public Administration and Policy, Department of; Records <num>ua680.005</num></titleproper><author>unprocessed</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2017</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-06-12 05:51:50 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2017 April 3</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Benjamin Covell</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Department of Public Administration and Policy Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="local">Rockefeller College of Public Affairs and Policy. Department of Public Administration and Policy</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ua680.005</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1968/1987" type="inclusive">1968-1987</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_c97e8b16bfcf0c6e2382bd799b47bec7">Contains inactive records from the Department of Public Administration and Policy, a department within the Rockefeller College of Public Affairs and Policy.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_166b058fc9f2fec6e5fd6f9597dc52fb">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_662edf09037ef17be8a7aaa256821591">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_22584cf2a4e8991cf57ab33f727c96e6" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_ed7a6556128b6b1f223fce10f402b4f0">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2017 by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_0fa396418206402417820992875f4ba9">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed and contains sensitive information and personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_338f62c005bbf8aa0af3382acda2c2db">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_3d28561a89d74ce66bdb48631386df5b">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_6fa4258e70754e1b686d0505dd164167">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Rockefeller College of Public Affairs &amp; Policy originated in 1947 as the Albany Graduate Program in Public Administration, a joint program of New York University and Syracuse University.</p><p> The new graduate program provided the rapidly expanding post-WWII state government of Governor Thomas E. Dewey with academic training in public administration. The State University of New York began to subsidize the training program in 1950, and in 1962 the State University of New York formally took over the program and renamed it the Graduate School of Public Affairs. The new school offered MA and PhD programs in public administration and political science, and an MA in public affairs. An MPA was quickly added. The school affiliated with the State University of New York at Albany (SUNYA) in September 1966. As part of SUNYA, the Graduate School took over the University's department of political science, adding undergraduate programs, and in 1981 created a department of public administration and policy. These departments are the academic heart of the college. The current name of the school, the Rockefeller College of Public Affairs &amp; Policy, was adopted in 2000 to honor the contributions of Governor Nelson Rockefeller who served from 1959-1973.</p><p> The Department of Public Administration and Policy provides graduate and undergraduate students the skills and insights necessary to participate in the management of public and nonprofit organizations and the creation of public policy.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_16f042de132c6bcb919de19ef6a775c8">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Materials in this collection include: Program proposals, self studies, and accreditation files; grant proposals; course syllabi and curricula; long-range planning documentation; committee materials; M.P.A. requirements documentation; and faculty files.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_3d9c09d0e49b492cc0d01c7d2aa3c029">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_fb31e5062ff00058a4a550059e2eb51d">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Department of Public Administration and Policy Records, 1968-1987. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Department of Public Administration and Policy Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public administration--Study and Teaching</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher--Administration</subject>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Administrative records</genreform>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Academic Departments</subject>
    <corpname source="lcsh">Rockefeller College of Public Affairs and Policy</corpname>
    <corpname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
