<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ua730.xml">ua730</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Student Affairs, Division for; Records <num>ua730</num></titleproper><author>Miles Lawlor</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2019</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-06-12 08:04:53 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2017 March 13</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Benjamin Covell</item></change><change><date>2019</date><item>Collection-level processing revised by Miles Lawlor</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Division of Student Affairs Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="local">State University of New York at Albany. Division of Student Affairs</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ua730</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">18.33 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1926/2005" type="inclusive">1926-2005</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_13a687108e10bf094c2a2abc71cfa7b3">Contains the records of the Division of Student Affairs, its subordinate offices, and its predecessor bodies, including the Office of the Dean of Students. Materials include: planning and policy documentation, admissions and financial aid statistics, correspondence, and meeting minutes.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_84577e187c88f3bcf2ccca809328d90b">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_72cc66585c2504a98eef6e22b1d23e1a">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_f48b5e9033d0066ef3def467cd749cb9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_ce58ec097869f06687a878dafa3b4ea0">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Student disciplinary records containing personally identifying information and records cotaining student medical information removed in 2019 by Miles Lawlor.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_bd8e12a467ebe6b3a15ebfba049c8840">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>The Office of the Vice President for Student Affairs was created in 1965 to oversee a variety of aspects of student life at the University, including: residental life, counseling, athletics, financial aid, student activities, and health services. Most of these duties had previously been overseen by the Deans of Men and Women. The position of Vice President for Student Affairs was replaced by the Dean of Student Affairs (also referred to as Dean of Students) in 1972; the position reverted to a Vice Presidency in 1983. The Office was later renamed the Division of Student Success, but as of 2017 it is once again referred to as the Division of Student Affairs.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_877917fa43832240672cc3455883a194">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection documents the work of the Division of Student Affairs Records and its predecessor offices.  At different times the Division has overseen student counseling and student recreation, meaning these areas are documented as well.  Recreation and athletics, particularly the University’s move to Division I in the 1990s, is documented.  A significant amount of this collection, focused in the mid-1980s and 1990s, documents the correspondence of the Division’s Vice President.  This collection also contains records on a number of Task Forces and Committees that representatives from Student Affairs sat on, including, the SIRS Design Team, the Task Force on EOP and MRP Admissions, and the Committee to Evaluate University Alcohol Policies as well as others.  There is also admissions information, including population-level information on accepted students and proposed enrollment growth rates for the University.  The collection also contains event notices; five-year planning records; files from the Five-Quad Ambulance Service and other student groups; and various other records pertaining to the administration of student affairs and activities at the University.  Finally, the collection contains of files of correspondence and planning documents and pfrom the offices of the Deans of Men and Women, who oversaw many of the Division's responsibilities before the 1960s.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_69ecb41cce540af542ab26d7e3289a82">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>This collection has been arranged based upon labels on the original boxes when collection was transferred to the archives.  Files in this collection were maintained in this original order and as such are not arranged chronologically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_4940b7291457b582271c17b19a87e146">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_30fbb6c480f83fb8f49fa5c8dd98687a">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_55ffc8f780152f55332fe2a64bbac296">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_cb2d202338e2d30363e05923510c919a">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Division of Student Affairs Records, 1926-2005. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Division of Student Affairs Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Student affairs services</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Student affairs administrators</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher--Administration</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">College discipline</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Administrative records</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Student Affairs</subject>
    <corpname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
