<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ua760</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>University Relations, Office of; Records <num>ua760</num></titleproper><author>Collection record created in 2017 by Benjamin Covell.
Series-level description added in 2019 by Miles Lawlor.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2017</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-11-25 23:00:48 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Office of University Relations Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="local">State University of New York at Albany. Office of University Relations</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ua760</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">36.5 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1960/1995" type="inclusive">1960-1999</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_30857a198a7fe44875784f1345ec5379">Contains records form the Office of University Relations and its predecessors, including the Office of Public Relations and Office of Community Relations.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_015a444fd3fe072cc22d3b946a9ed84d">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_4e3fe1ffdaeabca2bb7c773d9fd2b79a">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_df2a2074cc3f99a7978064c3e2659f7d">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Series-level processing completed in 2019 by Miles Lawlor.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_7e69600bce194a2b13927e157ed6f866">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_69ac60cd0727864e27662690c4c28f2b">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites. Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder. The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks. The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_acd0dfead9a91e5005bf0783c82c1682">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_27121cab0aeb3fda12a39e3949408ad8">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection has been organized into five series.  The first series is made up of subject files and administrative files maintained by the office.  The second series includes press releases that the office produced from various publications.  The third series includes a file of publications produced by the office for various entities throughout the University.  The fourth series documents the schools athletic teams.  The fifth series is made up of photographs and photographic materials, while the sixth and final series is made up of press clippings that the office retained from various publications.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_d65102a5e2dc5b37d3ba995326b15659">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, University Relations, 1960-1994. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the University Relations).</p>  </prefercite>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_a2a1ef92f11e5d1c06078d291c5fe0a4">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains materials created by the Office of University Relations and several of its predecessor and subordinate offices, including: the Office of Community Relations, the Public Relations Office, and the News Bureau.</p><p>Materials include: University publications; press releases; clippings; CRO logs; sports files that include press releases, season schedules, brochures, statistics, and clippings; and budget files.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_c1f4382b6159f72e80d6b61d631522f0">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The University's Public Relations Office, responsible for press releases and public information, was created circa 1961.  In the late 1960s, it became the Office of Community Relations, which was incorporated into the newly-formed Office of University Affairs in 1972.  The title changed again when it became the Office of University Relations (sometime prior to 1985), although, somewhat confusingly, there was a brief period in the 1990s when the Office of Community Relations was reintroduced and existed alongside the Office of University Relations.  From 1990 through circa 2005, the Office of University Relations was administered by the Division of University Advancement.  As of 2017, public information and media relations are managed by the Office of Communications and Marketing.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">public relations</genreform>
    <genreform source="local">News Clippings</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Press releases.</genreform>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Communications &amp; Marketing</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
