<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ua800.014</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Pride Alliance; collection <num>ua800.014</num></titleproper><author>Erik Stolarski</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2017</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-09-03 13:21:39 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Pride Alliance Collection</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua800.014</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.0 cubic ft.</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">2 Rolls</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1984/2009" type="inclusive">1984-2009</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_771e080835638ef9f9b981d4d7247dfc">This collection is made up of programs and advertisements for events hosted by various LGBTQ groups on campus.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_a700220c6f8680a5c0cc4e1b2eb7af20">Materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_d0f18b9f20d98593fa618c153af18885" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container>
    <container id="aspace_7a193daa7e9fca440d2ada9b542f953b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Roll">1</container>
    <container id="aspace_251d67fa02ed0565927b7e69777e649f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Roll">2</container>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_d5873f7cf575ab970329ddd325fe42e0">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Collection is arranged in the order it was recieved in.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_590583a2d66ea27ab58cd52584bf015c">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>The UA Pride Alliance was first formed in 1970 to foster a feeling of community on campus for LGBTQ students. The original name for this group was the Gay Liberation Front. The title of this group, as well as the level of inclusion has developed over the years. Other names used were the Gay Alliance in 1974, the Gay and Lesbian Alliance in 1984 and the Lesbian, Gay, and Bisexual Alliance in 1992. The current name was introduced in 2000 based on the records in the collections. This group in its current iteration has helped to make Albany an inclusive campus and works with the Gender and Sexuality Resource Center based in the campus center. The Pride Alliance also works with the Middle Earth Peer Assistance Program for many of their programs.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_bedfcaa15b0fb3e2bad98828538148d8">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collecion is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_7d3a5d83f4693da59db84836d30ca9ac">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>

<p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>


<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>

<p>The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_c2e33a50679875a888b120f873bdc02c">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by the Gender and Sexuality Resource Center.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_4efa0008d0c99b1a9cfbcfd19c46cea4">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, The Pride Alliance Collection, 1984-2009. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Pride Alliance)</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_c08ef9f249c0bbe963fa24afcaf41dea">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Collection was processed in 2017 by Erik Stolarski.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_f79a86302557a3488b1f3187ffc809dc">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of materials related to events hosted by or affiliated with the various iterations of the University at Albany Pride Alliance. Most of these items are posters, flyers and other forms of advertisement for these events. The rest of the materials are programs from these events. The date and time of the events being held, as well as other affiliated groups can be found on many of these items. Other non-community building events were meant to inform fellow classmates on the gay experience and teach a feeling of acceptance for people of different sexual orientations.The rolled materials are banners for the Second Chance Prom or Dragapella Karaoke Dance Championship hosted by the Pride alliance and the Gender and Sexuality Resource Center.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Gay rights--New York (State)</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Gay Liberation Front</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Students - Political activity</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">State universities and colleges</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
