<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ua800.011</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Sigma Xi; Records <num>ua800.011</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-03-02 00:51:15 -0500</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Sigma Xi Records</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua800.011</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.17 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1968/1976" type="inclusive">1968-1976</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_258e0e06b6756ee7fb620fc8fa81fb65">This collections contains records on the founding of the SUNY Albany Chapter of Sigma Xi and its early years.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_c792bce838eb818a83d1ac35faf9565f">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_29d85397c816dec57e4a83729c9fb0c3" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_6a0bb18280f3782d09692b77291de5ac">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>Sigma Xi is an academic honor society, originally founded at Cornell University in 1886.  The Albany chapter of the Society was founded as a club in 1943; the club became a fully affiliated chapter with the national Sigma Xi organization in 1970.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_a4afdeef78f3b8af1c03231ffa3e36c1">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection is made up of a formal petition for establishment of the chapter, copies of posters and articles on the chapter's establishment and correspondence files.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_905306d766509f73c41ae10ffb989510">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2019 by Miles Lawlor.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_a5b470081d0dedd9e10f2487cb16e265">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Collection was maintained in the original order after it was transferred.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_9cbbb35eaed684cc26bb9d1fa00bff91">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_fb99029e73371ec4c674e8a22a1255c9">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestrcited</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_bc632bc1cabda75e3296d6e348ad70f2">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
<p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
<p>The M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collection and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_72c99a8fe3723c2c29202ad623b1e4e0">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Sigma Xi Records, 1968-1976. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Sigma Xi Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Student Groups</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
