<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ua800.010.xml">ua800.010</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Adelphoi Literary Society; Records <num>ua800.010</num></titleproper><author>Jenifer Sigafoes</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2016</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-06-12 06:10:51 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2014</date><item>EAD file created</item></change><change><date>2016 May</date><item>Encoded in EAD by Gregory Wiedeman</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Adelphoi Literary Society Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="local">Adelphoi Literary Society</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ua800.010</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.33 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1902/1931" type="inclusive">1902-1931</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_eee523018ec7cd4b923bde554e4ce9a5">A social fraternity for High School students attending the Milne School, the training school attached to the New York State College for Teachers.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_9d1f42200d9ebef7fd16abb8293ee886">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_4740e2326dacdc88e9503b328a3676fe">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_6b96aa3f5972f1a1de384e191c9be1a1">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2016 by Jenifer Sigafoes .</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_d16703eae30a7b7ff0daf6fa1c6bd11f">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Adelphoi Literary Society was one of the fraternal organizations for students attending the New York State Normal College High School / Milne High School, the practice teaching school for the New York State Normal College / New York State College for Teachers. The Adelphoi Literary Society was founded between 1890 and 1895.[1] The society participated in a number of academic, as well as social activities. The society held literary readings at most meetings.[3] One Adelphoian policy was to train its members in public speaking.[4] The group held many mock trials and debates. The debates usually followed political topics of the day such as, "women's suffrage"[5] or historically political topics such as, "who was the greater man Washington or Lincoln."[6] The society also organized many social outings each semester, like in 1907 a yachting party on the Hudson,[7] in 1913 sleigh rides at the Canton Hotel[8], and in 1915 they held their annual picnic at Indian Ladder.[9] The Adelphoi Literary Society appears to have remained in existence until 1960. In the December 21, 1960 edition of the Crimson and White, the Milne High newspaper, Gay Dexter reported that Dr. Carlton Moose, the faculty advisor, recommended that the Adelphoi Literary Society be discontinued for lack of interest. Dr. Moose commented that the society had only six members at this point and had "lost sight of their original function as a literary society."[10] During the years from the founding in the 1890s to its discontinuation in 1960 the society provided an academic and social outlet for many of Milne's male students. Additional information about the Adelphoi Literary Society can be found in The Crimson and White, the Milne High School literary magazine; Crimson and White, the Milne High School's newspaper; and Bricks and Ivy, the Milne High School yearbook. </p><p> [1] For Youth and the State 1845-1940. 1890-1940: The Milne School of the New York State College for Teachers. Albany, New York. 1940, p. 14. There is some confusion about the exact date. A review of available sources was unable to reveal the exact year the society was founded. The June 1913 issue of The Crimson and White (literary magazine) on page 139 has an ambiguous reference to the organization entering its 62nd year.[2] Adelphoi Literary Society, Minutes, 1902-1913.[3] The Crimson and White. (literary magazine) December 1913, p. 49.[4] The Crimson and White. (literary magazine) December 1914, p. 42.[5] The Crimson and White. (literary magazine) February 1912, p. 62-3.[6] The Crimson and White. (literary magazine) April 1913, p. 101.[7] The Crimson and White. (literary magazine) June 1907, p. 120.[8] The Crimson and White. (literary magazine) April 1911, p. 101.[9] The Crimson and White. (literary magazine) June 1915, p. 128-9.[10] Crimson and White. (newspaper) December 21, 1960, p. 2.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_cdb34d3593d8b806b972a86efc91a3f7">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Adelphoi Literary Society records consist of two secretary's meeting minutes books spanning the years 1902-1913, 1924-1931. No constitution or by-laws for the organization were found. The minutes contain attendance rolls and routine proceedings of the meetings as handwritten by the secretary. The secretaries recorded information about the installation of officers, literary programs, critics reports, reports of committees, and new and unfinished business. The literary programs included readings, recitations, debates, and mock trials. Each meeting appears to either begin or end with a prayer.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_18da4625bd9baace97ca272bfe374828">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection is has no series and contains only meeting minutes.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_a98b0054f638e4f1e85770a3228eddb9">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by Kenneth D. Mosher, Jr., Class of 1946<date normal="1998">1998</date></p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_0782d22de8302daa60bc4f5d7def997d">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_aaae619b0572d13e21c4b9501afe4ad8">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p><p> The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_c552dabeeda0cb7f36b7a7895247258a">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Adelphoi Literary Society Records, 1902-1931. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Adelphoi Literary Society Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">Literature</subject>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Student Groups</subject>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Minutes (administrative records)</genreform>
    <corpname source="lcsh">State University of New York at Albany</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_d1a5f5c43caad704bb14355fe009353a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Secretary's Book, Meeting Minutes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1902/1905" type="inclusive">1902-1905</unitdate><container id="aspace_a4e6fcb0d5aad7d33a3fed5d54415711" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (Adelphoi Literary Society Records)</container><container id="aspace_75bff07eb77e40d81d27b61117b5f930" parent="aspace_a4e6fcb0d5aad7d33a3fed5d54415711" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ffd75f78b8be21964ba281f02ecfa4dc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Secretary's Book, Meeting Minutes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1906/1913" type="inclusive">1906-1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_9c425b50a822baa9a87348d4c4cad1d3" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (Adelphoi Literary Society Records)</container><container id="aspace_992f243664dc1de912afba6c787fe8dc" parent="aspace_9c425b50a822baa9a87348d4c4cad1d3" type="Folder">2</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
