<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ua810</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>University Photo Service; Records <num>ua810</num></titleproper><author>Miles Lawlor</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2019</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-10-28 19:04:26 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2019 October 9</date><item>EAD file created.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>University Photo Service Records</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua810</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1966/1993" type="inclusive">1966-1993</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_22d378bd93ad4a30c3422c73be4a31b3">This collection is made up of negatives, contact sheets and photographic prints produced by the Univeristy Photo Services student group.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_c2f85cf03f1b34d69ae1365d90adc870">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_b61939930337dcebdfe1cec822681164">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2019 by Miles Lawlor.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_5acf168c5e8921a29d0ded6f7224f89a">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>University Photo Service is a student group that produced photographs of campus events. Founded in 1963, the group provides photographic equipment and darkroom services to its members in exchange for documenting campus events. From its foundation until 2014, University Photo Service also produced the Torch Yearbook. As of 2019, Photographic Services has maintained an office in the Campus Center for more than 50 years.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_ad17f3e92fc386ba0478d004b20813c5">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection is made up of photographic negatives (primarily in 35mm and 6x7 formats), contact sheets and photographic prints (primarily in 5"x8" and 8"x10" sizes). Many of the photographs have been placed into folders, though there are also  binders of photographic prints in this collection as well.  As the University Photo Service was responsible for producing the Torch yearbook until 2014, many prints and negatives of photographs that appeared in the Torch can be found in this collection. The photographs document life and events on and around campus. Student dorm life, athletic events, campus visits by dignitaries, faculty portraits, graduations and building dedications are among the subjects of these photographs.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_915e92702e9f08eeb948f4355357b5d9">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Collection was maintained in the original order after it was transferred.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_35ad5c2987b4151973766a553210c38c">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_3d2012b5d5d3c95222b21224e0e61339">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_c2731ce0d3a5adef13932d2e4723e170">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
<p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
<p>The M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collection and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_aa246407e81244af11192187281ab8f4">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, University Photo Service Records, 1966-1993. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the University Photo Services Records).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographic prints</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Negatives (photographic)</genreform>
    <genreform source="gmgpc">Contact sheets.</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
