<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ua902.084</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Applebee, Arthur; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>Applebee, Arthur; Papers <num>ua902.084</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-09-29 00:31:39 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Arthur Applebee Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua902.084</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1965/2014" type="inclusive">1965-2014</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_9431a5bbb7d585a4914a38c2beeffe1b">This collection is made up of the papers of Arthur N. Applebee, Distinguished Professor of Education and founder of Center on English Learning And Achievement (CELA), covering his professional career in Albany.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_04e5de73b6ccfa0b59d3e8cd3442e9f8">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_028726d5460d0fb087e6beebe387d975" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_9e63c401201e4cc066418b08b7c8735f">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Collection was maintained in the original  order after it was transferred.</p>  </arrangement>
  <processinfo id="aspace_81a2695adf829f5d121805f649f0506c">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2019 by Miles Lawlor.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_f3599e12418dec0055a760b02b84b48f">
    <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
<p>Arthur N. Applebee was a renowned scholar and professor of English education as well as director of the University's Center on English Learning and Achievement (CELA).  Holding degrees from Harvard, Yale and the University of London, Dr. Arthur N. Applebee came to the University at Albany, SUNY from Stanford in 1987 alongside his wife, Judith Langer, also an accomplished language psychologist and linguist.  Applebee taught at Albany's School of Education until his retirement in 2013, along with his duties with CELA.  During his career, he published 25 books and monographs as well as over 100 articles on English education.  Dr. Arthur Applebee and Dr. Judith Langer were the first husband and wife duo to both be named Distinguished Professors at the University.  Applebee died on September 20, 2015, at the age of 69.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_1f62803fda1d5c6291ea019f49431dad">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection documents Arthur Applebee's professional career as a professor and scholar.  The majority of the collection is made up of articles written and published by Applebee during his lifetime.  This collection also includes files related to Applebee's responsibilities as a professor at the University at Albany from roughly 2000 until his retirement.  These files cover such topics as doctoral program regulations, human subject testing guidelines and class scheduling and course load procedures.  The collection also contains a number of compact and floppy disks of educational statistics created by the US Department of Education.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_f0fd245e253350ef4533e9be3870c764">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 2015.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_485c9e98fc97574e71b443df0cc837a0">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted .</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_2a9a4b3fae3463f5ac900e05f28592bd">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
<p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
<p>The M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collection and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Faculty &amp; Alumni Papers</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
