<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ua902.069</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Mackiewicz, John; Papers <num>ua902.069</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-05-04 14:41:40 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>John Mackiewicz Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="local">Mackiewicz, John S.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ua902.069</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1976/1986" type="inclusive">1976-1986</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_9f92a83ca71d6dc4e4066844f1951fc6">John Mackiewicz worked with the University and SUNY Honors Programs as a Biological Science professor. Mackiewicz was the first Distingushed Professor of the University at Albany in 1973. </abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_a4620bbf339e136446cedc5eda61185d">English. </langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_d74097c8a04fe182320b519f39c9101b">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_28b51b6c6b5e98711542e4bbeb3bd9f7" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_5af312807e55e9b0e561fb15ded35e34">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Procesed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_94f118efe455d3fed1d621012ce584af">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>John Mackiewicz was born in 1930. Macklewicz spent most of his childhood in hospitals due to a bone infection. In 1939, after four surgeries he was discharged from the Newington Home and moved back to his family in Waterbury, Conneticut. </p><p>Mackiewicz earned his Ph.D from Cornell Uniersity and began teaching at the Medical Entomology and Parasitiology Center at the University in 1957. After leaving the University in 1959, Mackiewicz was a fellow for the National Institute of Health and conducted research at the Instiute de Zoologie in Neuchatel, Switzerland from 1960-1961. </p><p>In 1961, Mackiewicz began teaching at the University at Albany in the Bilogical Sciences department. Mackiewicz studied the evolution and ecology of parasites and wrote various publications while teaching. Mackiewicz earned the rank of Distinguished Teaching Professor in 1973 and retireed offically from the University in 2017. </p><p>Mackiewicz is the Research Affiliate of the Harold W. Manter Labratory of Parastiology at the University of Nebraska State Museum and has given lectures in many countries across the world.  Mackiewicz is also a member of nine scientific associations and enjoys fly fishing. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_fe9478c9a3e0a1a9c3dfea77ad79b491">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains the papers of John Mackiewicz.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_7bc3327ce501981fa06c57f88de8950c">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_d09bc18a79bc3366af5f9a685264f210">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_c247fb61c1c87a34e0dbab8efcf0fde7">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites. Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder. The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks. The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_c94fcb896cece1daa38a69eff247e9f6">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, John Mackiewicz Papers, 1976-1986. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Mackiewicz).</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_b3819f696004d0e849695d4e9bd19102">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Materials were donated to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives, yet little acquisition documentation exists. The undated original accession record for this collection was modified on April 4th and December 8th, 2014.-12-08</p>  </acqinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Faculty &amp; Alumni Papers</subject>
    <geogname source="local">Mackiewicz, John  S.</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
