<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ua902.070</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Hall, Kermit; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>Hall, Kermit; Papers <num>ua902.070</num></titleproper><author>Maggie Zehr</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2024</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-06-06 23:00:18 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Kermit Hall Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua902.070</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8.19 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1956/2006" type="inclusive">1956-2006</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_77f726901430213e163021da4b46ebde">Personal papers of former University at Albany President Kermit Hall, who passed away suddenly in 2006.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_eaa5f4a7ec291bc7a1d7072ac3de41a0">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_2d34be1db86bfbbc8d1516050050325e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_7f9f949290f1ae7c03ed831b47dda078">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection was processed in 2024 by Maggie Zehr.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_ce258817c2783bef8f73441efe8f45c9">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Kermit Lance Hall was born on August 31, 1944 in Akron, Ohio. Hall served in the Vietnam War from 1967-1969 and then earned a bachelor's degree from the University of Akron, a master's degree from Syracuse University in 1967, and a Ph.D from the University of Minnesota in 1972. Hall also recieved a MSL from Yale Law School in 1980. He was a recognized scholar and expert on legal history and the Supreme Court and wrote extensively on the development of federal and state courts. In 1979, as a scholar at Wayne State University, Hall published his first book, The Politics of Justice: Lower Federal Judicial Selection and the Second Party System, 1829-61.</p><p>On December 29, 2004, Hall was named the 17th president of the University at Albany, State University of New York. Prior to his appointment at Albany, Hall held academic and administrative positions at Vanderbilt University (1972-1976), University of Florida (1981-1992), University of Tulsa (1992-1994), before landing at Ohio State University in 1994 as Dean of the College of Humanities from 1994-1999, and as Executive Dean and a professor of History and Law of the College of Arts and Sciences (1996-99). From 1999-2001 he was the Provost and Vice President for academic affairs and a professor of History at North Carolina State University before becoming President and professor of History at Utah State University until 2005.</p><p>Hall was also known for his various publications about the American law and the judicial branch. His works granted him various awards including grants from the National Endowment for Humanities, the American Bar Association, and the James Madison Award from the American Library Association. While he worked on many long term publications concerning the Supreme Sourt and legal history, a significant amount of his research was dedicated to The New York Times v Sullivan, a case that originated in Alabama and concerned libel and freedom of the press. Beyond the First Amendment implications, Hall's research and writings on this case explored the racial tensions and civil rights coverage in Alabama that was intertwined with the court's proceedings at the time.</p><p>In 1992, President Bill Clinton appointed Hall to the five member Assassination Records Review Board to review and approve the release of public documents related to the assassination of President John F. Kennedy. Hall served as board member for numerous organizations relating to higher education, including the American Council on Eduction, the National Association of State University and Land Grant Colleges, the International Student Exchange Program, the NCAA Presidential Task Force on the Future of Intercollegiate Athletics, and the Research Foundation of the State University of New York. He was formerly a member of the board of the Research Triangle Institute, one of the nation's most succesful private research enterprises. Hall held fellowships and grants from the National Endowment for the Humanities, the National Science Foundation, the American Council of Learned Societies, the American Bar Foundation, and the Fulbright Education Foundation. </p><p>Hall died on August 13, 2006 in South Carolina and was survived by his wife Phyllis. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_9813ef9ddd778893fecb52ae295d96d7">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains Kermit Hall's personal papers.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_5d72c0030e0cd8e9f127e4d40e87bc62">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged alphabetically into four series as follows:</p><p>1: New York Times v Sullivan, 1956-2004, undated
2: Assassination Records Review Board, 1963-2004, undated
3: Essays and Publications, 1983-2005, undated
4: UAlbany Talks and Presentations, 2004-2006, undated</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_e3c4d3084a4d95dba443b2180f42ec87">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Phyllis Hall donated materials to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 2007.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_1756a8998b1febdcaea62efece721a13">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b7f1089bbc62eaf0261623b040c85735">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites. Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder. The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks. The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_a993baf995980a54bf7596b297db755f">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Kermit Hall Papers, 1980-2006. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Hall Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_813e6d0468e36cacb4732056342334aa">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Includes much of the materials housed in Kermit Hall's office after his death. Includes publications, manuscripts, research files on New York Times Co. v. Sullivan, records from the Assassination Records Review Board, and speeches given while President of UAlbany.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Faculty &amp; Alumni Papers</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">	Hall, Kermit L., 1944-2006</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">History--Study and teaching.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Law (discipline)</genreform>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Research (documents)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Research Notes</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Research</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">United States. Supreme Court.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Lectures.</genreform>
    <genreform source="local">News Clippings</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Manuscripts for publication</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Constitution</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Civil Rights</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Race relations</subject>
    <subject source="aat">assassinations</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
