<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ua902.039</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">White, Theodore; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>White, Theodore; Papers <num>ua902.039</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-09-29 00:30:58 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Theodore White Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua902.039</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1600/2000" type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_6311e891303b00bbc9c7df04c7530d38">Primarily files related to his tenure as a professor of Political Science, internal political science department files but also 1 box of a proposed but never realized Asian Studies Major in the early 1970s.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_2a1ebb2e7e522d6ccd823ca4b1ba75df">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_4f6afcc35de9e390a36f75a5fc329c78" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_7114dbe0362ef85aa6429bf9f02758b1">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_707fdbc09c464103537897bd8485e5d9">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Theodore White was a professor of Political Science at the State University of New York.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_350874df52120b565bd820e7489bd22b">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection primarily contains files related to White's tenure as a professor of Political Science and internal political science department. files. The collection also has one box of a proposed but never realized Asian Studies Major in the early 1970s.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_cfe779259815805c5c4c6c386c7eb9f3">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_3e63f002d714ea1fca4df9e2bf1bf61b">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_0386f23eb0424dd3001c804e6a90541e">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites. Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder. The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks. The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_5f10abfa735891d5d3b30af05c30e2d7">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Theodore White Papers, Undated. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the White Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_a9808c5c0e5181ea8e34789a81aac519">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>All materials were donated to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives on April 12, 2006.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Faculty &amp; Alumni Papers</subject>
    <geogname source="local">White, Theodore</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
