<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ua902.017</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Burian, Jarka M.; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>Burian, Jarka M.; Papers <num>ua902.017</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.
Processed by unprocessed.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-09-29 00:30:31 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Jarka M. Burian Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua902.017</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">30 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1956/1991" type="inclusive">1956-1991</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_3b525d09eb23cfdd5d50658ecef9ff96">Contains materials documenting various technical and production issues relating to the theatrical productions Burian was involved in between 1956 and 1991, as the theater director at the State University of New York at Albany (and its predecessor, the New York State College for Teachers) and the Arena Summer Theatre in Albany.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_0062e1a556f55e916b0ff2b8fc90f6a9">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_cdf8a7848b9f6903ca84fb579b025c20" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_dfc40e73cb4d869f72141a7f822d1dbe">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_b301507db1a664beb3987f460014a729">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Jaka M. Burian was a theater director and professor at the State University of New York at Albany (and its predecessor, the New York State College for Teachers) and the Arena Summer Theatre in Albany. Prior to working at the University at Albany, Burian was in the United States Army from 1946-1947 and a staff sargent from 1950-1951. Burian joined the New York State College for Teachers  as a Professor of English in 1955. Burian studied the relationship between government and theater in the Czech Republic and wrote various books on the topic. Burian retired from the University in 1992 and died in 2005.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_97ceffe0fc9a1022547e14351635be70">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains materials, including programs, press announcements, press reviews, photographs, correspondence, and notes regarding various technical and production issues relating to the theatrical productions Burian was involved in between 1956 and 1991, as the director.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_8908d36ecc5c5f02dd0e3bf31e798d08">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_c0804936e9b053e617502ed13cc190c6">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Jaka M Burian donated his papers to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 1998. Later materials were donated by Grayce Burian a number of times after his death.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_37cd26c1e1b3e9a240c66453f2deca0f">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_e5e7720ed18238303838c44bd9535089">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites. Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder. The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks. The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_8dc95ce565b3cbc6c0188cd49ea8787d">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Jaka M. Burian, 1956-1991. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Burian Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Faculty &amp; Alumni Papers</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Burian, Jarka, 1927-2005</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Theater -- Study and teaching -- New York (State) -- Albany.</subject>
    <subject source="aat">Correspondence.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">theater programs</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Press Releases</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
