<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="unprocessed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid></eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">LeComte, Edward S.; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>LeComte, Edward S.; Papers <num>ua902.087</num></titleproper><author>Benjamin Covell</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2017-04-27</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-03-09 03:11:13 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Edward S. LeComte Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="local">LeComte, Edward S.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ua902.087</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1940/2003" type="inclusive">1940-2003</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_bee282640b287bb1602ba660ca3c56cf">Contains the papers of Edward S. LeComte, who served as a professor of English at the University at Albany from 1964 until his retirement in 1981.  Materials in this collection include personal correspondence, course planning materials, publications and administrative documents from the Department of English, newsxpaper clippings, manuscripts of LeComte's writing, and communications with publishers.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_ffb76ce6eb56c39f9565bb639ec52477">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_b21c61ed1adc2365e02ea4e7d8258d3b">The materials are located onsite in the department. </physloc>
    <container id="aspace_005e09652adfe3143c19d68f377d3e5f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container>
    <container id="aspace_088aacb78f4a75763de0f2d5809581fd" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container>
    <container id="aspace_35cfb1fef6b98882e0eb89f9a6617528" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container>
    <container id="aspace_c73d6b9c30db132f8aff20b50ebcac69" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container>
    <container id="aspace_f2d6bee0e9c0bc179eeef054a2ac06af" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">5</container>
    <container id="aspace_e78bc5aa856cc6d3314628c275d2d9d3" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">6</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_7ef0310f6156a0b27806eaf02be33e41">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Unprocessed</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_ec98a6f1f79b38a51026640a90acf723">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is unprocessed and its contents are likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_810434f8038736bd3d561c068251b118">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_45e4401ad2683649b1aa7a102c243980">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_277e9a897265f8afd9a0664e68c48c8e">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites. Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder. The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks. The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_910078816447c98c9f0f077793a1f20c">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Edward S. LeComte Papers, 1940-2003. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Edward S. LeComte Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="aspace_bd37c1edf335e6090239cde078dd0e27">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Edward S. LeComte was born Edward S. Brandt in New York City on May 28, 1916.  As a young adult he legally changed his last name to that of his stepfather, LeComte.  He studied English at Columbia University and received his A.B. in 1939, his M.A. in 1940, and his Ph.D. in 1943.  After finishing his studies, LeComte taught English at Columbia, first as an instructor and then as a professor, from 1943 until 1964.  In 1964 he joined the English faculty at the University at Albany, where he remained until his retirement in 1981.  LeComte specialized in the works of John Milton and wrote numerous articles and books on the subject.  In addition, he wrote several works of fiction. LeComte passed away on October 23, 2004.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_8955991a73fb8f82f8f8cdd9e725bc06">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection documents various aspects of LeComte's personal and professional life.  The earliest manuscript in the collection is a 1940 paper he wrote while pursuing his M.A. at Columbia.  Much of the collection pertains to LeComte's published work, both his scholarly writings about John Milton and his own fiction works.  Materials include: manuscripts and drafts, handwritten notes, correspondence with publishers (including records of payment), and page proofs.  Written works in the collection also include drafts and clippings of reviews and editorials that LeComte wrote for scholarly journals and newspapers, as well as issues of scholarly journals and copies of articles written by other Milton scholars.  The collection also includes material related to LeComte's career at the University at Albany, including course syllabi and exams, English department reports and newsletters, memoranda, and faculty handbooks.  Finally, the collection contains personal correspondence with friends, family, and colleagues and a small number of photographs.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">English literature--Study and teaching (Higher)</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
