<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ua902.003</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Hopkins, Vivian C.; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>Hopkins, Vivian C.; Papers <num>ua902.003</num></titleproper><author>Miles Lawlor</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-09-29 00:30:03 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Vivian C. Hopkins Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua902.003</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">23.5 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1842/1980" type="inclusive">1842-1980</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1930/1980" type="bulk">1930-1978</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_96fd048f6809c38a15ff9b031d5fbe6b">This collection consists of the papers of Dr. Vivian Constance Hopkins, documenting both her career in academia and her personal correspondence.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_093269be4dae378c59ea6242d6336865">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_22449585f2ea701fb304069a4a71ab36" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_89e38743798eb810e2cf42a71504a6ba">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Collection includes correspondence, scrapbooks, class lecture notes, and Hopkins' academic research materials on a variety of topics including Satan's portrayal in literature, Ralpha Waldo Emerson, Dewitt Clinton, Delia Bacon, Francis Bacon, and Francis Adrian Van Der Kamp. Also includes typescripts, and drafts of articles and monographs written by Hopkins, including <i>Prodigal Puritan: a Life of Delia Bacon</i> and <i>Spires of Form: A Study of Emerson's Aesthetic Theory</i>. Collection also contains the records of the Albany Gravel Company.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e305ac780750a500a2770c3327bebef8">
    <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
<p>Vivian C. Hopkins was a long-time English professor at the State University of New York at Albany and its predecessors. Born in Troy in 1909, Hopkins received her B.A from Wellesley College and later her Ph.D. from the University of Michigan in 1943. She joined the faculty of the New York State Teachers College in 1941 and taught at the College and later University until her retirement in 1973. Hopkins received a Guggenheim Fellowship in 1956 for her study of Francis Bacon's  influence on American thought in the early 19th century. In addition to Bacon, Hopkins published on other literary figures including Nathaniel Hawthorne, Delia Bacon, Dewitt Clinton and Ralph Waldo Emerson. Hopkins died in 1989.</p>  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_cfa644134b7d37435db923397484b7a8">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Series-level finding aid created by Miles Lawlor in 2019. Folder-level processing on this collection had not been completed and individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_6ba6fedacd3ed18ef242eeb23633fc4e">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Collection was maintained in the original order after it was transferred. Materials in this collection have been broken into series which correspond with the original numbered order of boxes within the collection.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_5acf8a206242c9149da33a12a2db9bb8">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>All items in this collection were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 1986 by Vivian C. Hopkins.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_a177d979c70202343fe4750d5e97b845">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_a88013b618b3c9673db9715381f4dcdb">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
<p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
<p>The M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collection and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_b6716a5936e548ab019dcf7c51093736">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Vivian C. Hopkins Papers, 1842-1980. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Hopkins Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Faculty &amp; Alumni Papers</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_61e58e6334b2ed9b4e4a8c85500d65a5" level="series"><did><unittitle>Personal and Family Papers</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">11 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1842/1978" type="inclusive">1842-1978</unitdate><unitdate normal="1930/1970" type="bulk">1930-1970</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_04f84b98f9126c3e7ca7aad213f32608"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Files in this series have been maintained in their original order.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_ee011c832dd75438b1a7db5d56b2efef"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series is made up Hopkins' correspondence and scrapbooks, as well as correspondence belonging to other members of her family. Collection includes scrapbooks, correspondence, and press clippings. The correspondence includes exchanges between Hopkins and her former student, the Japanese poet Naoshi Koriyama. Series also includes a framed 1842 marriage certificate likely belonging to one of Hopkins' ancestors.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_852e38ac947e656f9d03d02ec077144f"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Series has not been processed at the item level. Most pieces of the correspondence in this series are still in their original envelopes.</p></processinfo></c><c id="aspace_ce7204a7b346f4e003d7981ddf73dfb4" level="series"><did><unittitle>Manuscript and Publication Notes</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">11.75 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1935/1979" type="inclusive">1935-1979</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_0a5500c3aa7fd3b2302f8a12caebc588"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Materials in this series have been maintained in their original order.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_3181212e5bd828c7890b808355a42456"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series includes research materials maintained by Hopkins related to articles, monographs and book reviews that she published, as well as proposed manuscripts. Series focuses on several literary figures and topics that were of particular interest to Hopkins, including Dewitt Clinton, Delia Bacon, Francis Adrian Van Der Kamp, Francis Bacon, Ralph Waldo Emerson, and the portrayal of Satan in literature. Included are materials related to her works <i> Prodigal Puritan: A Life of Delia Bacon </i> (1940), <i> Spires of Form: A Study of Emerson's Aesthetic Theory</i> (1951), as well as a number of articles. Series includes typescripts, handwritten and typed notes, copies of scholarly journal articles by Hopkins, publications containing the work of her former student Naoshi Koriyama, and correspondence.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0024e7abe108014ffdbbe527ce5cffb2" level="series"><did><unittitle>Albany Gravel Company</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.75 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1920/1980" type="inclusive">1920-1980</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_a77010a2ebfb0d630d740cb0326fdef3"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Materials in this series have been maintained in their original order.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_d27eabe7944dde495e52b6d88caabe06"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains contains records of the Albany Gravel Company up to its liquidation in 1980. John B. Hopkins, father to Vivian Hopkins, had served as President of the company and Vivian Hopkins later served on the Board of Directors as well.  Series includes meeting minutes, correspondence, stock certificates, and correspondence.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
