<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ua902.083</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Wittern-Keller, Laura; Papers <num>ua902.083</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-10-28 18:54:40 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2020</date><item>Collection level finding aid created by Sheri Sarnoff</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Laura Wittern-Keller Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua902.083</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.01 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="2001/2005" type="inclusive">2001-2005</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_1cf54225454c455bebfc8a9bc6aec370">Laura Wittern-Keller is a Professor of History at the University at Albany. This collection contains 3 cassette tapes of Shientag attorneys and distributors Freedman and Brandt who fought against state movie censorship.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_0b7aa953e51a122bd5d699c6a7e88fa2">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_cc801e9404f7386af8ddaed60edebebe" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_9188a1b2df161a64040f215620d8de2b">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_a47994076e378939604261beb0e13253">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Laura Wittern-Keller was born in 1951. Wittern-Keller recieved her PhD. from the University at Albany. Wittern-Keller's research has focused on the first amendment's right to freedom of speech and film censorship. Wittern-Keller is currently a professor in  the University at Albany's History Department.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_f3122815ec21ea8081eadd3b52ed0038">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains 3 cassette tapes of Shientag attorneys and distributors Freedman and Brandt who fought against state movie censorship.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_f5ad961e28b1e035c65a5df094aedee0">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_bd5d07727cdddf19686e46e1b0cc5a69">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Laura Wittern-Keller donated materials to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collectiosn and Archives in 2015.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_9958ca34d826fd22155ba84fa46fa830">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_c8cb6b9101c6e9fdccd4f687d24e9f2a">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites. Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder. The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks. The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_7c08e91bd86d5896821ba47e3f077672">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Laura Wittern-Keller Papers, 2001-2005. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Wittern-Keller Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Faculty &amp; Alumni Papers</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Wittern-Keller, Laura, 1951-</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Cassette tapes</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
