<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ua901.005</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Graduate Student Association; Records <num>ua901.005</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-06-12 08:17:33 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Graduate Student Association Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Graduate Student Association</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ua901.005</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12.33 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1990/2000" type="inclusive">1990-2000</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_9ddeebc66e2208a1ca549e2c5ee10ac9">This collection is made up of the inactive records of the University at Albany, SUNY's Graduate Student Association and its predecessors.  </abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_af691a598a72fc1e656acebd6374ec9c">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_46d785a546f9648399694d2fd1041d5f">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_9b5f0ec6e46730fb4068f76e0c808316" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_a359350e56b350a5eac5aa0b4aa59a4b">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>The University at Albany Graduate Student Organization (GSO) was voted into existence in the Spring of 1990 to address the needs of the University at Albany graduate students. In 2013, its name was changed to the University at Albany Graduate Student Association (GSA).</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_e840ee321a02037803cded8af530e902">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Audio cassette recordings of meetings,, meeting minutes, photographs and negatives, correspondence, grant proposals and grant evaluation forms, bylaws and constitutions, speech scripts, and award nominations.  The collection also contains a large number of floppy disks.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_9d62ddc05a73c9b09d8bd3e4d914be46">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2019 by Miles Lawlor.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_f500c0f12838970e8b71cae3c1abc377">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Collection was maintained in the original order after it was transferred.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_c0c5947b090b62d28bc7e8c1212c40bf">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_dcad5d495d64c9f0af43cc5912ad83b6">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_8f5ce8e21c6bfe46ca12b15257ac8581">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
<p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
<p>The M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collection and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_8995eba132961aafd32adafd26046de2">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Graduate Student Association Records (GSA), 1990-2000. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the GSA Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Student Groups</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
