<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ua902.003</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Hopkins, Vivian C.; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>Hopkins, Vivian C.; Papers <num>ua902.003</num></titleproper><author>Miles Lawlor</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-08-18 01:02:52 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Vivian C. Hopkins Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua902.003</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">23.5 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1842/1980" type="inclusive">1842-1980</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1930/1980" type="bulk">1930-1978</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_96fd048f6809c38a15ff9b031d5fbe6b">This collection consists of the papers of Dr. Vivian Constance Hopkins. These papers document Dr. Hopkins's career in academia, her personal correspondence, familial materials, and the records of the Albany Gravel Company.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_093269be4dae378c59ea6242d6336865">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_658ffffc34a1ff9c94a7e949d434a2f9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_89e38743798eb810e2cf42a71504a6ba">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Collection primarily includes correspondence, scrapbooks, and Hopkins' research materials and secondary sources, on a variety of topics including the portrayal of Satan in literature, Robert Frost, Ralpha Waldo Emerson, DeWitt Clinton, Delia Bacon, Francis Bacon, and Francis Adrian Van Der Kamp. Additionally, the collection includes typescripts, drafts, and final publications of serial articles, fictional work, and monographs written by Hopkins which directly relate to her research materials. Monographs include <i>Prodigal Puritan: a Life of Delia Bacon</i> and <i>Spires of Form: A Study of Emerson's Aesthetic Theory</i>. However, the collection has correspondence with publishers and materials that relate to the publication of such works, other monographs and serials, regardless of if she was successful in publishing them.  </p><p>The collection has some materials that relate to Hopkins' academic background and professional experience; however, this is limited in quantity and were thus merged with the materials relating to her personal and familial life. The Hopkins Papers include the records of the Albany Gravel Company, also known as Albany Gravel Co., up to the company's liquidation in 1980. Hopkins' father, John B. Hopkins, and her brother, Richard W. Hopkins, both served as presidents of the company, and Vivian later served on the Board of Directors.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e305ac780750a500a2770c3327bebef8">
    <head>Biographical Sketch</head>
<p>Vivian Constance Hopkins was born in Troy in 1909, receiving her B.A. from Wellesley College, and later her Ph.D. from the University of Michigan in 1943. During her time at the University of Michigan, Hopkins would become friends, and potentially, a romantic partner, with Virginia A. French. In 1941, Hopkins joined the faculty of the New York State Teachers College to teach as an English professor. During her time at the Teachers College, she received a Guggenheim Fellowship in 1956 for her study of Francis Bacon and his influence on American thought in the early 19th century. In addition to her work on Francis Bacon, Hopkins published on other literary figures including Nathanial Hawthorne, Delia Bacon, Robert Frost, DeWitt Clinton, and Ralph Waldo Emerson.  </p><p>During her time at the Teachers College, Dr. Hopkins became the mentor and later, friend, of her student Naoshi Koriyama, who studied English Literature and graduated in 1954, who later became a poet and professor in Japan. Dr. Hopkins would continue in her role as a Professor of English when the College became the State University of New York at Albany in 1962 and would retire in 1973 and eventually died in 1989. Prior to her death, Dr. Hopkins assisted with the liquidation of the Albany Gravel Company, which was created by her father, John B. Hopkins. During her retirement, she worked to establish The Vivian C. Hopkins Scholarship Award at the University at Albany, SUNY for outstanding scholastic ability and character in the Department of English. </p>  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_cfa644134b7d37435db923397484b7a8">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Series-level finding aid created by Miles Lawlor in 2019. Folder-level processing, arrangement, and description was completed by Liam Sperrazza in 2025.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_6ba6fedacd3ed18ef242eeb23633fc4e">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is organized into 3 series, and are arranged alphabetically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_5acf8a206242c9149da33a12a2db9bb8">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>All items in this collection were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 1986 by Vivian C. Hopkins.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_a177d979c70202343fe4750d5e97b845">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_a88013b618b3c9673db9715381f4dcdb">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
<p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
<p>The M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collection and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_b6716a5936e548ab019dcf7c51093736">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Vivian C. Hopkins Papers, 1842-1980. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Hopkins Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Faculty &amp; Alumni Papers</subject>
    <function source="lcsh">Hopkins, Vivian C. (Vivian Constance), 1909-1989</function>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
    <subject source="local">English--Education</subject>
    <function source="lcsh">Literature</function>
    <subject source="lcsh">English literature--Study and teaching (Higher)</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_61e58e6334b2ed9b4e4a8c85500d65a5" level="series"><did><unittitle>Personal and Family Papers</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">11 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1842/1978" type="inclusive">1842-1978</unitdate><unitdate normal="1930/1970" type="bulk">1930-1970</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_04f84b98f9126c3e7ca7aad213f32608"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Folders in this series are arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_ee011c832dd75438b1a7db5d56b2efef"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series is made up Hopkins' correspondence, genealogy materials, photographs, newspaper clippings, scrapbooks, some diaries as well as correspondence belonging to other members of her family that mention her, all of which ranging the entirety of her life. The correspondence includes letters and poems from Virginia A. French. These letters, sometimes signed letters as "G.A." or "Ginny Addy," are strongly suggestive a romantic relationship between the women from 1941 to 1943. While Hopkins usually kept a duplicate of her correspondence with individuals and publishers, she did not create any duplicates of her letters to Virginia French. It is unknown what happened to French and the true scope and length of the relationship between two women. Additionally, there are the letters, newsclippings and photographs between Hopkins and her former student, the Japanese poet and professor Naoshi Koriyama. These materials range from 1954 to 1979 and are a mix of correspondence relating to literature and English and Japanese academia to details and updates of Koriyama's life. Hopkins also was a friend of the American Poet, Robert Frost, and the series includes Christmas poetry booklets with personal notes to Hopkins. Finally, this series also includes the diary of her grandfather during his time in the Civil War.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_852e38ac947e656f9d03d02ec077144f"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Series has not been processed at the item level. Most pieces of the correspondence in this series are still in their original envelopes.</p></processinfo></c><c id="aspace_ce7204a7b346f4e003d7981ddf73dfb4" level="series"><did><unittitle>General Research, Writings, and Publication Materials</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7.4 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1935/1979" type="inclusive">1935-1979</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_0a5500c3aa7fd3b2302f8a12caebc588"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Folders in this series are arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_3181212e5bd828c7890b808355a42456"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series is primarily made up of Hopkins' research materials and notes, both typed and handwritten, for scholarly publications as articles, monographs and books. However, it also includes newspaper clippings about her publications, secondary sources that were used in her research process, typescripts, author's galleys, drafts and publication copies of serial articles, fictional short stories and plays, and monographs. Included in this are folders of unidentified research notes and fictional works. Furthermore, it contains correspondence concerning research questions, and correspondence for manuscript proposals, regardless of success or failure to publish them.  </p><p>The series focuses on several literary and historical figures, family members, and topics of particular interest to Hopkins. These include DeWitt Clinton, Delia Bacon, Francis Bacon, Herman Melville, Francis Adrian Van Der Kemp, Ralph Waldo Emerson, and the portrayal of Satan in English literature. Included are materials related to her works <i> Prodigal Puritan: A Life of Delia Bacon </i> (1940), <i> Spires of Form: A Study of Emerson's Aesthetic Theory</i> (1951), as well as a number of articles for various serial publications.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0024e7abe108014ffdbbe527ce5cffb2" level="series"><did><unittitle>Albany Gravel Company Records</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.75 cubic ft.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1920/1980" type="inclusive">1920-1980</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_a77010a2ebfb0d630d740cb0326fdef3"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Folders in this series are arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_d27eabe7944dde495e52b6d88caabe06"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains the records of the Albany Gravel Company, also called Albany Gravel Co., up to its liquidation in 1980 to Valente Gravel. Vivian's father, John B. Hopkins, and brother, Richard W. Hopkins, both served as presidents of the company, with the latter becoming president after his father's death. Following the sudden death of John in 1972, Vivian, who was a member of the Board of Directors, started the liquidation of the company to Valente Gravel. The series includes meeting minutes, photographs, business correspondence, stock certificate ledgers property appraisals, licensing and inventory materials, and land contracts, such as that with Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
