<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ua902.070</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Hall, Kermit; Papers</titleproper><titleproper>Hall, Kermit; Papers <num>ua902.070</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-03-25 23:00:25 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Kermit Hall Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua902.070</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">45 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1980/2006" type="inclusive">ca. 1980-2006</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_77f726901430213e163021da4b46ebde">Personal papers of former University at Albany President Kermit Hall, who passed away suddenly in 2006.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_eaa5f4a7ec291bc7a1d7072ac3de41a0">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_07a4dee430e69326046f87b5e34732d8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_7f9f949290f1ae7c03ed831b47dda078">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by unprocessed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_ce258817c2783bef8f73441efe8f45c9">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Kermit Lance Hall was born on August 31, 1944 in Akron, Ohio. Hall served in the Vietnam War and then earned a bachelor's degree from the University of Akron, a master's degree from Syracuse University in 1967, and a Ph.D from the University of Minnesota in 1972. Hall also recieved a MSL from Yale Law School in 1980. </p><p>Hall began teaching history at various Universities including Vanderbilt, Wayne State, and the University of Florida. Hall served as the president of Utah State University from 2000-2005, and in 2005 he became the 70th president of the State University of New York. </p><p>Hall was also known for his various publications about the American law and the judicial branch. His works granted him various awards including grants from the National Endowment for Humanities, the American Bar Association, and the James Madison Award from the American Library Association. </p><p>Hall was also appointed by President Bill Clinton to sit on the Assasination Records Review Board which looked at the documents relating to the death of President Kennedy. </p><p>Hall died on August 13, 2006 in South Carolina and was survived by his wife Phyllis. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_9813ef9ddd778893fecb52ae295d96d7">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains Kermit Hall's personal papers.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_5d72c0030e0cd8e9f127e4d40e87bc62">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_e3c4d3084a4d95dba443b2180f42ec87">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Phyllis Hall donated materials to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 2007.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_1756a8998b1febdcaea62efece721a13">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b7f1089bbc62eaf0261623b040c85735">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites. Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder. The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks. The University Archives are eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_a993baf995980a54bf7596b297db755f">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Kermit Hall Papers, 1980-2006. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Hall Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_813e6d0468e36cacb4732056342334aa">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Includes much of the materials housed in Kermit Hall's office after his death. Includes publications, manuscripts, research files on New York Times Co. v. Sullivan, records from the Assassination Records Review Board, and memorabilia.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Faculty &amp; Alumni Papers</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">	Hall, Kermit L., 1944-2006</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
