<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="new" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/view?docId=ua902.012.xml">ua902.012</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Sirotkin, Phillip; Papers <num>ua902.012</num></titleproper><author>Geoffrey A. Huth</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>1989 June 2</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-09-03 12:52:47 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Phillip Sirotkin Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua902.012</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1968/1972" type="inclusive">1968-1972</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_f880ca0084d860e32aeed9b30aab93e8">Sirotkin was Executive Vice President for Academic Affairs at the University at Albany. Collection consists of materials pertaining to the hospitalization of political dissidents in Soviet mental institutions, retained by Sirotkin as a member of the First U.S. Mission on Mental Health to the Soviet Union.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_bde7257de1f3a2f2514dd5309de9df34">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_cb6f51fc0f59fe473a52d67daea94c27">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 1989 June 2 by Geoffrey A. Huth.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_5a2b0a62c8dcab1f57e2c43c5d584c9a">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_3135c9512d9ddd4c3b3c62bb08203278">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites. </p><p> Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p><p> The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks. </p><p> The Department of Special Collections and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_e78f62997fd0861313081238d6bef22a">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by Phillip Sirotkin.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_22bf47e351ab60b4a7e9b2558f22e9a3">
    <head>Biographical History</head>
<p>Phillip Leonard Sirotkin was born in Moline, Illinois, on August 2, 1923. He married Cecille Sylvia Gussack on May 1, 1945, and they had two children: Steven and Laurie. He received his B.A. from Wayne State University in 1945, his M.A. in 1947 and his Ph.D. in 1951, both from the Universtiy of Chicago. </p><p> Sirotkin was a lecturer at the University of Chicago (1949-50), an instructor (1950-52) and an assistant professor of political science (1953-57) at Wellesley College, associate director of Western Interstate Commission on Higher Education, Boulder, Colorado (1957-60), executive assistant to the director of the California Department of Mental Hygiene (1960-63), assistant director of the National Institute of Mental Health (1964-66), associate director of NIMH (1967-71) and a consultant at NIMH (1971-73), executive vice president for academic affairs at the State University of New York at Albany (1971-76), and executive director of Western Interstate Commission for Higher Education, Boulder, Colorado (1976-). </p><p> n 1967, Philip Sirotkin, while associate director of the National Institute of Mental Health, was part of the First U.S. Mission on Mental Health to the U.S.S.R. In February 1969, the Mission published its report. Three years later, the New York Review of Books published a series of articles on the Soviet Union's commitment of dissidents to mental institutions. R. B. Silvers, editor of the New York Review of Books, wrote letters to all seven members of the Mission requesting that they respond to documents supporting this claim.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_f9d028fcc5179cc7b121223bfa7e441e">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The papers contain correspondence sent to Sirotkin as a member of the First U.S. Mission on Mental Health to the U.S.S.R. Included are documents in English translation (including reports by Soviet officials on the mental health of people accused of crimes against the state, statements by people who had been confined in Soviet mental institutions, and appeals from prominent Soviet dissidents such as Alexander Solzhenitsyn and V. N. Chalidze on behalf of those confined), articles about Soviet dissidents who were sent to mental institutions, and a note about the authenticity of the Soviet documents by Peter Reddaway.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_77bb1711ba20a07170917657092e6ad9">
    <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>The collection has no series.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_1638c0576f56f05fe705c2a146f3720c">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p> Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Phillip Sirotkin Papers, 1967-1972. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Sirotkin Papers).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">Medicine and Health Care</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">[name here]</geogname>
    <subject source="local">[name here]</subject>
    <genreform source="lcsh">[name here]</genreform>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Faculty &amp; Alumni Papers</subject>
    <persname source="lcsh">Sirotkin, Phillip</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_361657287fe03b7c83ec8ce724a5e060" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_982565d203dc678451f238a218e74bac" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (Phillip Sirotkin Papers)</container><container id="aspace_78877842fa577b9a88410bba05ffc4e3" parent="aspace_982565d203dc678451f238a218e74bac" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_b88892f4d9e32028524633cb67a7f13d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reports by Soviet Authorities on Compulsory Confinement</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1968/1971" type="inclusive">1968-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_37ff50d40d09d89bfbfbaeed418de783" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (Phillip Sirotkin Papers)</container><container id="aspace_49a36647100751fc334c0077c43b76aa" parent="aspace_37ff50d40d09d89bfbfbaeed418de783" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_527b108759ee42519a69a35386d9dcd8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters and Statements by Soviet Citizens Who Are or Have Been Confined in Mental Institutions</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1968/1971" type="inclusive">1968-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_4a5da8459921f53be6e18f05b1fa6026" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (Phillip Sirotkin Papers)</container><container id="aspace_7813d7db0ab7a4b4cdd5800281bb0313" parent="aspace_4a5da8459921f53be6e18f05b1fa6026" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_c930b8683dc9c264a525a684b0327d9c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Statements and Appeals by Soviet Citizens on Behalf of Those Under Confinement</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_700910991bd0df17e0fdb974e0bce7ab" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (Phillip Sirotkin Papers)</container><container id="aspace_5edfd477678d3fa66197412ada34f819" parent="aspace_700910991bd0df17e0fdb974e0bce7ab" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ee5dae8b5cc18a2d054aca385c5ea464" level="file"><did><unittitle>Statements and Articles by Peter Reddaway</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1971/1971" type="inclusive">1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_cf500bab863bd8eecf99113115e47973" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 (Phillip Sirotkin Papers)</container><container id="aspace_cac9edb2deeb4e2fcc1dfed253a68a93" parent="aspace_cf500bab863bd8eecf99113115e47973" type="Folder">5</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
