<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ua950.024</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Veterans Project; Collection <num>ua950.024</num></titleproper><author>Miles Lawlor</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2019</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-10-18 15:42:12 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2019 October 17</date><item>EAD file created</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Veterans Project Collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="local">M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ua950.024</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.66 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1866/2019" type="inclusive">1866-2019</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_c8892a7be5480235639b0d0ec8052c40">This artificial collection documents university students who served in the military during armed conflicts, particularly during World War II.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_76ee5715c16787fb13ec95b2ed614ccf">English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_afc1b700e37d3203e8cc4e4a211b4fb3">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_cb7330cbe7f6b357efcb81c281f65c33" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container>
    <container id="aspace_5e41437efd456ddce5bc1924f53b770e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_ffada5a0d2aa8691951a4a8a54dc45eb">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Collection inititally curated by Geoff Williams. Materials were initially rehoused by Miles Lawlor in 2019.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_a20efc0f0c8e2cbca2d28e5920310406">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>Students and Faculty affiliated with the University have served in the American military going back to the Mexican-American War. Begun in 1999, the Alumni Relations Office began an ongoing project seeking to recognize members of the University at Albany community who had served in the military with a Wall of Honor in the Science Library. The Wall was unveiled as part of Alumni Weekend in 2001.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_9a36d593543e614aa33303b862ad92b2">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Collection was maintained in the original order after it was transferred.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_5ca5f30c58bb817b63efcaa843c01a1c">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_f7f68cb44aac6a46222e65a3bca05e91">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_e2ea025b2acdbe409efa3990834ef5ba">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
<p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
<p>The M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collection and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_fdd815783f5354dbb446198d63a19b72">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Veterans Project Collection, 1927-2000. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Veterans Collection).</p>  </prefercite>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_60b05fce7acf4a39371aef48b23da380">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This artificial collection consists of materials assembled as part of the Veterans Project. It includes photographic prints and photocopies, press clippings, correspondence and brief summaries of students' military service. The majority of the materials in the collection relate to service in World War II.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <phystech id="aspace_e78665f0c5e24980626a0ab0763f6ba3">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Collection contains CD-Rs, a zip disk and a 3.5' floppy disk.</p>  </phystech>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Photographs</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Veterans</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War II</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
