<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ua950.006</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Vietnam War; Collection <num>ua950.006</num></titleproper><author>Migrated from collection-level xlsx spreadsheet.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-09-03 13:25:40 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Vietnam War Collection</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua950.006</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.4 cubic ft.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1967/1973" type="inclusive">1967-1973</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_0fb93167739f3c3fa996dbb8103c0cce">An artificial collection documents the influence of the Vietnam War on the SUNY Albany campus..</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_133bc4e13138e547cdfb8eb55f125f36">The materials are located onsite in the department.</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_00ab05b7c1f2696c10b1665c98afe812" label="Mixed Materials" type="Collection">X</container>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_bc3f232476617fa09495ddaa2dee33b3">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>Like many other colleges and universities throughout America, The State University of New York at Albany saw its share of protests on the Vietnam War and related events during the late 1960s and into the 1970s.  Murmurs of protest began as early as 1967 and continued even after the United States began drawing down troop levels in the 1970s.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_fc0c11895dad69e8cd669975b421ee46">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This artificial collection is primarily made up of flyers and posters found on campus relating to the war.  There are also files containing correspondence, newspapers, and publications on the Vietnam War.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_0a9cb079c82f618f84bae2dcc2bde1a1">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed in 2019 by Miles Lawlor.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_a2636eee451958225564f016f44b2836">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Collection was maintained in its original order upon processing.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_c8200952aa49a4829679d62de759b848">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_b1306a39883822114715b205f53514bc">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_198b5ef3c8cf8ea624d0cc930ea1381d">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>This page may contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>
<p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>
<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>
<p>The M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collection and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>
  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_d22fa7e450f1c0aacb5d06369b937643">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows: Identification of specific item, series, box, folder, Vietnam War Collection, 1967-1973. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York (hereafter referred to as the Vietnam War Collection).</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Reference Collections</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
