<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>ua950.025</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">UAlbany COVID-19 Website; Collection</titleproper><titleproper>UAlbany COVID-19 Website; Collection <num>ua950.025</num></titleproper><author>Amanda Greenwood</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>2021</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-04-07 14:13:49 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>UAlbany COVID-19 Website</unittitle>
    <unitid>ua950.025</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">458 Captures</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="2020-03/2020-12" type="bulk">2020 March - 2021 April</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_9450f44af45ef3b64bf92cdffd35e807">This collection contains captures during the months of March 2020 and April 2020 for the sub domain of the University website: www.albany.edu/covid-19. Web crawling is managed through the Internet Archive's Archive-It service.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_b69777a0ac86424b91afd5d812cf2eca">English</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_9f090e90b59293022be632ab05b075c8">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The website of UAlbany COVID-19 was created in March 2020 to document the University's response the the 2019 novel coronavirus disease (SARS-CoV-2 disease). </p><p>Because of the quickening infection rates of the COVID-19 virus in New York State, UAlbany President Dr. Havidán Rodríguez decided to suspend classes on Friday, March 13, 2020. A decision was made to offer classes remotely after spring break, starting on Monday, March 23, until further notice. The suspension of classes was decided to give faculty and staff important additional time to prepare for the transition. In addition, all business buildings were still open and expected to resume normal operations, and UAlbany's three campuses would also remain open, including the residence halls, libraries, offices, and dining services.</p><p>As the University continued to monitor developments related to COVID-19 with guidance from local and state health departments and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), this website was created to notify faculty, staff, an students of important announcements, updates, virus infection rates, and other news related to the pandemic and its effect on the University community.</p>  </bioghist>
  <userestrict id="aspace_835c685b5f47e62bf144753180109c02">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This page contain links to digital objects. Access to these images and the technical capacity to download them does not imply permission for re-use. Digital objects may be used freely for personal reference use, referred to, or linked to from other web sites.</p>

<p>Researchers do not have permission to publish or disseminate material from these collections without permission from an archivist and/or the copyright holder.</p>

<p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming to the laws of copyright. Some materials in these collections may be protected by the U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) and/or by the copyright or neighboring-rights laws of other nations. More information about U.S. Copyright is provided by the Copyright Office. Additionally, re-use may be restricted by terms of University Libraries gift or purchase agreements, donor restrictions, privacy and publicity rights, licensing and trademarks.</p>

<p>The M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collection and Archives is eager to hear from any copyright owners who are not properly identified so that appropriate information may be provided in the future.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_bacc3006bd38dc134a901c022e064277">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>This website was captured and preserved at the time when it was crawled by using web crawling tools that allow for the preservation and access of internet sites. Web Archives are created through regular crawls performed by Archive-It, a service provided by the Internet Archive. Archive-It performs regular crawls to create as complete a snapshot of the University's website as is feasible. In a given webcrawl, Archive-It begins from a seed (a high level domain, such as www.albany.edu) or set of seeds, and then automatically harvests successive layers of the website by following links from this seed. This process continues for a specified duration or until a specified number of documents has been harvested. Additional information on Archive-It can be found <a href="https://archive-it.org/learn-more/">here.</a> Additional information on the Internet Archives can be found <a href="http://archive.org/about/">here.</a> </p><p>This archived website can be viewed through the Internet Archive's Wayback Machine website. The Wayback Machine is a service that allows people to visit and browse archived versions of web sites. In addition, web crawling tools can make interactive maps and other dynamic web content, such as embedded videos, difficult to capture. </p><p>In the case of the UAlbany COVID-19 website, the embedded video links hosted via YouTube needed to be copied, pasted, and manually entered as separate seeds in the collection. They were then separately crawled in order for Archive-It to capture the video content and make it available.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <phystech id="aspace_a24bcd0fb0c214cfbbf5e5740d6802ae">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>The University's Web Archives are hosted by the Internet Archive and can be viewed on the Wayback Machine. Viewing archived webpages requires a browser with Javascript turned on. If Javascript is turned off, images and links on web pages will be from the live web, not from archived web files.</p>  </phystech>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_6140c38f49a8f32645010019c52dbc5b">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains archived versions of the University COVID-19 website from March 2020 and onward. The site is one of the main methods of delivery for news and information about the novel Coronavirus and how it has impacted the University community. Content includes Coronavirus case statistics, University news, student and employee health screenings, test kit information, student documentation, surveillance testing, health and safety documentation, and contract tracing program information. Documents in the web archives include a variety of formats ranging from simple URL links to other university webpages, PDFs, and images, to more complex web documents containing embedded video and audio content, forms, and other common features. The completeness of each website snapshot varies.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_446587dc7f9bd917722d69d4a00ae5e9">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <arrangement id="aspace_1539fdbb31899dffb439c124293cd2d9">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The web archive maintains the original links and arrangement of the website when it was captured.</p>  </arrangement>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Web archives</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher--New York (State)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher--Administration</subject>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Academic Administration</subject>
    <subject source="meg">UAlbany Communications &amp; Marketing</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Digital Moving Image Formats</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">COVID-19 (Disease)</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_8b2a9fe7e00df39637b1baa9afa6852f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Campus Communications</unittitle><unitdate normal="2020-03/2021-05" type="inclusive">2020 March - 2021 May</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/3308/20200317230825/https://www.albany.edu/covid-19/campus-communications" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="COVID-19 Campus Communications" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>COVID-19 Campus Communications</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f636484fe181db15b0175efd0a4560f5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The UAlbany COVID-19 Campus Communications page serves as a platform of communication for the UAlbany administration to release news about state and University-related matters related to the COVID-19 pandemic.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3bb5db53c56c38abfa65ad53334f1179" level="item"><did><unittitle>Information for Faculty and Staff</unittitle><unitdate normal="2020-03/2020-03">2020 March</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/3308/20200317230645/https://www.albany.edu/covid-19/information-faculty-staff" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="UAlbany Covid-19 Information for Faculty and Staff" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>UAlbany Covid-19 Information for Faculty and Staff</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4775562dfa37e8f142c649015aaa7d59"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The UAlbany COVID-19 Information for Faculty and Staff page was a means of communication between the University administration and the faculty and staff concerning all matters related to the COVID-19 pandemic, including information on how to continue teaching after the state shutdown, training videos for remote teaching, and answers to frequently asked questions.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5c19bdeb5760f04092ae1b7aa69b5d9f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Information for Students</unittitle><unitdate normal="2020-03/2021-05" type="inclusive">2020 March - 2021 May</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/3308/*/https://www.albany.edu/covid-19/information-resources-students" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Information &amp; Resources for Students" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Information &amp; Resources for Students</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c4b7ba0839f5a078da38b28a1148f524"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The UAlbany COVID-19 Information for Students page served as a means of communication between the University administration and the students for all matters related to the COVID-19 pandemic, including health and safety tips, housing, financial aid, and academics.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5878c634341003b0a66ccfc3363a61b2" level="item"><did><unittitle>Information Dashboard</unittitle><unitdate normal="2020-09/2021-05" type="inclusive">2020 September - 2021 May</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/3308/*/https://www.albany.edu/covid-19/ualbany-covid-19-dashboard" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="UAlbany COVID-19 Information Dashboard" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>UAlbany COVID-19 Information Dashboard</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e9649a3978cad39c7cf134fd66fe7710"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The UAlbany COVID-19 Dashboard is page that shows the daily statistics related to COVID-19 testing, positive student and employee cases, on-campus quarantine and isolation, and the SUNY pause status.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
